[{"question":"Internet advertising is growing at a rate of more than 30 percent a year.","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 6","number":"1","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"A business model describes how a company produces, delivers, and sells a product or service to create wealth.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 11","number":"2","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"Information technology (IT) consists of all the hardware that a firm needs to use in order to achieve its business objectives, whereas information systems consist of all the software and business processes needed.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 13–14","number":"3","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"Computers are only part of an information system.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 16","number":"4","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"Information systems literacy describes the behavioral approach to information systems, whereas computer literacy describes the technical approach.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 16","number":"5","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"The dimensions of information systems are management, organizations, and information technology.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 16","number":"6","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"In order to understand how a specific business firm uses information systems, you need to know something about the hierarchy and culture of the company.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 17–18","number":"7","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"Developing a new product, fulfilling an order, or hiring a new employee are examples of business processes.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 7","number":"8","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"Business processes are logically related tasks for accomplishing tasks that have been formally encoded by an organization.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18","number":"9","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"A network requires at least two computers and a shared resource, such as a printer.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"10","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"An IT infrastructure provides the platform on which the firm can build its information systems.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 21","number":"11","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"UPS’s use of Web-based tools that allow customers to embed UPS functions such as tracking and cost calculations into their own Web sites was an information systems solution used to achieve customer intimacy.\nAnalysis in terms of categorize","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 11, 20–21","number":"12","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"A fully digital firm produces only digital goods or services.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 7","number":"13","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"There are four major business functions: Sales and marketing; manufacturing and production; finance and accounting; and information technology.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"14","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"In the behavioral approach to information systems, technology is ignored in favor of understanding the psychological, social, and economic impacts of systems.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 27","number":"15","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"Government and private sector standards are examples of complementary social assets required to optimize returns from IT investments.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 25","number":"16","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"Knowledge workers assist with paperwork at all levels of the firm.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"17","type":0,"answer":"false"},{"question":"A firm that invests in efficient business processes is making an investment in organizational complementary assets.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 25","number":"18","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"A substantial part of management responsibility is creative work driven by new knowledge and information.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"19","type":0,"answer":"true"},{"question":"Intranets allow firms to work easily with third-party suppliers and vendors. Answer: False\nMultiple-Choice Questions","ref":"p. 19","chapter":1,"number":"20","diff":"Medium"},{"type":1,"question":"The six important business objectives of information technology are new products, services, and business models; customer and supplier intimacy; survival; competitive advantage; operational excellence; and:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 8","number":"21","option":[{"value":"improved flexibility.","index":"a"},{"value":"improved decision making.","index":"b"},{"value":"improved business practices.","index":"c"},{"value":"improved efficiency.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"Dell Computer’s use of information systems to improve efficiency and implement “mass customization” techniques to maintain consistent profitability and an industry lead illustrates which business objective?","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"number":"22","option":[{"value":"Improved flexibility","index":"a"},{"value":"Improved business practices","index":"b"},{"value":"Competitive advantage","index":"c"},{"value":"Survival","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"The use of information systems because of necessity is:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 13","number":"23","option":[{"value":"survival.","index":"a"},{"value":"improved business practices.","index":"b"},{"value":"competitive advantage.","index":"c"},{"value":"improved flexibility.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Which of the following choices may lead to competitive advantage (1) new products, services, and business models; (2) charging less for superior products; (3) responding to customers in real time?","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 12–13","number":"24","option":[{"value":"1 only","index":"a"},{"value":"1 and 2","index":"b"},{"value":"2 and 3","index":"c"},{"value":"1, 2, and 3","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"Verizon’s implementation of a Web-based digital dashboard to provide managers with real-time information such as customer complaints is an example of:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 12","number":"25","option":[{"value":"improved flexibility.","index":"a"},{"value":"improved decision making.","index":"b"},{"value":"improved efficiency.","index":"c"},{"value":"customer and supplier intimacy.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"The move of retail banking to use ATMs after Citibank unveiled its first ATMs illustrates the information system business objective of:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 13","number":"26","option":[{"value":"improved efficiency.","index":"a"},{"value":"customer and supplier intimacy.","index":"b"},{"value":"survival.","index":"c"},{"value":"competitive advantage.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"An information system can be defined technically as a set of interrelated components that collect (or retrieve), process, store, and distribute information to support:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 14","number":"27","option":[{"value":"decision making and control in an organization.","index":"a"},{"value":"communications and data flow.","index":"b"},{"value":"managers analyzing the organization’s raw data.","index":"c"},{"value":"the creation of new products and services.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"The three activities in an information system that produce the information organizations use to control operations are:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 14–15","number":"28","option":[{"value":"information retrieval, research, and analysis.","index":"a"},{"value":"input, output, and feedback.","index":"b"},{"value":"input, processing, and output.","index":"c"},{"value":"data analysis, processing, and feedback.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Order data for baseball tickets and bar code data are examples of:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 15","number":"29","option":[{"value":"raw input.","index":"a"},{"value":"raw output.","index":"b"},{"value":"customer and product data.","index":"c"},{"value":"sales information.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"option":[{"value":"input.","index":"a"},{"value":"raw data.","index":"b"},{"value":"meaningful information.","index":"c"},{"value":"output.","index":"d"}],"chapter":1,"number":"30","question":"The average number of tickets sold daily online is an example of:","answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Output:\nevaluate the input stage.\nwill be used.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 14","number":"31","option":[{"value":"is feedback that has been processed to create meaningful information.","index":"a"},{"value":"is information that is returned to appropriate members of the organization to help them","index":"b"},{"value":"transfers data to the people who will use it or to the activities for which it will be used.","index":"c"},{"value":"transfers processed information to the people who will use it or to the activities for which it","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"Converting raw data into a more meaningful form is called:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 15","number":"32","option":[{"value":"capturing.","index":"a"},{"value":"processing.","index":"b"},{"value":"organizing.","index":"c"},{"value":"feedback.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"An example of raw data from a national chain of automobile stores would be:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 14","number":"33","option":[{"value":"an average of 13 Toyotas are sold daily in Kentucky.","index":"a"},{"value":"30 percent increase in Toyota RAV 4 sales during September in Kentucky.","index":"b"},{"value":"1 Toyota RAV4 sold March 3, 2005 in Louisville, Kentucky.","index":"c"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"The field that deals with behavioral issues as well as technical issues surrounding the development, use, and impact of information systems used by managers and employees in the\nfirm is called:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"number":"34","option":[{"value":"information systems literacy.","index":"a"},{"value":"information systems architecture.","index":"b"},{"value":"management information systems.","index":"c"},{"value":"information technology infrastructure.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"In a hierarchical organization, the upper levels consist of:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"number":"35","option":[{"value":"managerial and professional employees.","index":"a"},{"value":"managerial, professional, and technical employees.","index":"b"},{"value":"professional and operational employees.","index":"c"},{"value":"managerial, professional, and operational employees.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"A hierarchy:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"36","option":[{"value":"is based on a clear-cut division of labor.","index":"a"},{"value":"is composed primarily of experts trained for different functions.","index":"b"},{"value":"is a pyramid structure of rising authority and responsibility.","index":"c"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"The fundamental set of assumptions, values, and ways of doing things that has been accepted by most of a company’s members is called its:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18","number":"37","option":[{"value":"culture.","index":"a"},{"value":"environment.","index":"b"},{"value":"atmosphere.","index":"c"},{"value":"values.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Business processes:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18","number":"38","option":[{"value":"include informal work practices.","index":"a"},{"value":"are used primarily for sales and accounting functions.","index":"b"},{"value":"are governed by information technology.","index":"c"},{"value":"are logically related tasks used primarily by operational personnel.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Data management technology consists of:\ncomponents in an information system.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"39","option":[{"value":"the physical hardware and media used by an organization for storing data.","index":"a"},{"value":"the detailed, preprogrammed instructions that control and coordinate the computer hardware","index":"b"},{"value":"the software governing the organization of data on physical storage media.","index":"c"},{"value":"the hardware and software used to transfer data.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"The hardware and software used to transfer data in an organization is called:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"40","option":[{"value":"data management technology.","index":"a"},{"value":"networking and data management technology.","index":"b"},{"value":"data and telecommunications technology.","index":"c"},{"value":"networking and telecommunications technology.","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"Networking and telecommunications technologies, along with computer hardware, software, data management technology, and the people required to run and manage them, constitute an organization’s:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 19–20","number":"41","option":[{"value":"data management environment.","index":"a"},{"value":"networked environment.","index":"b"},{"value":"IT infrastructure.","index":"c"},{"value":"information system.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"An example of a business using information systems to create new products and services is:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 11","number":"42","option":[{"value":"Wal-Mart’s RetailLink system.","index":"a"},{"value":"the Mandarin Oriental hotel’s customer-preference tracking system.","index":"b"},{"value":"Verizon’s Web-based digital dashboard.","index":"c"},{"value":"Apple Inc.’s iPod.","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"An example of a business using information systems to attain operational excellence is:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 10","number":"43","option":[{"value":"Wal-Mart’s RetailLink system.","index":"a"},{"value":"the Mandarin Oriental hotel’s customer-preference tracking system.","index":"b"},{"value":"Verizon’s Web-based digital dashboard.","index":"c"},{"value":"Apple Inc.’s iPod.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"An example of a business using information systems for customer and supplier intimacy is:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 11","number":"44","option":[{"value":"Wal-Mart’s RetailLink system.","index":"a"},{"value":"the Mandarin Oriental hotel’s customer-preference tracking system.","index":"b"},{"value":"Verizon’s Web-based digital dashboard.","index":"c"},{"value":"Apple Inc.’s iPod.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"Maintaining the organization’s financial records is a business function of:","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18","number":"45","option":[{"value":"accounting.","index":"a"},{"value":"finance.","index":"b"},{"value":"sales.","index":"c"},{"value":"marketing.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Based on the examples in the chapter, if you were asked to formulate a plan for a regional drive- in restaurant chain’s efforts to use information technology to attract customers, what would be the best use of information technology from the list below:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 11","number":"46","option":[{"value":"Use IT to increase supplier loyalty.","index":"a"},{"value":"Use IT to increase operational efficiency.","index":"b"},{"value":"Use IT to create new products and business models.","index":"c"},{"value":"Use IT to help survive government reporting requirements.","index":"d"},{"value":"Use IT to achieve customer intimacy.","index":"e"}],"answer":"e"},{"type":1,"question":"The fact that online advertising revenues are growing at 30% a year, while offline traditional advertising is growing at about 5% a year, suggests that:","diff":"Hard Reference p. 11","chapter":1,"number":"47","option":[{"value":"Internet advertising is very inexpensive.","index":"a"},{"value":"offline traditional advertising is not very effective.","index":"b"},{"value":"the Internet is transforming the traditional advertising business model.","index":"c"},{"value":"new technologies are more efficient at selling to customers.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Toyota Motor Europe’s vehicle orders management system allows it to improve efficiency by basing vehicle production on:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 3","number":"48","option":[{"value":"superior forecasts of regional demand.","index":"a"},{"value":"actual customer orders.","index":"b"},{"value":"improved decision making.","index":"c"},{"value":"customer preferences.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"In a business hierarchy, the level that is responsible for monitoring the daily activities of the business is:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"49","option":[{"value":"middle management.","index":"a"},{"value":"service workers.","index":"b"},{"value":"production management.","index":"c"},{"value":"operational management.","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"Which of the following are environmental actors that interact with an organization and its information systems?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 15","number":"50","option":[{"value":"Customers","index":"a"},{"value":"Suppliers","index":"b"},{"value":"Regulatory agencies","index":"c"},{"value":"All of the above","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"From a business perspective, raw data is transformed systematically during various stages, transforming it into valuable information, in a process called:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 23","number":"51","option":[{"value":"the information value chain.","index":"a"},{"value":"the IT value chain.","index":"b"},{"value":"information processing.","index":"c"},{"value":"feedback.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"A corporation that funds a political action committee, which in turn promotes and funds a political candidate who agrees with the values of that corporation, could be seen as investing in which main category of complementary assets?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 25","number":"52","option":[{"value":"Managerial","index":"a"},{"value":"Governmental","index":"b"},{"value":"Social","index":"c"},{"value":"Organizational","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Apple Computer dominates the online legal music sales industry primarily because of a failure of recording label companies to:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"number":"53","option":[{"value":"invest in technology.","index":"a"},{"value":"adopt a new business model.","index":"b"},{"value":"invest in complementary assets.","index":"c"},{"value":"modernize their information value chain.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"An example of an organizational complementary asset is:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"number":"54","option":[{"value":"using the appropriate business model.","index":"a"},{"value":"as collaborative work environment.","index":"b"},{"value":"laws and regulations.","index":"c"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"An example of a social complementary asset is:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 25","number":"55","option":[{"value":"technology and service firms in adjacent markets.","index":"a"},{"value":"training programs.","index":"b"},{"value":"distributed decision-making rights.","index":"c"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Disciplines that contribute to the technical approach to information systems are:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 26","number":"56","option":[{"value":"computer science, engineering, and networking.","index":"a"},{"value":"operations research, management science, and computer science.","index":"b"},{"value":"engineering, utilization management, and computer science.","index":"c"},{"value":"management science, computer science, and engineering.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"The discipline that focuses on mathematical techniques for optimizing parameters of organizations, such as transportation and inventory control is:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 27","number":"57","option":[{"value":"management science.","index":"a"},{"value":"MIS.","index":"b"},{"value":"operations research.","index":"c"},{"value":"utilization management.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Sociologists study information systems with an eye to understanding:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 27","number":"58","option":[{"value":"how systems affect individuals, groups, and organizations.","index":"a"},{"value":"how human decision makers perceive and use formal information.","index":"b"},{"value":"how new information systems change the control and cost structures within the firm.","index":"c"},{"value":"the production of digital goods.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Psychologists study information systems with an eye to understanding:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 27","number":"59","option":[{"value":"how systems affect individuals, groups, and organizations.","index":"a"},{"value":"how human decision makers perceive and use formal information.","index":"b"},{"value":"how new information systems change the control and cost structures within the firm.","index":"c"},{"value":"the production of digital goods.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"The costs for firms operating on a global scale have been drastically reduced by:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 7","number":"60","option":[{"value":"networking technology.","index":"a"},{"value":"investments in organizational complementary assets.","index":"b"},{"value":"the Internet.","index":"c"},{"value":"the rise of digital content.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Key corporate assets are:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 7","number":"61","option":[{"value":"intellectual property, core competencies, and financial and human assets.","index":"a"},{"value":"production technologies and business processes for sales, marketing, and finance.","index":"b"},{"value":"knowledge and the firm’s tangible assets, such as goods or services.","index":"c"},{"value":"time and knowledge.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Overproduction or underproduction of goods and services, misallocation of resources, and poor response times are the results of a firm’s having:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 12","number":"62","option":[{"value":"poor relationships with suppliers.","index":"a"},{"value":"poor relationships with customers.","index":"b"},{"value":"inadequate information.","index":"c"},{"value":"surplus of information.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"A firm that must invest in new information systems capabilities in order to comply with federal legislation can be said to be investing to achieve which business objective?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 13","number":"63","option":[{"value":"Customer intimacy","index":"a"},{"value":"Operational excellence","index":"b"},{"value":"Survival","index":"c"},{"value":"Improved reporting","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Which of the following would not be used as an input for an information system?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 15","number":"64","option":[{"value":"Digital dashboard","index":"a"},{"value":"Handheld computer","index":"b"},{"value":"Bar-code scanner","index":"c"},{"value":"Cell phone","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"Which field of study focuses on both a behavioral and technical understanding of information systems?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 16–17","number":"65","option":[{"value":"Sociology","index":"a"},{"value":"Operations research","index":"b"},{"value":"Economics","index":"c"},{"value":"Management information systems","index":"d"}],"answer":"d"},{"type":1,"question":"The three principle levels within a business organization hierarchy are:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"66","option":[{"value":"senior management, operational management, and service workers.","index":"a"},{"value":"senior management, middle management, and operational management.","index":"b"},{"value":"senior management, operational management, and information systems.","index":"c"},{"value":"senior management, middle management, and service workers.","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"Engineers, scientists, or architects, who design new products or services for a firm, belong to which level of a business hierarchy?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"67","option":[{"value":"Middle management","index":"a"},{"value":"Production workers","index":"b"},{"value":"Knowledge workers","index":"c"},{"value":"Data workers","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":1,"question":"Which main business function is responsible for maintaining employee records?","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18","number":"68","option":[{"value":"Sales and marketing","index":"a"},{"value":"Human resources","index":"b"},{"value":"Finance and accounting","index":"c"},{"value":"Manufacturing and production","index":"d"}],"answer":"b"},{"type":1,"question":"An organizational element in the UPS tracking system described in the chapter is:","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 22","number":"69","option":[{"value":"the specification of procedures for identifying packages with sender and recipient information.","index":"a"},{"value":"monitoring service levels.","index":"b"},{"value":"promoting the company strategy of low-cost, superior service.","index":"c"},{"value":"the use of handheld computers and networks for managing package delivery.","index":"d"}],"answer":"a"},{"type":1,"question":"A managerial element in the UPS tracking system described in the chapter is:","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 22","number":"70","option":[{"value":"taking inventory.","index":"a"},{"value":"providing package status reports to customers.","index":"b"},{"value":"the decision to use automation.","index":"c"},{"value":"in-house package tracking software.","index":"d"}],"answer":"c"},{"type":2,"question":"________ is data that has been shaped into a form that is meaningful to human beings.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 14","number":"71","case":"Content","answer":"Information"},{"type":2,"question":"________ is output returned to appropriate members of the organization to help them evaluate or correct the input stage.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 15","number":"72","case":"Content","answer":"Feedback"},{"type":2,"question":"________ is a global network that uses universal standards to connect millions of different networks around the world.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"73","case":"Content","answer":"The Internet"},{"type":2,"question":"________ consists of the detailed, preprogrammed instructions that control and coordinate the computer hardware components in an information system.\n￼￼￼￼14","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"74","case":"Content","answer":"Computer software"},{"type":2,"question":"The ________ is a service provided by the Internet that uses universally accepted standards for storing, retrieving, formatting, and displaying information in a page format.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"75","case":"Content","answer":"World Wide Web/Web/WWW"},{"type":2,"question":"________ are private corporate networks extended to authorized users outside the organization.","diff":"Easy","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 19","number":"76","case":"Content","answer":"Extranets"},{"type":2,"question":"The key elements of an organization are its people, structure, business processes, politics, and ________.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18","number":"77","case":"Content","answer":"culture"},{"type":2,"question":"In a ________, the performance of a system is optimized when both the technology and the organization mutually adjust to one another until a satisfactory fit is obtained.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 28","number":"78","case":"Content","answer":"sociotechnical perspectiveview"},{"type":2,"question":"________ makes long-range strategic decisions about the firm’s products and services.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 17","number":"79","case":"Content","answer":"Senior management"},{"type":2,"question":"Investments in organization and management, such as investments in new business models and training, are also known as ________.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 25","number":"80","case":"Content","answer":"organizational and management capital"},{"type":2,"question":"Define operational excellence. How can information systems help achieve it?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 8–11","number":"81","case":"Content","answer":"Operational excellence is the achievement of higher levels of productivity, efficiency, and profitability. Information systems can help achieve operational excellence by improving communications to supplier and optimizing the supply chain. Information systems could help managers communicate with workers more efficiently, enable technological innovation in products, minimize warehouse overhead, and streamline distribution."},{"type":2,"question":"(Synthesis)\nYou work for an auto manufacturer and distributor. How could you use information systems to achieve greater customer intimacy?\nSynthesis in terms of bringing knowledge together","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 11","number":"82","case":"Content","answer":"You could create a Web site that allows customers to customize cars, communicate with support personnel and other car owners. You could create an automated e-mail service reminding car owners to take their car in for periodic checkups. You could have an information system that tracks customer preferences in local areas, so you can provide cars that reflect local customer needs and desires."},{"type":2,"question":"What is the difference between information technology and information systems? Describe some of the functions of information systems.","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 14","number":"83","case":"Content","answer":"Information technology (IT) consists of all the hardware and software that a firm needs to use to achieve its business objectives. Information systems are more complex. An information system can be defined technically as a set of interrelated components that collect (or retrieve), process, store, and distribute information to support decision making and control in an organization.\nAn information system:\n• Supports decision making, coordination, and control\n• Helps employees analyze problems\n• Helps employees visualize complex subjects\n• Helps create new products"},{"type":2,"question":"(Synthesis)\nYou are a marketing manager for a national movie theater chain. Give an example of data that your department could use for creating meaningful information. What type of information could that data produce?\n(Synthesis in terms of bringing knowledge together)","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 14","number":"84","case":"Content","answer":"Movie ticket sales from individual theaters would be an example of raw data. Meaningful information from this would be: average number of tickets sold to seniors on certain days of the week."},{"type":2,"question":"(Synthesis)\nDefine business process. What might be a business process used at a hospital?\n(Synthesis in terms of bringing knowledge together)","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 7","number":"85","case":"Content","answer":"A business process is a set of logically related tasks and behaviors for accomplishing work. Hiring a new employee, customer intake, and filing medical records are examples of business processes at a hospital."},{"type":2,"question":"(Synthesis)\nYou are starting a small bike messenger company. Given your type of services (hand- delivering packages within a small geographical area), could your firm be a digital firm? If so, what would make this a digital firm?\n(Synthesis in terms of model)","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p.7","number":"86","case":"Content","answer":"Being a digital firm doesn’t purely rely on having digital goods and services. A digital firm would have most of its relationships with customers, suppliers, and employees be digitally enabled. Ordering deliveries, assigning deliveries, managing employees and assignments could certainly be digitally enabled; using cell phones, information systems, and handheld devices to connect customers, delivery management, and bike messengers."},{"type":2,"question":"(Evaluation)\nThis chapter discusses how each organization has its own culture and sets of values shared by most of its members. What kind of shared values might you find at a law firm?","diff":"Medium","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 18 (Evaluation in terms of assess, choose)","number":"87","case":"Content","answer":"Shared values at a law firm might be: The legal system works, the legal system is fair, lawyers help people, and people need help with the legal system because it is complicated."},{"type":2,"question":"(Synthesis)\nYou work at the business headquarters for a chain of movie theaters. Describe this\nfirm’s information value chain.\n(Synthesis in terms of propose, model)","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 22–23","number":"88","case":"Content","answer":"An information value chain adds value to data at various stages, transforming it into valuable data. At a chain of movie theaters, data would be gathered from ticket sales and concession sales. Information systems would help transform this into meaningful information, such as determining the types of movies popular in certain regions, times and days of the week that people most often saw movies, what snacks were the most popular. This information would be valuable in making decisions, such as offering ticket discounts during less popular time slots, and offering more popular snack items. Further feedback based on the results of these decisions could determine whether these decisions were effective."},{"type":2,"question":"(Evaluation)\nWhich dimension of information systems do you feel was the most important source of problems discussed in this chapter’s study of the Morgan Stanley and Dean Witter merger? Why?","diff":"Hard","chapter":1,"ref":"p. 35 (Evaluation in terms of appraise, assess)","number":"89","case":"Content","answer":"Student answers will vary. The following is an example of a possible answer: The problems with the merger were primarily technical. The employees at Retail Brokerage felt underappreciated because their information systems were antiquated. Brokers had to work overtime and clients did not receive good information from reports or the Web site. This led to both customers and brokers leaving the firm. In addition, the CEO Philip Purcell underestimated investing in technology, placing the company in a poor position when the market rebounded. In discussing the company’s problems, Chief Executive Mack stated that divisions of Morgan Stanley had not received the technology they needed."},{"type":2,"number":"90","diff":"Medium","option":[{"value":"Based on your reading of Chapter 1, which of the six strategic business objectives does Accenture’s information systems contribute to?","index":"s"}],"chapter":1,"ref":"pp. 8–13","question":"(Evaluate)\n(Evaluate in terms of appraise, choose)","case":"Content","answer":"Student answers will vary. The following is an example of a possible answer: Accenture’s information systems allow its mobile workforce to be within easy, constant reach of its customers, contributing to the business objective of customer and supplier intimacy. Additionally, the ability of employees to connect to and work with local branch information systems in standard ways, regardless of their location, contributes to more efficient processes and operational excellence."},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"1","number":"1","ref":"45","question":"Operational management is responsible for directing the day-to-day operations of the business and therefore needs transaction-level information.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"2","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"45-47","question":"Deciding whether to introduce a new product line is the responsibility of an operational manager.","case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.1","diff":"3","number":"3","ref":"42","question":"Tata Motors had to revise many of its manufacturing processes to support digital manufacturing.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"4","ref":"45","question":"Transaction processing systems are most commonly used by the senior management level of an organization.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","diff":"1","number":"5","ref":"45","question":"A transaction processing system is a computerized system that performs and records the daily routine transactions necessary to conduct business.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"6","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"45","question":"A hotel reservation system is a typical example of a management information system.","case":"Content Objective: 2.5","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"48","question":"Management information systems typically support nonroutine decision making.","case":"Content Objective: 2.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.1","diff":"2","number":"8","ref":"43","question":"Enrolling employees in benefits plans is a business process handled by the finance and accounting function.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"9","ref":"45","question":"Functional systems that support business processes within a single functional group, such as human resources, are being phased out in favor of cross-functional systems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"10","ref":"46","question":"Managers need TPSs to monitor the status of internal operations and the firm's relations with the external environment.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"11","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"45-46, 49","question":"Most MISs use sophisticated mathematical models or statistical techniques.","case":"Content Objective: 2.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"1","number":"12","ref":"48","question":"Decision-support systems help managers make decisions that are unique, rapidly changing, and not easily specified in advance.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"13","ref":"48","question":"Decision-support systems use internal information as well as information from external sources.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"14","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"51","question":"ESSs are designed to serve the middle management of the organization.","case":"Content Objective: 2.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"15","ref":"51","question":"ESSs are designed to incorporate data about external events, but they also draw summarized information from internal MIS and DSS.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"16","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"51","question":"ESSs are designed primarily to solve specific problems.","case":"Content Objective: 2.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","diff":"2","number":"17","ref":"55","question":"Information supplied by an enterprise system is structured around cross-functional business processes.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"18","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"52-55","question":"Enterprise systems often include transactions with customers and vendors.","case":"Content Objective: 2.3","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"19","diff":"3","chapter":2,"ref":"56-57","question":"Supply chain management systems are more externally oriented than enterprise systems.","case":"Analysis Objective: 2.3","answer":"true"},{"chapter":2,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"20","ref":"59","question":"Maintaining online directories of employees with special areas of expertise is one application of knowledge management systems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"21","option":[{"value":"KMS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS","index":"B"},{"value":"DSS","index":"C"},{"value":"ESS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"41-42","question":"Tata Motor's new information system, enabling it to automate processes in product design and production engineering planning, is best categorized as a(n)","diff":"3","answer":"a"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"finance and accounting","index":"A"},{"value":"human resources","index":"B"},{"value":"manufacturing and production","index":"C"},{"value":"sales and marketing","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"22","ref":"43","question":"Identifying customers is a responsibility of the ________ function.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"finance and accounting","index":"A"},{"value":"human resources","index":"B"},{"value":"manufacturing and production","index":"C"},{"value":"sales and marketing","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"23","ref":"43","question":"Producing bills of materials is a business process within the ________ function.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"24","option":[{"value":"identifying customers","index":"A"},{"value":"creating a new product","index":"B"},{"value":"assembling a product","index":"C"},{"value":"paying creditors","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"43","question":"Which of the following is an example of a cross-functional business process?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"25","option":[{"value":"ESS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS","index":"B"},{"value":"MIS","index":"C"},{"value":"DSS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"45-46","question":"Which type of system would you use to change a production schedule if a key supplier was late in delivering goods?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"decision-support","index":"A"},{"value":"knowledge","index":"B"},{"value":"transaction processing","index":"C"},{"value":"management information","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"26","ref":"46","question":"To monitor the status of internal operations and the firm's relations with the external environment, managers need ________ systems.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"transaction processing systems","index":"A"},{"value":"management information systems","index":"B"},{"value":"executive support systems","index":"C"},{"value":"decision-support systems","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"27","ref":"46","question":"Which systems are typically a major source of data for other systems?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"28","option":[{"value":"ESS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS","index":"B"},{"value":"MIS","index":"C"},{"value":"DSS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"47-48","question":"Which type of system would you use to determine the five suppliers with the worst record in delivering goods on time?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"knowledge management systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"transaction processing systems.","index":"B"},{"value":"executive-support systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"management information systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"29","ref":"47-48","question":"A relocation control system that reports summaries on the total moving, house-hunting, and home financing costs for employees in all company divisions would fall into the category of","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"integrated data processing throughout the firm.","index":"A"},{"value":"transaction process reporting.","index":"B"},{"value":"employees with online access to historical records.","index":"C"},{"value":"middle management functions.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"30","ref":"47-48","question":"The term \"management information systems\" designates a specific category of information systems serving:","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"MIS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS","index":"B"},{"value":"ESS","index":"C"},{"value":"DSS","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"31","ref":"48","question":"Decisions that are unique, rapidly changing, and not easily specified in advance are best suited to which type of system?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"Management information","index":"A"},{"value":"Transaction processing","index":"B"},{"value":"Decision-support","index":"C"},{"value":"Knowledge management","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"32","ref":"48","question":"________ systems are especially suited to situations in which the procedure for arriving at a solution may not be fully defined in advance.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"33","option":[{"value":"ESS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS","index":"B"},{"value":"MIS","index":"C"},{"value":"DSS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"48-49","question":"Which type of system would you use to forecast the return on investment if you used new suppliers with better delivery track records?","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"information","index":"A"},{"value":"intelligence","index":"B"},{"value":"analysis","index":"C"},{"value":"modeling","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"34","ref":"49","question":"Decision-support systems are often referred to as business ________ systems.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"enhanced visibility of fleetwide data","index":"A"},{"value":"support of existing business model and enterprise resource planning and financial software","index":"B"},{"value":"increased operational efficiencies","index":"C"},{"value":"ability to match work requirements against changing locations and flight schedules","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"35","ref":"50","question":"Which benefits of AirCanada's new Maintenix software best illustrate the DSS capabilities of their new information system?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"operational","index":"A"},{"value":"end-user","index":"B"},{"value":"middle management","index":"C"},{"value":"senior management","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"36","ref":"51","question":"ESS are specifically designed to serve which level of the organization?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"long-range planning activities of senior management.","index":"A"},{"value":"knowledge and data workers in an organization.","index":"B"},{"value":"decision-making and administrative activities of middle managers.","index":"C"},{"value":"day-to-day processes of production.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"37","ref":"51","question":"Executive support systems are information systems that support the","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"transaction processing systems","index":"A"},{"value":"executive support systems","index":"B"},{"value":"management information systems","index":"C"},{"value":"decision-support systems","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"38","ref":"51","question":"Which systems often deliver information to senior executives through a portal, which uses a Web interface to present integrated personalized business content?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"39","option":[{"value":"ESS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS","index":"B"},{"value":"MIS","index":"C"},{"value":"DSS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"51","question":"Which type of system would you use to determine what trends in your supplier's industry will affect your firm the most in five years?","diff":"1","answer":"a"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 2.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"40","option":[{"value":"increasing speed of communicating","index":"A"},{"value":"enabling business functions and departments to share information","index":"B"},{"value":"enabling a company to work collaboratively with customers and suppliers","index":"C"},{"value":"enabling cost-effective e-business processes","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"52-54","question":"What is the most important function of an enterprise application?","diff":"3","answer":"b"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"Decision-support systems","index":"A"},{"value":"Management information systems","index":"B"},{"value":"CRM systems","index":"C"},{"value":"Enterprise applications","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"41","ref":"52-54","question":"________ are designed to support organization-wide process coordination and integration.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"transaction","index":"A"},{"value":"enterprise","index":"B"},{"value":"automatic reporting","index":"C"},{"value":"management information","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"42","ref":"55","question":"A(n) ________ system collects data from various key business processes and stores the data in a single, comprehensive data repository, usable by other parts of the business.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 2.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"43","option":[{"value":"CRM","index":"A"},{"value":"enterprise system","index":"B"},{"value":"extranet","index":"C"},{"value":"intranet","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"52-59","question":"You manage the IT department at a small startup Internet advertiser. You need to set up an inexpensive system that allows customers to see real-time statistics such as views and click- throughs about their current banner ads. Which type of system will most efficiently provide a solution?","diff":"3","answer":"c"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"44","option":[{"value":"POS system","index":"A"},{"value":"DSS","index":"B"},{"value":"CRM","index":"C"},{"value":"KMS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"53","question":"The Smart Site Solution system used by Johnny's Lunch to help identify the best locations to open new franchises is best categorized as a","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"45","option":[{"value":"TPS","index":"A"},{"value":"ESS","index":"B"},{"value":"CRM","index":"C"},{"value":"KMS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"53-54","question":"The MICROS system used by Johnny's Lunch to captures sales transaction data and help monitor inventory, control waste, and adhere to government regulations is best categorized as a(n)","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"SCMs, CRMs, DSSs, and KMSs.","index":"A"},{"value":"SCMs, CRMs, ESSs, and KMSs.","index":"B"},{"value":"enterprise systems, SCMs, DSSs, and CRMs.","index":"C"},{"value":"enterprise systems, SCMs, CRMs, and KMSs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"46","ref":"54","question":"The four major enterprise applications are","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"resource planning","index":"A"},{"value":"enterprise resource planning","index":"B"},{"value":"enterprise support","index":"C"},{"value":"management information","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"47","ref":"55","question":"Enterprise systems are also known as ________ systems.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"SCMs","index":"A"},{"value":"TPSs","index":"B"},{"value":"KMSs","index":"C"},{"value":"ERPs","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"48","ref":"56","question":"Enabling management to make better decisions regarding organizing and scheduling sourcing, production, and distribution is a central feature of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"Collaborative distribution","index":"A"},{"value":"Supply-chain management","index":"B"},{"value":"Reverse logistics","index":"C"},{"value":"Enterprise planning","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"49","ref":"56","question":"________ systems integrate supplier, manufacturer, distributor, and customer logistics processes.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"CRM","index":"A"},{"value":"MIS","index":"B"},{"value":"CLE","index":"C"},{"value":"CLU","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"50","ref":"57","question":"________ uses a set of integrated applications to address all aspects of the customer relationship.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"TPS","index":"A"},{"value":"Extranets","index":"B"},{"value":"KMS","index":"C"},{"value":"CRM","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"51","ref":"58","question":"Which types of systems consolidate the relevant knowledge and experience in the firm to make it available to improve business processes and management decision making?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"52","option":[{"value":"distributing documents","index":"A"},{"value":"documenting the expertise of company specialists","index":"B"},{"value":"enabling the discovery of new product applications","index":"C"},{"value":"discovering new sales channels for a product","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"58-59","question":"An information system for ________ would NOT be categorized as a KMS.","diff":"1","answer":"d"},{"case":"Synthesis Objective: 2.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"53","option":[{"value":"CRM","index":"A"},{"value":"MIS","index":"B"},{"value":"TPS","index":"C"},{"value":"KMS","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"59","question":"Which type of information system is an intranet most easily adapted to?","diff":"3","answer":"d"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"intranet","index":"A"},{"value":"extranet","index":"B"},{"value":"KMS","index":"C"},{"value":"TPS","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"54","ref":"59","question":"Which of the following types of system helps expedite the flow of information between the firm and its suppliers and customers?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"55","option":[{"value":"sales representative","index":"A"},{"value":"business manager","index":"B"},{"value":"engineer","index":"C"},{"value":"operations manager","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"60","question":"Which of the following occupations would NOT be categorized as an \"interaction\" job?","diff":"1","answer":"c"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"56","option":[{"value":"How long will it take to manufacture this product?","index":"A"},{"value":"Should we collaborate with outside vendors on new products and services?","index":"B"},{"value":"In which geographical locations are our products garnering the most sales?","index":"C"},{"value":"Which product design is the most efficient for the user in terms of energy use?","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"60","question":"Which of the following decisions requires knowledge based on collaboration and interaction?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.4","option":[{"value":"the Internet and networking technologies","index":"A"},{"value":"e-commerce","index":"B"},{"value":"e-business","index":"C"},{"value":"any computerized technology","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"57","ref":"62","question":"E-government refers to the application of ________ to digitally enable government and public sector agencies' relationships with citizens, businesses, and other arms of government.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.4","option":[{"value":"e-commerce.","index":"A"},{"value":"e-business.","index":"B"},{"value":"an intranet.","index":"C"},{"value":"an extranet.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"58","ref":"62","question":"Buying or selling goods over the Internet is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.4","option":[{"value":"e-commerce.","index":"A"},{"value":"e-business.","index":"B"},{"value":"enterprise applications.","index":"C"},{"value":"MIS.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"59","ref":"62","question":"The use of digital technology and the Internet to execute the major business processes in the enterprise is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"programmer.","index":"A"},{"value":"information systems manager.","index":"B"},{"value":"systems analyst.","index":"C"},{"value":"CTO.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"60","ref":"63","question":"The principal liaison between the information systems groups and the rest of the organization is a(n)","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"CEO","index":"A"},{"value":"CFO","index":"B"},{"value":"CIO","index":"C"},{"value":"CTO","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"61","ref":"63","question":"A ________ is a senior manager who oversees the use of IT in the firm.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"CTO","index":"A"},{"value":"CSO","index":"B"},{"value":"CKO","index":"C"},{"value":"CPO","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"62","ref":"64","question":"The ________ helps design programs and systems to find new sources of knowledge or to make better use of existing knowledge in organizational and management processes.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"ensuring that the company complies with existing data privacy laws.","index":"A"},{"value":"making better use of existing knowledge in organizational and management processes.","index":"B"},{"value":"enforcing the firm's information security policy.","index":"C"},{"value":"overseeing the use of information technology in the firm.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"63","ref":"64","question":"The CPO is responsible for","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"this is more likely to produce more compatible systems and more coherent long-term systems development plans.","index":"A"},{"value":"this lowers costs of technology purchases.","index":"B"},{"value":"systems are built that directly address that function's business needs.","index":"C"},{"value":"systems are built that can function independently and more efficiently.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"64","ref":"64","question":"The advantage of a having a centralized information services department that operates as a separate department similar to other departments is that","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"writing software instructions for computers","index":"A"},{"value":"acting as liaison between the information systems group and the rest of the organization","index":"B"},{"value":"translating business problems into information requirements","index":"C"},{"value":"managing data entry staff","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"65","ref":"63","question":"Which of the following roles falls into the duties of an information systems manager?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"as departments within each functional area","index":"A"},{"value":"as a separate, centralized department","index":"B"},{"value":"represented within each major division of the company","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"66","ref":"64-66","question":"Which of the following types of organizing the information systems function would you be most likely to find in a small company with 20 employees?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","option":[{"value":"as departments within each functional area","index":"A"},{"value":"as a separate, centralized department","index":"B"},{"value":"represented within each major division of the company","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"67","ref":"64-66","question":"Which of the following types of organizing the information systems function would you be most likely to find in a very large, multinational corporation?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Synthesis Objective: 2.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"68","option":[{"value":"an intranet with KMS capabilities","index":"A"},{"value":"an extranet with KMS capabilities","index":"B"},{"value":"a TPS with KMS capabilities","index":"C"},{"value":"a CRM","index":"D"}],"chapter":2,"ref":"45-59","question":"You work for a highly successful advertiser that is just about to expand nationally. Of utmost importance will be finding a way to store and disseminate their clients' continually updated branding guides, which include multiple image files and text documents, to all of the firm's branches. What system will best serve these needs?","diff":"3","answer":"b"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"2.2","option":[{"value":"TPS","index":"A"},{"value":"TPS with DSS capabilities","index":"B"},{"value":"TPS with MIS capabilities","index":"C"},{"value":"TPS with ESS capabilities","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"69","ref":"45-49","question":"You have been hired by a non-profit agency to implement a system to handle their donations. Event fundraisers need to be able to quickly access a donor's information and history. The marketing department needs to be able to create customized mailing lists, in order to send different messages to different types of donors. What system will best meet these needs?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":2,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"2.3","option":[{"value":"Extranet, to enable quick collaboration over the Internet , minimize the time spent communicating with the client, and minimize the amount of paperwork needed","index":"A"},{"value":"CRM, to maintain easily accessible customer records to minimize the time spent looking for client data","index":"B"},{"value":"KMS, for minimizing redundant work on similar clients","index":"C"},{"value":"marketing system, for improving sales levels","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"70","ref":"45-49","question":"You have been hired by Inspiration Inc, to help improve their profit margin. Inspiration Inc. is a business communications consultancy that services many clients in different industries throughout the United States. The end products of the company are customized recommendations for the best use of a client's existing resources for improving internal communications, typically delivered via documentation in different media. The company has approximately 100 consultants, all of whom are located in their central headquarters in Chicago. What system do you recommend to improve the company's business processes and increase their profit margin?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.1","diff":"1","number":"71","ref":"43","question":"A(n) ________ is a set of logically related activities for accomplishing a specific business result.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"business process"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"2","number":"72","ref":"51","question":"A Web interface used to present integrated personalized business content to users is called a(n) ________.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"portal"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","diff":"2","number":"73","ref":"52","question":"________ applications span the entire firm, integrating information from multiple functions and business processes to enhance the performance of the organization as a whole.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Enterprise"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"1","number":"74","ref":"48","question":"________ systems are used by middle management to combine data and sophisticated analytical models or data analysis tools to support nonroutine decision making.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Decision-support"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","diff":"3","number":"75","ref":"66","question":"IT ________ includes the strategy and policies for using information technology within an organization.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"governance"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.2","diff":"1","number":"76","ref":"43","question":"The ________ function is responsible for attracting, developing, and maintaining the firm's workforce.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"human resources"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"77","diff":"3","chapter":2,"ref":"62","question":"A state Web site that allows citizens to pay parking fines online is a form of ________.","case":"Analysis Objective: 2.4","answer":"e-government"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.3","diff":"2","number":"78","ref":"56","question":"Supply chain management systems are one type of ________ system because they automate the flow of information across organizational boundaries.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"interorganizational"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","diff":"1","number":"79","ref":"63","question":"________ are highly trained technical specialists who write the software instructions for computers.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Programmers"},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"2.5","diff":"1","number":"80","ref":"64","question":"________ are representatives of departments outside of the information systems group for whom applications are developed.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"End users"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"81","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"45-52","question":"Identify and discuss the major types of information systems that serve the main management groups within a business. What are the relationships among these systems?","case":"Analysis Objective: 2.2","answer":"The four major categories of information systems are:\n1. Transaction processing systems, such as payroll or order processing, track the flow of the daily routine transactions that are necessary to conduct business.\n2. Management-information systems (MIS) provide the management control level with reports and access to the organization's current performance and historical records. Most MIS reports condense information from TPS and are not highly analytical.\n3. Decision-support systems (DSS) support management decisions when these decisions are unique, rapidly changing, and not specified easily in advance. They have more advanced analytical models and data analysis capabilities than MIS and often draw on information from external as well as internal sources.\n4. Executive-support systems (ESS) support senior management by providing data of greatest importance to senior management decision makers, often in the form of graphs and charts delivered via portals. They have limited analytical capabilities but can draw on sophisticated graphics software and many sources of internal and external information.\nThe various types of systems in the organization exchange data with one another. TPS are a major source of data for other systems, especially MIS and DSS. ESSs primarily receive data from lower-level systems."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"82","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"61-62","question":"You have been hired to work with 10 salespeople from different branches of a national business in creating an online training site for new Sales employees. Identify six collaboration tools that are available to help the team work together. Which single tool would be the most helpful for the project, in your opinion, and why?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 2.2","answer":"Collaboration tools include (1) Internet-based collaboration environment; (2) E-mail and instant messaging; (3) Cell phones and smart phones; (4) Social networking; (5) Wikis; and (6) virtual worlds. The most helpful of these might be the Internet-based collaboration environment, because it would enable people to have discussions, calendars, conferences, and share documents."},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"2.1","diff":"2","number":"83","ref":"43-44","question":"Your aunt has asked you for your suggestions to make her business, a local sandwich shop, more efficient. Describe at least three types of business processes that a sandwich shop have. Can any be better coordinated through the use of information systems?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The business processes of a sandwich shop would include: Taking orders, making sandwiches, selling to the customer, ordering supplies, opening the store, closing the store, cleaning the store, paying employees, hiring employees, paying creditors and vendors, creating financial statements, paying taxes, managing cash.\nMany of these processes could be helped by better information systems, specifically those that require recorded data, such as any financial processes (payments, cash management, taxes, salaries) and information gathered from and distributed to employees."},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"2.5","diff":"2","number":"84","ref":"66","question":"Describe the role of IT governance within the firm.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"IT governance is the management of how the information systems function is organized and handled within the firm. IT governance includes the strategy and policies for using information technology within an organization. It specifies the decision rights and framework for accountability to ensure that the use of information technology supports the organization's strategies and objectives. For example, IT governance decides how decisions implementing and evaluating new systems are made, whether the IT function should be decentralized or centralized, who has power to create and manage systems, and what kind of ROI is expected from systems."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"85","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"45-52","question":"Apex Vacuum, a family-owned manufacturer of budget vacuums, has grown exponentially over the last few years. However, the company is having difficulty preparing for future growth. The only information system used at Apex is an antiquated accounting system. The company has one manufacturing plant located in Arkansas; and three warehouses, in Arkansas, Delaware, and California. The Apex sales force is national, and Apex purchases about a third of its vacuum parts and materials from a single overseas supplier. You have been hired to recommend the information systems Apex should implement in order to maintain their competitive edge. However, there is not enough money for a full-blown, cross-functional enterprise application, and you will need to limit the first step to a single functional area or constituency. What will you choose, and why?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 2.2","answer":"Student answers will vary. E.g. A TPS focusing on production and manufacturing to keep production costs low while maintaining quality, and for communicating with other possible vendors. The TPS would later be used to feed MIS and other higher level systems."},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"2.3","diff":"1","number":"86","ref":"52-56","question":"Describe at least two benefits of using enterprise systems.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Enterprise systems integrate the firm's key business processes in sales, production, finance, logistics, and human resources into a single software system so that information can flow throughout the organization, improving coordination, efficiency, and decision making. These systems help create a more uniform organization in which everyone uses similar processes and information, and measures their work in terms of organization-wide performance standards. The coordination of the firm's key business processes allows the firm to respond more rapidly to customer demands."},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"2.3","diff":"2","number":"87","ref":"57-58","question":"How can a good CRM system increase profits for a company?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Customer relationship management uses information systems to coordinate all of the business processes surrounding the firm's interactions with its customers. The systems consolidate customer information from multiple sourcestelephone, e-mail, wireless devices, traditional sales and marketing systems, and the Webso that the firm can obtain a unified view of a customer. This allows the firm to identify its most profitable customers and make special efforts to please them."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"88","diff":"2","chapter":2,"ref":"43-45","question":"What is the connection between organizations, information systems, and business processes?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 2.1","answer":"Business processes refer to the manner in which work activities are organized, coordinated, and focused to produce a specific business result. They also represent unique ways in which organizations coordinate work, information, and knowledge and the ways in which management chooses to coordinate work. Managers need to pay attention to business processes because they determine how well the organization can execute, and thus are a potential source for strategic success or failures. Although each of the major business functions has its own set of business processes, many other business processes are cross-functional. Information systems can help organizations achieve great efficiencies by automating parts of these processes or by helping organizations rethink and streamline them. Firms can become more flexible and efficient by coordinating and integrating their business processes to improve management of resources and customer service."},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"2.1","diff":"1","number":"89","ref":"44","question":"What are cross-functional business processes? Give an example.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Cross-functional processes are those that require input, cooperation, or coordination between the major business functions in an organization. For instance, when a salesman takes an order, the major business functions of planning, production, inventory control, shipping, accounting, and customer relations will all be involved before the order is completed."},{"chapter":2,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"2.2","diff":"3","number":"90","ref":"45-52","question":"The retail home improvement chain you work for, DIY Discount, has noticed that one of its brands of faucets is not selling nearly as well as anticipated. What information systems of the business will you use to determine the reason for the poor sales? Discuss what information you will retrieve from which system. Which of the information systems will be most important for your analysis? Which of the systems will be least important?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"You might query operational level TPS to make sure that the product is actually getting to the stores and being restocked. You could query MIS to see average sales levels according to geography, location, and other factors to see if there are any specific factors affecting the sales. You might query ESS to see if the same faucets are being sold by competitors and what these prices are. You might use DSS to see what factors could increase sales.\nAssuming that the faucets are being properly stocked at the stores, the most important systems to query are the managerial-level systems: MIS for summaries of sales records to help pinpoint any other factors; ESS to check competition, and DSS for higher-level analysis to forecast possible solutions."},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","diff":"3","number":"1","ref":"86","question":"An adhocracy is a knowledge-based organization where goods and services depend on the expertise and knowledge of professionals.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","diff":"3","number":"2","ref":"87","question":"From the point of view of economics, information systems technology can be viewed as a factor of production that can be substituted for traditional capital and labor.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"3","diff":"3","chapter":3,"ref":"95","question":"One type of competitive advantage Amazon was able to implement in selling books over the Internet was that of being a new market entrant.","case":"Analysis Objective: 3.2","answer":"true"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"2","number":"4","ref":"92","question":"A firm can be said to have competitive advantage when they have higher stock market valuations than their competitors.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"5","diff":"1","chapter":3,"ref":"92","question":"The competitive forces model was created for today's digital firm.","case":"Content Objective: 3.2","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"6","diff":"1","chapter":3,"ref":"95","question":"Customers are one of the competitive forces that affect an organization's ability to compete.","case":"Content Objective: 3.2","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"95","question":"A transparent marketplace means that there is high product differentiation.","case":"Content Objective: 3.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"2","number":"8","ref":"97","question":"In an efficient customer response system, digital answering systems are used to monitor and respond to customer inquiries.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"9","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"98","question":"Mass customization is a form of mass production.","case":"Content Objective: 3.2","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"10","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"99","question":"Strong linkages to customers and suppliers decrease switching costs.","case":"Content Objective: 3.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"2","number":"11","ref":"97","question":"In the strategy of product differentiation, information systems are used to enable new products and services.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"12","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"102","question":"The effect of the Internet has been to raise bargaining power over suppliers.","case":"Content Objective: 3.2","answer":"true"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"1","number":"13","ref":"101","question":"In the age of the Internet, Porter's traditional competitive forces model is still at work, but competitive rivalry has become much more intense.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","diff":"2","number":"14","ref":"102","question":"In the value chain model, primary activities are most directly related to the production and distribution of the firm's products and services that create value for the customer.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"15","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"102","question":"The value chain model classifies all company activities as either primary or support.","case":"Content Objective: 3.3","answer":"true"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","diff":"1","number":"16","ref":"105","question":"The idea driving synergies is that when the output of some units can be used as inputs to other units, the relationship can lower cost and generate profits.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"17","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"106","question":"The law of diminishing returns always applies to digital, as well as traditional companies.","case":"Content Objective: 3.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","diff":"2","number":"18","ref":"106","question":"In network economics, the more people that use Microsoft Office software and related products, the greater its value.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","diff":"2","number":"19","ref":"107","question":"The term business ecosystem describes the interplay between the various organizational forces within a firm.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":3,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"3.5","diff":"3","number":"20","ref":"109","question":"The use of Internet technologies allows companies to more easily sustain competitive advantage.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 3.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"21","option":[{"value":"low-cost leadership","index":"A"},{"value":"focus on market niche","index":"B"},{"value":"customer and supplier intimacy","index":"C"},{"value":"product differentiation","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"77, 97","question":"As discussed in the chapter opening case, which of the four generic strategies to combat competitive forces formed the basis of e-Bay's growth strategy?","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 3.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"22","option":[{"value":"instant messaging","index":"A"},{"value":"e-mail","index":"B"},{"value":"Internet telephony","index":"C"},{"value":"PCs","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"84-85","question":"Which of the following would NOT be considered a disruptive technology?","diff":"3","answer":"a"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"primarily guided by the decision making of middle- and senior-managers.","index":"A"},{"value":"a complex, two-way relationship mediated by factors such as the environment and organizational structure.","index":"B"},{"value":"driven by the microeconomic forces of capital and labor.","index":"C"},{"value":"successfully managed when the organization's existing culture and goals are seen as the driving force.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"23","ref":"79","question":"The interaction between information systems and organizations is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"stable, formal social structure that takes resources from the environment and processes them to produce outputs.","index":"A"},{"value":"formal, legal entity with internal rules and procedures that must abide by laws.","index":"B"},{"value":"collection of social elements.","index":"C"},{"value":"b and c","index":"D"},{"value":"a, b, and c","index":"E"}],"answer":"e","number":"24","ref":"79-80","question":"An organization is a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 3.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"25","option":[{"value":"It sees information systems as a way to rearrange the inputs and outputs of the organization.","index":"A"},{"value":"It sees capital and labor as primary production factors.","index":"B"},{"value":"It sees the inputs and outputs, labor and capital, as being infinitely malleable.","index":"C"},{"value":"It sees the organization as a social structure similar to a machine.","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"80","question":"How does the technical view of organizations fall short of understanding the full impacts of information systems in a firm?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"microeconomic","index":"A"},{"value":"macroeconomic","index":"B"},{"value":"sociotechnical","index":"C"},{"value":"behavioral","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"26","ref":"80","question":"According to the ________ definition of organizations, an organization is seen as a means by which primary production factors are transformed into outputs consumed by the environment.","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"business processes.","index":"A"},{"value":"environments.","index":"B"},{"value":"goals.","index":"C"},{"value":"agency costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"27","ref":"81-86","question":"All of the following are major features of organizations that impact the use of information systems EXCEPT for","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"informal practices and behaviors.","index":"A"},{"value":"formalized and documented practices.","index":"B"},{"value":"routines.","index":"C"},{"value":"rights and privileges.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"28","ref":"82","question":"Business processes are collections of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"entrepreneurial structure.","index":"A"},{"value":"divisionalized bureaucracy.","index":"B"},{"value":"professional bureaucracy.","index":"C"},{"value":"adhocracy.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"29","ref":"85-86","question":"Mintzberg's classification of organizational structure categorizes the knowledge-based organization where goods and services depend on the expertise and knowledge of professionals as a(n):","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"machine","index":"A"},{"value":"professional","index":"B"},{"value":"divisionalized","index":"C"},{"value":"multidivisional","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"30","ref":"86","question":"A large bureaucracy existing in a slowly changing environment that produces standard products and is dominated by centralized management making is classified by Mintzberg as a ________ bureaucracy.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"small startup firm.","index":"A"},{"value":"school system.","index":"B"},{"value":"mid-size manufacturing firm.","index":"C"},{"value":"consulting firm.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"31","ref":"86","question":"An example of a professional bureaucracy is a","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"switching costs.","index":"A"},{"value":"transaction costs.","index":"B"},{"value":"procurement.","index":"C"},{"value":"agency costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"32","ref":"87","question":"The costs incurred when a firm buys on the marketplace what it cannot make itself are referred to as:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"It helps firms expand in size.","index":"A"},{"value":"It helps firms lower the cost of market participation.","index":"B"},{"value":"It helps reduce internal management costs.","index":"C"},{"value":"It helps reduce transaction costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"33","ref":"87","question":"Which of the following statements is NOT true about information technology's impacts on business firms?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"unified, profit-maximizing entity.","index":"A"},{"value":"task force organization that must respond to rapidly changing environments.","index":"B"},{"value":"entrepreneurial endeavor.","index":"C"},{"value":"\"nexus of contracts\" among self-interested individuals.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"34","ref":"87","question":"According to agency theory, the firm is viewed as a(n):","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.1","option":[{"value":"environment, organization, structure, tasks.","index":"A"},{"value":"technology, people, culture, and structure.","index":"B"},{"value":"organization, culture, management.","index":"C"},{"value":"tasks, technology, people, and structure.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"35","ref":"90-91","question":"According to Leavitt's model of organizational resistance, the four components that must be changed in an organization in order to successfully implement a new information system are","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"network economics","index":"A"},{"value":"competitive forces","index":"B"},{"value":"competitive advantage","index":"C"},{"value":"demand control","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"36","ref":"92","question":"The ________ model is used to describe the interaction of external forces that affect an organization's strategy and ability to compete.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"suppliers","index":"A"},{"value":"other competitors","index":"B"},{"value":"external environment","index":"C"},{"value":"customers","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"37","ref":"92-95","question":"Which of the following is NOT one of the competitive forces?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 3.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"38","option":[{"value":"product differentiation","index":"A"},{"value":"traditional competitors","index":"B"},{"value":"low number of suppliers","index":"C"},{"value":"new market entrants","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"95","question":"A manufacturer of deep-sea oil rigs may be least concerned about this marketplace force.","diff":"3","answer":"d"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 3.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"39","option":[{"value":"satellite TV.","index":"A"},{"value":"broadcast TV.","index":"B"},{"value":"satellite radio.","index":"C"},{"value":"the Internet.","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"95","question":"A substitute product of most concern for a cable TV distributor is","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 3.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"40","option":[{"value":"automotive","index":"A"},{"value":"computer chip","index":"B"},{"value":"restaurant","index":"C"},{"value":"airline","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"95","question":"Which of the following industries has a low barrier to entry?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"transparent marketplace","index":"A"},{"value":"high product differentiation","index":"B"},{"value":"poor process efficiency","index":"C"},{"value":"demand control","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"41","ref":"95","question":"Which of the following can force a business and its competitors to compete on price alone?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"more suppliers.","index":"A"},{"value":"fewer suppliers.","index":"B"},{"value":"global suppliers.","index":"C"},{"value":"local suppliers.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"42","ref":"95","question":"A firm can exercise greater control over its suppliers by having","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"low-cost leadership.","index":"A"},{"value":"product differentiation.","index":"B"},{"value":"focusing on market niche.","index":"C"},{"value":"strengthening customer intimacy.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"43","ref":"96","question":"Amazon's use of the Internet as a platform to sell books illustrates a tactical use of information services for","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"low-cost leadership; substitute products and services; customers; and suppliers.","index":"A"},{"value":"low-cost leadership; product differentiation; focus on market niche; and customer and supplier intimacy.","index":"B"},{"value":"new market entrants; substitute products and services; customers; and suppliers.","index":"C"},{"value":"low-cost leadership; new market entrants; product differentiation; and focus on market niche.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"44","ref":"96","question":"The four major types of competitive strategy are","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"provide mass customization.","index":"A"},{"value":"provide an efficient customer response system.","index":"B"},{"value":"strengthen customer intimacy.","index":"C"},{"value":"achieve economy of scale.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"45","ref":"97","question":"Wal-Mart's continuous replenishment system allows it to:","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"product differentiation","index":"A"},{"value":"market niche","index":"B"},{"value":"mass customization","index":"C"},{"value":"process efficiency","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"46","ref":"98","question":"When a firm provides a specialized product or service for a narrow target market better than competitors, they are using a ________ strategy.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"Mass customization","index":"A"},{"value":"Size customization","index":"B"},{"value":"Magnitude customization","index":"C"},{"value":"Dimension customization","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"47","ref":"98","question":"________ is the ability to offer individually tailored products or services using the same production resources as bulk production.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"complex trend forecasting.","index":"A"},{"value":"tailoring products to the client.","index":"B"},{"value":"intensive product trend analysis.","index":"C"},{"value":"intensive customer data analysis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"48","ref":"98-99","question":"An information system can enable a company to focus on a market niche through","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"strengthen customer intimacy.","index":"A"},{"value":"differentiate their service.","index":"B"},{"value":"focus on market niche.","index":"C"},{"value":"increase efficiency.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"49","ref":"98","question":"Hilton Hotels' use of customer information software to identify the most profitable customers to direct services to is an example of using information systems to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"air travel, books, bill payments","index":"A"},{"value":"air travel, books, music","index":"B"},{"value":"real estate, air travel, books","index":"C"},{"value":"real estate, books, bill payments","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"50","ref":"99","question":"Which industries did the first wave of e-commerce transform?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"positioning and rivalry among competitors","index":"A"},{"value":"low cost of entry","index":"B"},{"value":"substitute products or services","index":"C"},{"value":"customer's bargaining power","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"51","ref":"101","question":"To what competitive force did the printed encyclopedia industry succumb?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"makes it easy for rivals to compete on price alone.","index":"A"},{"value":"imposes a significant cost of entry, due to infrastructure requirements.","index":"B"},{"value":"increases the difference between competitors because of the wide availability of information.","index":"C"},{"value":"makes it easy to sustain operational advantages.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"52","ref":"101","question":"Internet technology","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"creating new opportunities for building loyal customer bases.","index":"A"},{"value":"making more products available.","index":"B"},{"value":"making information available to everyone.","index":"C"},{"value":"lowering transaction costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"53","ref":"101","question":"The Internet raises the bargaining power of customers by","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","option":[{"value":"categorizes five related advantages for adding value to a firm's products or services.","index":"A"},{"value":"sees the supply chain as the primary activity for adding value.","index":"B"},{"value":"categorizes four basic strategies a firm can use to enhance its value chain.","index":"C"},{"value":"helps a firm identify points at which information technology can most effectively enhance its competitive position.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"54","ref":"102","question":"The value chain model","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","option":[{"value":"inbound logistics, operations, outbound logistics, sales and marketing, and service.","index":"A"},{"value":"inbound logistics, operations, outbound logistics, technology, and service.","index":"B"},{"value":"procurement, inbound logistics, operations, technology, and outbound logistics.","index":"C"},{"value":"procurement, operations, technology, sales and marketing, and services.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"55","ref":"102","question":"The primary activities of a firm include","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","option":[{"value":"inbound logistics, technology, outbound logistics, sales and marketing, and service.","index":"A"},{"value":"inbound logistics, organization infrastructure, outbound logistics, technology, and procurement.","index":"B"},{"value":"organization infrastructure, human resources, sales and marketing, and technology.","index":"C"},{"value":"organization infrastructure, human resources, technology, and procurement.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"56","ref":"102","question":"The secondary activities of a firm include","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","option":[{"value":"compares the efficiency and effectiveness of your business processes against strict standards.","index":"A"},{"value":"allows industry participants to influence industry-wide standards.","index":"B"},{"value":"is used to measure the speed and responsiveness of information technology.","index":"C"},{"value":"synchronizes the business processes of customers, suppliers, and trading partners.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"57","ref":"103","question":"Benchmarking","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","option":[{"value":"value activities.","index":"A"},{"value":"best processes.","index":"B"},{"value":"core competencies.","index":"C"},{"value":"best practices.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"58","ref":"103","question":"The most successful solutions or methods for achieving a business objective are called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","option":[{"value":"industry value chain.","index":"A"},{"value":"business ecosystem.","index":"B"},{"value":"value web.","index":"C"},{"value":"consortia.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"59","ref":"104","question":"A collection of independent firms that use information technology to coordinate their value chains to produce a product or service for a market collectively is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Content Objective: 3.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"60","option":[{"value":"by building industry-wide, IT-supported consortia and symposia","index":"A"},{"value":"by raising the bargaining power of suppliers","index":"B"},{"value":"by encouraging the entry of new competitors","index":"C"},{"value":"by enforcing standards that reduce the differences between competitors","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"104","question":"How are information systems used at the industry level to achieve strategic advantage?","diff":"1","answer":"a"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","option":[{"value":"a value web.","index":"A"},{"value":"a value chain.","index":"B"},{"value":"synergies.","index":"C"},{"value":"core competencies.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"61","ref":"105","question":"If two organizations pool markets and expertise that result in lower costs and generate profits it is often referred to as creating","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.4","option":[{"value":"Amazon's use of the Internet to sell books.","index":"A"},{"value":"JP Morgan Chase's merger with Bank One Corporation, which provided JP Morgan with a network of retail branches in new regions.","index":"B"},{"value":"Blockbuster combining traditional video rental with online video rental.","index":"C"},{"value":"Wal-Mart's order entry and inventory management system to coordinate with suppliers.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"62","ref":"105","question":"An example of synergy in business is","diff":"1","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","option":[{"value":"providing better reporting facilities.","index":"A"},{"value":"creating educational opportunities for management.","index":"B"},{"value":"allowing operational employees to interact with management.","index":"C"},{"value":"encouraging the sharing of knowledge across business units.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"63","ref":"106","question":"An information system can enhance core competencies by","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","option":[{"value":"the point of no return.","index":"A"},{"value":"the law of diminishing returns.","index":"B"},{"value":"supply and demand.","index":"C"},{"value":"network inelasticity.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"64","ref":"106","question":"The more any given resource is applied to production, the lower the marginal gain in output, until a point is reached where the additional inputs produce no additional output. This is referred to as","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","option":[{"value":"applies the law of diminishing returns to communities of users.","index":"A"},{"value":"applies traditional economics to networked users.","index":"B"},{"value":"sees the cost of adding new members as inconsequential.","index":"C"},{"value":"balances the high cost of adding new members to a community against the lower cost of using network infrastructure.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"65","ref":"106","question":"Network economics","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 3.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"66","option":[{"value":"increases as more people use them.","index":"A"},{"value":"decreases as more people use them.","index":"B"},{"value":"increases due to higher marginal gain in output.","index":"C"},{"value":"decreases according to the law of diminishing returns.","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"106","question":"In network economics, the value of a commercial software vendor's software products","diff":"1","answer":"a"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","option":[{"value":"uses the capabilities of other companies without being physically tied to those companies.","index":"A"},{"value":"uses Internet technology to maintain a virtual storefront.","index":"B"},{"value":"uses Internet technology to maintain a networked community of users.","index":"C"},{"value":"provides entirely Internet-driven services, or virtual products.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"67","ref":"107","question":"A virtual company","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.2","option":[{"value":"low-cost leadership","index":"A"},{"value":"product differentiation","index":"B"},{"value":"focus on market niche","index":"C"},{"value":"customer intimacy","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"68","ref":"99, 100","question":"AutoNation's analytic software that mines customer data with a goal of enabling the building of automobiles that customers actually want can be categorized as using information systems for which competitive strategy?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":3,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"3.5","option":[{"value":"E-commerce is affected by the law of diminishing returns.","index":"A"},{"value":"Internet technologies are universal, and therefore usable by all companies.","index":"B"},{"value":"Internet shopping produces cost transparency.","index":"C"},{"value":"The Internet enables the production or sales of substitute products or services.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"69","ref":"109","question":"The emergence, for Amazon.com, of new competitors in the sphere of online shopping illustrates what disadvantage posed by the use of information systems to achieve competitive advantage?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Synthesis Objective: 3.5","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"70","option":[{"value":"Identify the business ecosystem the distributor is in.","index":"A"},{"value":"Implement a strategic transition to the new system.","index":"B"},{"value":"Perform a strategic systems analysis.","index":"C"},{"value":"Benchmark existing systems.","index":"D"}],"chapter":3,"ref":"110","question":"You are consulting for a beverage distributor who is interested in determining the benefits it could achieve from implementing new information systems. What will you advise as the first step?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"1","number":"71","ref":"97","question":"________ is a competitive strategy for creating brand loyalty by developing new and unique products and services that are not easily duplicated by competitors.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Product differentiation"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"1","number":"72","ref":"98","question":"________ is the ability to offer individually tailored products and services using the same production resources as mass production.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Mass customization"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"2","number":"73","ref":"99","question":"________ are the expenses incurred by a customer or company in lost time and resources when changing from one supplier or system to a competing supplier or system.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Switching costs"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"102","question":"The ________ highlights the primary or support activities that add a margin of value to a firm's products or services where information systems can best be applied to achieve a competitive advantage.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"value chain model"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","diff":"1","number":"75","ref":"102","question":"A(n) ________ activity is one that is directly related to the production and distribution of a firm's products or services.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"primary"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","diff":"2","number":"76","ref":"102","question":"A(n) ________ activity is a part of the organization's infrastructure, human resources, technology, and procurement that makes the delivery of the firm's products or services possible.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Support activities"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.4","diff":"3","number":"77","ref":"111","question":"Sociotechnical changes affecting a firm adopting new information systems requiring organizational change can be considered ________.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"strategic transitions"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","diff":"3","number":"78","ref":"104","question":"The ________ is a collection of independent firms that use information technology to coordinate their value chains to collectively produce a product or service for a market.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"value web"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"79","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"105","question":"A(n) ________ is an activity at which a firm excels as a world-class leader.","case":"Content Objective: 3.3","answer":"core competency"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"3.3","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"107","question":"A(n) ________ company uses networks to link people, assets, and ideas, enabling it to work with other companies to create products and services without being limited by traditional organizational boundaries or physical locations.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"virtual"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"81","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"79-81","question":"Differentiate between the technical and behavioral definitions of an organization.","case":"Analysis Objective: 3.1","answer":"The behavioral definition of an organization is that it is a collection of rights, privileges, obligations, and responsibilities that is delicately balanced over a period of time through conflict and conflict resolution. The technical definition sees an organization as an entity that takes inputs from the environment and processes these to create products that are then consumed by the environment. The technical view sees capital and labor as interchangeable units, with the ability to rearrange these units at will, whereas the behavioral view sees that rearranging some aspects of the organization, such as an information system, will have important consequences and changes for the organization's other units."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"82","diff":"3","chapter":3,"ref":"89-92","question":"List three organizational factors that can prevent a firm in fully realizing the benefits of a new information system, and provide examples for each.","case":"Synthesis Objective: 3.1","answer":"Features of organizations include the organization's culture, politics, and structure. A new information system might be resisted by end users or by managers for political reasons because they are concerned about the political changes the system implies. For example, a new system might lessen the authority of a manager in overseeing the employees, and he or she may not want to relinquish this power. A new information system might challenge the organization's culture and be resisted for this reason. For example, an information system might allow students at a university to take self-managed courses, while the university's basic cultural assumptions include the concept that professors are the purveyors of knowledge. An information system, by allowing the distribution of knowledge, may be better used in a company with a flatter organization. A company with a highly stratified hierarchy may have difficulty adjusting its business processes and structures to an information system that does not follow the same business hierarchy of information."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"83","diff":"3","chapter":3,"ref":"92-99","question":"You are advising the owner of Smalltown Computer, a new, local computer repair store that also builds custom computers to order. What competitive strategies could Smalltown Computer exert? Which ones will it have difficulty exercising?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 3.2","answer":"Low-cost leadership: Smalltown Computer may have difficulty competing against the warranty services or computer sales of major national computer manufacturers, such as Dell, but may be able to exercise low-cost leadership in comparison to any other local computer repair stores.\nProduct differentiation: Although many national computer manufacturers sell customized computers to the individual, Smalltown computer may be able to differentiate their product by using superior components and adding more services to their product.\nFocus on market niche: Smalltown computer could determine a market niche geared to their advantage in being a local store with in-store technology support and assistance.\nCustomer and supplier intimacy: Smalltown computer has an advantage in customer intimacy, in that it can develop relationships with local customers on a face-to-face basis. This advantage could be augmented to offset the low-cost leadership of national manufacturer's such as Dell. Because of much smaller production scales, Smalltown will probably not be able to exercise as much control over suppliers as Dell or other manufacturers."},{"type":2,"question":"You are consulting with the owner of Better Bodies, a national chain of gyms. What strategies might Better Bodies use in applying information services to achieve a competitive advantage?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","chapter":3,"ref":"92-99","number":"84","case":"Synthesis Objective: 3.2","answer":"Better Bodies could use computers to monitor and evaluate health and fitness of members and customize workouts in product differentiation strategy. They could use information systems for sales and marketing data research in order to define a niche market that would bring greater profits. They could allow customers to review their health data and add additional information or view statistics to create customer intimacy. If the individual gyms are franchises, then a network could be used for franchisees to share data and research new sales tactics, etc. Diff: 2"},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"3.2","diff":"2","number":"85","ref":"96-102","question":"The text describes Michael Porter's view of the Internet as somewhat negative. What negative influences does Porter see? Describe several positive influences the Internet has on business. Do these outweigh the negative influences?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Answers will vary. An example of a possible answer is:\nPorter sees the Internet as creating ever more intense rivalry, through allowing new competitors to enter the market, and forcing competition on price alone, raising the bargaining power of customers, and dampening profits.\nPositive influences of the Internet would be lowering telecommunications costs, creating new opportunities for building brands and loyal customer bases, lowering costs of globalization. You could also view Porter's negative take on lowering the barrier to entry as a positive for new companies.\nThe Internet's influence being negative or positive depends in part on the point of view from which the influence is being seen. For example, a telephone utility is impacted negatively by the emergence of Internet telephony, whereas other industries may be impacted positively either through the use of this technology or through engaging in Internet telephony as a business."},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.3","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"102-103","question":"Value chain analysis is useful at the business level to highlight specific activities in the business where information systems are most likely to have a strategic impact. Discuss this model, identify the activities, and describe how the model can be applied to the concept of information technology.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The value chain model identifies specific, critical leverage points where a firm can use information technology most effectively to enhance its competitive positions. Exactly where can it obtain the greatest benefit from strategic information systems? What specific activities can be used to create new products and services, enhance market penetration, lock in customers and suppliers, and lower operational costs? This model views the firm as a series or chain of basic activities that add a margin of value to a firm's products or services. These activities can be categorized as either primary activities or support activities.\n• Primary activities are most directly related to the production and distribution of the firm's products and services that create value for the customer. Primary activities include: inbound logistics, operations, outbound logistics, sales and marketing, and service.\n• Support activities make the delivery of the primary activities possible and consist of: organization infrastructure (administration and management), human resources (employee recruiting, hiring, and training, technology (improving products and the production process), and procurement (purchasing input)."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"87","diff":"2","chapter":3,"ref":"105-106","question":"How is the concept of core competency relevant to Smalltown computer, a local computer repair store that builds custom computers? Give examples.","case":"Evaluation Objective: 3.4","answer":"A core competency is an activity for which a company is a world leader, and from this perspective, Smalltown Computer does not have a core competency, as there are thousands of similar firms with longer track records. However, it might be good business practice for Smalltown Computer to define its core competencies in ways that differentiate its products from those of competitors and enable it to provide superior service or products. In defining a core competency, the business management can then determine ways to enable employees to understand and reach higher levels of quality production and service. For example, Smalltown Computer might define a core competency as being able to advise customers as to the types of system they really need, and Smalltown Computer could engage in knowledge gathering activities to help employees assess customer need."},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.4","diff":"2","number":"88","ref":"106-107","question":"How is Internet technology useful from a network economics perspective? Give examples.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"In network economics, the cost of adding a participant in the network is negligible, while the gain in value is relatively much larger. The Internet itself is an example of a successful implementation of network economicsthe more people participate, the more valuable and essential a commodity it is. If a company were to provide a service through the Internet such as a project management application, the costs to the company of adding another user are small (as the software infrastructure or application is already built), and the more users are signed up the more profit is made."},{"chapter":3,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"3.3","diff":"2","number":"89","ref":"107-108","question":"Define and describe a business ecosystem. Give an example of a business ecosystem.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"A business ecosystem is a collection of loosely coupled but interdependent industries (suppliers, distributors, technology manufacturers, etc.) that provides related services and products. It is similar to a value web, except that cooperation takes place across many industries rather than many firms.\nBusiness ecosystems can be characterized as having one or a few keystone firms that dominate the ecosystem and create the platforms used by other niche firms. Keystone firms in the Microsoft ecosystem include Microsoft and technology producers such as Intel and IBM. Niche firms include thousands of software application firms, software developers, service firms, networking firms, and consulting firms that both support and rely on the Microsoft products.\nAnother example of an business ecosystem is the mobile Internet platform. In this ecosystem there are four industries: device makers (Apple iPhone, RIM BlackBerry, Motorola, LG, and others), wireless telecommunication firms (AT&T, Verizon, T-Mobile, Sprint, and others), independent software applications providers (generally small firms selling games, applications, and ring tones), and Internet service providers (who participate as providers of Internet service to the mobile platform)."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"90","diff":"3","chapter":3,"ref":"110","question":"Describe in detail the major factors to determine when performing a strategic systems analysis.","case":"Analysis Objective: 3.5","answer":"One major factor is the structure of the industry the firm is in. For example, what competitive forces are at work in the industry, and what is the basis for competition? What is the nature and direction of change in the industry, and how does the industry use IT.\nA second major factor is determining the firm and industry value chains. For example, how is the company creating value for the customer? Are best practices being used and core competencies leveraged? Is the industry supply chain or customer base changing, and what will the effect be? Can the firm benefit from strategic partnerships or value webs? And where in the value chain will information systems provide the greatest value to the firm.\nThe third major factor to consider is has the firm aligned IT with its business strategy and goals. Have these goals been correctly stated or defined? Is IT improving the right business processes and activities in accordance with the firm's goals? Are we using the right metrics to measure progress?"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"1","diff":"1","chapter":4,"ref":"126","question":"Advances in data storage have made routine violation of individual privacy more difficult.","case":"Content Objective: 4.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","diff":"1","number":"2","ref":"130-131","question":"Professionals take on special rights and obligations because of their special claims to knowledge, wisdom, and respect.","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"true"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"1","number":"3","ref":"131","question":"Privacy is the right to be left alone when you want to be, without surveillance or interference from other individuals or organizations.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"4","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"134","question":"Web sites use \"cookies\" in order to obtain the names and addresses of their visitors.","case":"Content Objective: 4.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"5","ref":"134","question":"A cookie is a small file containing information about you and your Web activities that is deposited on your hard disk by a Web site.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"6","ref":"135","question":"Spyware is software that comes hidden in downloaded applications and can track your online movements.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"136","question":"Most Internet businesses do very little to protect the privacy of their customers.","case":"Content Objective: 4.3","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"8","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"137","question":"P3P encrypts or scrambles e-mail or data so that it cannot be read illicitly.","case":"Content Objective: 4.3","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"9","diff":"3","chapter":4,"ref":"138","question":"Protection for trade secrets is enforced at the federal level.","case":"Content Objective: 4.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"10","ref":"138","question":"Copyright is the legal protection afforded intellectual property, such as a song, book, or video game.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"11","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"138","question":"The Copyright Office began registering software programs in the 1990s.","case":"Content Objective: 4.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"12","ref":"138","question":"The drawback to copyright protection is that the underlying ideas behind the work are not protected, only their manifestation in a product.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"13","ref":"138-139","question":"According to the courts, in the creation of software, unique concepts, general functional features, and even colors are protectable by copyright law.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"3","number":"14","ref":"139","question":"The key concepts in patent law's determination of nonobviousness are originality, novelty, and value.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","diff":"2","number":"15","ref":"146","question":"Despite the passage of several laws defining and addressing computer crime, accessing a computer system without authorization is not yet a federal crime.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":4,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","diff":"1","number":"16","ref":"146","question":"Spam is unsolicited e-mail.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"17","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"146","question":"The European Parliament has passed a ban on unsolicited commercial messaging.","case":"Content Objective: 4.4","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"18","diff":"1","chapter":4,"ref":"150","question":"RSI is unavoidable for a computer keyboard worker.","case":"Content Objective: 4.4","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"19","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"150","question":"Technostress is a computer-related malady whose symptoms include fatigue.","case":"Content Objective: 4.4","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"2","chapter":4,"ref":"150","question":"Radiation from computer display screens has been proved to be a factor in CVS.","case":"Content Objective: 4.4","answer":"true"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"pose traditional ethical situations in new manners.","index":"A"},{"value":"raise new ethical questions.","index":"B"},{"value":"raise the same ethical questions created by the industrial revolution.","index":"C"},{"value":"raise ethical questions primarily related to information rights and obligations.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"21","ref":"123","question":"Information systems","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"dampening effect on the discourse of business ethics.","index":"A"},{"value":"ripple effect raising new ethical, social, and political issues.","index":"B"},{"value":"beneficial effect for society as a whole, while raising dilemmas for consumers.","index":"C"},{"value":"waterfall effect in raising ever more complex ethical issues.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"22","ref":"124","question":"The introduction of new information technology has a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"property rights and obligations.","index":"A"},{"value":"system quality.","index":"B"},{"value":"accountability and control.","index":"C"},{"value":"information rights and obligations.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"23","ref":"125","question":"In the information age, the obligations that individuals and organizations have concerning rights to intellectual property fall within the moral dimension of","diff":"1","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"family and home.","index":"A"},{"value":"property rights and obligations.","index":"B"},{"value":"system quality.","index":"C"},{"value":"quality of life.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"24","ref":"125","question":"In the information age, the obligations that individuals and organizations have regarding the preservation of existing values and institutions fall within the moral dimension of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"advances in wireless networking","index":"A"},{"value":"international standards for data protection","index":"B"},{"value":"networking advances and the Internet","index":"C"},{"value":"increased ease in file sharing and copying","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"25","ref":"126","question":"The four key technical trends responsible for current ethical stresses related to information technology are (1) doubling of computer power every 18 months, (2) data analysis advances, (3) declining data storage costs, and (4) ________.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 4.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"26","option":[{"value":"been accompanied by relevant federal statutes protecting personal data.","index":"A"},{"value":"made universal access possible.","index":"B"},{"value":"doubled every 18 months.","index":"C"},{"value":"made routine violations of privacy cheap and effective.","index":"D"}],"chapter":4,"ref":"126","question":"Advances in data storage techniques and rapidly declining storage costs have","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"profiling.","index":"A"},{"value":"phishing.","index":"B"},{"value":"spamming.","index":"C"},{"value":"targeting.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"27","ref":"126","question":"The use of computers to combine data from multiple sources and create electronic dossiers of detailed information on individuals is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"profiling technology used by the EU.","index":"A"},{"value":"federal privacy law protecting networked data","index":"B"},{"value":"new data analysis technology that finds hidden connections between data in disparate sources.","index":"C"},{"value":"sentencing guideline adopted in 1987 mandating stiff sentences on business executives.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"28","ref":"127","question":"NORA is a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.1","option":[{"value":"property rights and obligations","index":"A"},{"value":"system quality","index":"B"},{"value":"accountability and control","index":"C"},{"value":"information rights and obligations","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"29","ref":"127","question":"Which of the five moral dimensions of the information age do the central business activities of ChoicePoint raise?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"responsibility.","index":"A"},{"value":"accountability.","index":"B"},{"value":"liability.","index":"C"},{"value":"due process.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"30","ref":"129","question":"Accepting the potential costs, duties, and obligations for the decisions you make is referred to as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"accountability.","index":"A"},{"value":"responsibility.","index":"B"},{"value":"due process.","index":"C"},{"value":"liability.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"31","ref":"129","question":"The feature of political systems in which a body of laws is in place that permits individuals to recover the damages done to them by other actors, systems, or organizations is referred to as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"due process.","index":"A"},{"value":"accountability.","index":"B"},{"value":"the courts of appeal.","index":"C"},{"value":"the judicial system.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"32","ref":"129","question":"The feature of social institutions that means mechanisms are in place to determine responsibility for an action is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"liability.","index":"A"},{"value":"due process.","index":"B"},{"value":"the courts of appeal.","index":"C"},{"value":"accountability.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"33","ref":"129","question":"The process in law-governed societies in which laws are known and understood and there is an ability to appeal to higher authorities to ensure that the laws are applied correctly is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"assign responsibility","index":"A"},{"value":"identify the stakeholders","index":"B"},{"value":"identify the options you can reasonably take","index":"C"},{"value":"identify and clearly describe the facts","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"34","ref":"129-130","question":"Which of the following is not one of the five steps discussed in the chapter as a process for analyzing an ethical issue?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"Kant's Categorical Imperative","index":"A"},{"value":"The Golden Rule","index":"B"},{"value":"The Risk Aversion Principle","index":"C"},{"value":"The \"No free lunch\" rule","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"35","ref":"130","question":"A colleague of yours frequently takes for his own personal use small amounts of office supplies, noting that the loss to the company is minimal. You counter that if everyone were to take the office supplies, the loss would no longer be minimal. Your rationale expresses which historical ethical principle?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"acceptable, because the grocer suffers the least harm.","index":"A"},{"value":"acceptable, because the higher value is the survival of the family.","index":"B"},{"value":"wrong, because the man would not want the grocery to steal from him.","index":"C"},{"value":"wrong, because if everyone were to do this, the concept of personal property is defeated.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"36","ref":"130","question":"A classic ethical dilemma is the hypothetical case of a man stealing from a grocery store in order to feed his starving family. If you used the Utilitarian Principle to evaluate this situation, you might argue that stealing the food is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"if an action cannot be taken repeatedly, then it is not right to be taken at any time.","index":"A"},{"value":"one should take the action that produces the least harm or incurs the least cost.","index":"B"},{"value":"one can put values in rank order and understand the consequences of various courses of action.","index":"C"},{"value":"if an action is not right for everyone to take, it is not right for anyone to take.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"37","ref":"130","question":"Immanuel Kant's Categorical Imperative states that","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"if an action cannot be taken repeatedly, then it is not right to be taken at any time.","index":"A"},{"value":"one should take the action that produces the least harm or incurs the least cost.","index":"B"},{"value":"one can put values in rank order and understand the consequences of various courses of action.","index":"C"},{"value":"everything is owned by someone else, and that the creator wants compensation for this work.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"38","ref":"130","question":"The ethical \"no free lunch\" rule states that","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","option":[{"value":"are based on political philosophies.","index":"A"},{"value":"cannot be guides to actions.","index":"B"},{"value":"cannot be applied to many e-commerce situations.","index":"C"},{"value":"do not allow for competing values.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"39","ref":"130","question":"The ethical rules discussed in the textbook","diff":"3","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"Privacy Act of 1974","index":"A"},{"value":"Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act of 1999","index":"B"},{"value":"Freedom of Information Act","index":"C"},{"value":"HIPAA of 1996","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"40","ref":"132","question":"Which U.S. act restricts the information the federal government can collect and regulates what they can do with the information?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"accountability of the record holder.","index":"A"},{"value":"responsibility of the record holder.","index":"B"},{"value":"mutuality of interest between the record holder and the individual.","index":"C"},{"value":"privacy of the individual.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"41","ref":"132","question":"FIP principles are based on the notion of the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"customers must be allowed to choose how their information will be used for secondary purposes other than the supporting transaction.","index":"A"},{"value":"data collectors must take responsible steps to assure that consumer information is accurate and secure from unauthorized use.","index":"B"},{"value":"there is a mechanism in place to enforce FIP principles.","index":"C"},{"value":"Web sites must disclose their information practices before collecting data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"42","ref":"133","question":"The Federal Trade Commission FIP principle of Notice/Awareness states that","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"HIPAA","index":"A"},{"value":"Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act","index":"B"},{"value":"Privacy Protection Act","index":"C"},{"value":"Freedom of Information Act","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"43","ref":"133","question":"Which of the following U.S. laws gives patients access to personal medical records and the right to authorize how this information can be used or disclosed?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"less far-reaching","index":"A"},{"value":"less liable to laws","index":"B"},{"value":"much less stringent","index":"C"},{"value":"much more stringent","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"44","ref":"133","question":"European privacy protection is ________ than in the United States.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 4.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"45","option":[{"value":"have informed consent.","index":"A"},{"value":"create a safe harbor.","index":"B"},{"value":"develop equivalent privacy protection policies.","index":"C"},{"value":"make their privacy protection policies publicly available.","index":"D"}],"chapter":4,"ref":"134","question":"U.S. businesses are allowed to use personal data from EU countries if they","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"on the Web site computer.","index":"A"},{"value":"on the visitor's computer.","index":"B"},{"value":"on the ISP's computer.","index":"C"},{"value":"in a Web directory.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"46","ref":"134","question":"When a cookie is created during a Web site visit, it is stored","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"encourages self-regulation to develop a set of privacy guidelines for its members.","index":"A"},{"value":"protects user privacy during interactions with Web sites.","index":"B"},{"value":"has established technical guidelines for ensuring privacy.","index":"C"},{"value":"is a government agency regulating the use of customer information.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"47","ref":"136","question":"The Online Privacy Alliance","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"opt-in","index":"A"},{"value":"opt-out","index":"B"},{"value":"P3P","index":"C"},{"value":"PGP","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"48","ref":"136","question":"A(n) ________ model of informed consent permits the collection of personal information until the consumer specifically requests that the data not be collected.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"Privacy for Personal Protection.","index":"A"},{"value":"Platform for Privacy Preferences.","index":"B"},{"value":"Personal Privacy Policy.","index":"C"},{"value":"Personal Privacy Protection.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"49","ref":"137","question":"P3P stands for","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"controlling pop-up ads based on user profiles and preventing ads from collecting or sending information.","index":"A"},{"value":"allowing users to surf the Web anonymously.","index":"B"},{"value":"scrambling data so that it can't be read.","index":"C"},{"value":"blocking or limiting cookies.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"50","ref":"137","question":"The P3P standard is concerned with","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"the courts become involved.","index":"A"},{"value":"hackers are able to break into the source code.","index":"B"},{"value":"the software is widely distributed.","index":"C"},{"value":"a new version of the software is released.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"51","ref":"138","question":"The limitation of trade secret protection for software is that it is difficult to prevent the ideas in the work from falling into the public domain when","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"intangible property created by individuals or corporations.","index":"A"},{"value":"unique creative work or ideas.","index":"B"},{"value":"tangible or intangible property created from a unique idea.","index":"C"},{"value":"the expression of an intangible idea.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"52","ref":"138","question":"Intellectual property can best be described as","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"patent protection","index":"A"},{"value":"intellectual property law","index":"B"},{"value":"copyright law","index":"C"},{"value":"Fair Use Doctrine","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"53","ref":"138","question":"What legal mechanism protects the owners of intellectual property from having their work copied by others?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 4.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"54","option":[{"value":"the distinction between tangible and intangible ideas.","index":"A"},{"value":"the distinction between an idea and its expression.","index":"B"},{"value":"using the graphical elements of another product.","index":"C"},{"value":"using the creative elements of another product.","index":"D"}],"chapter":4,"ref":"138","question":"\"Look and feel\" copyright infringement lawsuits are concerned with","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"puts the strength of law behind copyright.","index":"A"},{"value":"allows protection from Internet theft of ideas put forth publicly.","index":"B"},{"value":"is easy to define.","index":"C"},{"value":"grants a monopoly on underlying concepts and ideas.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"55","ref":"139","question":"The strength of patent protection is that it","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"that only the underlying ideas are protected.","index":"A"},{"value":"digital media cannot be patented.","index":"B"},{"value":"preventing the ideas from falling into public domain.","index":"C"},{"value":"the years of waiting to receive it.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"56","ref":"139","question":"One of the difficulties of patent protection is","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"Digital Millennium Copyright Act","index":"A"},{"value":"Privacy Act","index":"B"},{"value":"Freedom of Information Act","index":"C"},{"value":"Electronic Communications Privacy Act","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"57","ref":"140","question":"Which of the following adjusts copyright laws to the Internet age by making it illegal to make, distribute, or use devices that circumvent technology-based protections of copyrighted materials?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"part of a machine.","index":"A"},{"value":"similar to books.","index":"B"},{"value":"services.","index":"C"},{"value":"artistic expressions.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"58","ref":"141","question":"In general, it is very difficult to hold software producers liable for their software products when those products are considered to be","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"Regulated common carriers","index":"A"},{"value":"Private individuals","index":"B"},{"value":"Organizations and businesses","index":"C"},{"value":"Elected officials","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"59","ref":"141","question":"________ are not held liable for the messages they transmit.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 4.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"60","option":[{"value":"any programming code is susceptible to error.","index":"A"},{"value":"it is too expensive create perfect software.","index":"B"},{"value":"errors can be introduced in the maintenance stage of development.","index":"C"},{"value":"any software of any complexity will have errors.","index":"D"}],"chapter":4,"ref":"141-142","question":"It is not feasible for companies to produce error-free software because","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"software bugs.","index":"A"},{"value":"software errors.","index":"B"},{"value":"hardware or facilities failures.","index":"C"},{"value":"data quality.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"61","ref":"142","question":"The most common source of business system failure is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","option":[{"value":"software bugs and errors","index":"A"},{"value":"hardware or facility failures caused by natural or other causes.","index":"B"},{"value":"insufficient integration with external systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"poor input data quality.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"62","ref":"142","question":"Which of the following is not one of the three principal sources of poor system performance?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 4.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"63","option":[{"value":"make work environments much more pleasant.","index":"A"},{"value":"create economies of efficiency.","index":"B"},{"value":"centralize power at corporate headquarters.","index":"C"},{"value":"blur the traditional boundaries between work and family time.","index":"D"}],"chapter":4,"ref":"143","question":"The \"do anything anywhere\" computing environment can","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"telephone solicitation is no longer legal.","index":"A"},{"value":"it is good advertising practice and brings in many new customers.","index":"B"},{"value":"it helps pay for the Internet.","index":"C"},{"value":"it is so inexpensive and can reach so many people.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"64","ref":"146","question":"The practice of spamming has been growing because","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"makes spamming illegal.","index":"A"},{"value":"requires spammers to identify themselves.","index":"B"},{"value":"has dramatically cut down spamming.","index":"C"},{"value":"does not override state anti-spamming laws.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"65","ref":"146","question":"The U.S. CAN-SPAM Act of 2003","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"quality of life","index":"A"},{"value":"system quality","index":"B"},{"value":"accountability and control","index":"C"},{"value":"information rights and obligations","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"66","ref":"146","question":"Which of the five moral dimensions of the information age does spamming raise?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"increases in efficiency may be accompanied by job losses.","index":"A"},{"value":"increases in efficiency may be accompanied by poor data quality.","index":"B"},{"value":"support for middle-management decision making may be offset by poor data quality.","index":"C"},{"value":"reliance on technology results in the loss of hands-on knowledge.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"67","ref":"146-147","question":"Re-designing and automating business processes can be seen as a double-edged sword because","diff":"2","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"computer","index":"A"},{"value":"technology","index":"B"},{"value":"digital","index":"C"},{"value":"electronic","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"68","ref":"147","question":"The term \"________ divide\" refers to large disparities in access to computers and the Internet among different social groups and different locations.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"eyestrain related to computer display screen use.","index":"A"},{"value":"carpal vision syndrome.","index":"B"},{"value":"wrist injuries brought about by incorrect hand position when using a keyboard.","index":"C"},{"value":"stress induced by technology.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"69","ref":"150","question":"CVS refers to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","option":[{"value":"CTS","index":"A"},{"value":"CVS","index":"B"},{"value":"RSI","index":"C"},{"value":"technostress","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"70","ref":"150","question":"________ can be induced by tens of thousands of repetitions under low-impact loads.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","diff":"1","number":"71","ref":"123","question":"The principles of right and wrong that can be used by individuals acting as free moral agents to make choices to guide their behavior are called ________.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"ethics"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.1","diff":"2","number":"72","ref":"124","question":"The liberties that individuals and organizations have with respect to data pertaining to themselves describe the moral dimension of ________.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"information rights"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","diff":"2","number":"73","ref":"129","question":"Accepting the potential costs, duties, and obligations for the decisions one makes is called ________.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"responsibility"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"129","question":"________ refers to the existence of laws that permit individuals to recover damages done to them by other actors, systems, or organizations.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Liability"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.2","diff":"3","number":"75","ref":"130","question":"The ethical principle called ________ states that one should take the action that produces the least harm or incurs the least cost.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"the Risk Aversion Principle"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"76","ref":"133","question":"________ is permission given with knowledge of all the facts needed to make a rational decision.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Informed consent"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"135","question":"A(n) ________ is a tiny graphic file embedded in e-mail messages and Web pages that is designed to monitor online Internet user behavior.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Web bug"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"78","ref":"136","question":"The ________ model prohibits an organization from collecting any personal information unless the individual specifically takes action to approve information collection and use.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"opt-in"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"79","ref":"139","question":"A(n) ________ grants the owner an exclusive monopoly on the ideas behind an invention for 20 years.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"patent"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"4.4","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"146","question":"The commission of acts involving the computer that may not be illegal but are considered unethical is called ________.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"computer abuse"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"4.1","diff":"2","number":"81","ref":"124-125","question":"List and describe the five moral dimensions that are involved in political, social, and ethical issues. Which do you think will be the most difficult for society to deal with? Support your opinion.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The five moral dimensions are:\n1. Information rights and obligations. What rights do individuals and organizations have with respect to information pertaining to them?\n2. Property rights. How can intellectual property rights be protected when it is so easy to copy digital materials?\n3. Accountability and control. Who will be held accountable and liable for the harm done to individual and collective information and property rights?\n4. System quality. What standards of data and system quality should we demand to protect individual rights and the safety of society?\n5. Quality of life. What values should be preserved? What institutions must we protect? What cultural values can be harmed?\nIndividual answers for determining the most difficult for society to deal with will vary. One answer might be: Quality of life issues will be most difficult for society to deal with in societies that are comprised of many different cultural and ethnic groups, such as the United States. It is difficult to regulate concerns that are based on subjective values."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"4.1","diff":"2","number":"82","ref":"125-128","question":"Discuss at least three key technology trends that raise ethical issues. Give an example of an ethical or moral impact connected to each one.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Key technology trends include the following: (1) Computer power doubling every 18 months: ethical impact - because more organizations depend on computer systems for critical operations, these systems are vulnerable to computer crime and computer abuse; (2) Data storage costs are rapidly declining: ethical impact - it is easy to maintain detailed databases on individuals -- who has access to and control of these databases?; (3) Data analysis advances: ethical impact - vast databases full of individual information may be used to develop detailed profiles of individual behavior; and (5) Networking advances and the Internet: ethical impact - it is easy to copy data from one location to another. Who owns data? How can ownership be protected?"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.2","diff":"1","number":"83","ref":"129-130","question":"What are the steps in conducting an ethical analysis?","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"The steps are: (1) Identify and describe clearly the facts; (2) define the conflict or dilemma and identify the higher-order values involved; (3) identify the stakeholders; (4) identify the options that you can reasonably take; and (5) identify the potential consequences of your options."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.2","diff":"2","number":"84","ref":"130","question":"List and define the six ethical principles discussed in your text.","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"The six ethical principles are the Golden Rule, Kant's Categorical Imperative, Descartes' rule of change (slippery slope), the Utilitarian Principle, the Risk Aversion Principle, and the \"no free lunch\" rule. The Golden Rule proposes: do unto others as you would have them do unto you. Immanuel Kant's Categorical Imperative proposes, if an action is not right for everyone to take, it is not right for anyone. Descartes' rule of change says: If an action cannot be taken repeatedly, it is not right to take at all. The Utilitarian Principle is: Take the action that achieves the higher or greater value. The Risk Aversion Principle is: Take the action that produces the least harm or the least potential cost. The ethical no free lunch rule says: Assume that virtually all tangible and intangible objects are owned by someone else unless there is a specific declaration otherwise.tangible objects are owned by someone else unless there is a specific declaration otherwise."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"4.2","diff":"2","number":"85","ref":"130-131","question":"Do you believe that professional groups should be allowed to assign their own professional codes of conduct and police themselves from within? Why or why not?","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"This is an opinion question, but anyone who aspires to management will consider himself or herself a professional and will need to have a clear understanding as to how he or she feels about this matter. With the recent scandals in large business firms, which have devastated our economy, there is likely to be a cry for legally sanctioned codes and outside regulatory agencies."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"4.3","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"125-128, 131-136","question":"What are the major issues concerning privacy in the information age? Do you believe the need for homeland security should overrule some of the personal privacy and information rights we have previously taken for granted? Why or why not?","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"One answer might be that we should depend upon the Federal Trade Commission Fair Information Practice Principles and that as long as these principles are not ignored or overset, personal privacy does not conflict with homeland security. This is a weak argument. Other issues involve online privacy, employee monitoring, tradeoffs between security and privacy and good business results versus privacy."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"objective":"4.3","aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"87","ref":"134-135","question":"How does a cookie work?","case":"Analysis","answer":"A cookie works as follows: A user opens a Web browser and selects a site to visit. The user's computer sends a request for information to the computer running at the Web site. The Web site computer is called the server, since it allows the user's computer to display the Web site. At the same time it sends a cookie — a data file containing information like an encrypted user ID and information about when the user visited and what he did on the site. The user's computer receives the cookie and places it in a file on the hard drive. Whenever the user goes back to the Web site, the server running the site retrieves the cookie to help identify the user. Diff: 2"},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"4.2","diff":"3","number":"88","ref":"129","question":"Define the basic concepts of responsibility, accountability, and liability as applied to ethical decisions. How are these concepts related?","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"Responsibility is the first key element of ethical action. Responsibility means that an individual, group, or organization accepts the potential costs, duties, and obligations for decisions made. Accountability is a feature of systems and social institutions. It means that mechanisms are in place to determine who took responsible action; i.e., who is responsible for the action. Liability is a feature of political systems in which a body of law is in place that permits individuals to recover the damages done to them by others.\nThese concepts are related as follows: I will assume the blame or benefit for the actions I take (responsibility); this blame or benefit accrues to me through the requirement that I be able to explain why I have taken the actions I have (accountability) for actions traceable to me by defined mechanisms in the organization, and if those actions result in hard to another, I will be held by law to reparations for those actions (liability)."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"4.4","diff":"2","number":"89","ref":"141-142","question":"What do you consider to be the primary ethical, social, and political issues regarding information system quality?","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"The central quality-related ethical issue that information systems raise is at what point should I release software or services for consumption by others? At what point can I conclude that my software or service achieves an economically and technologically adequate level of quality? What am I obligated to know about the quality of my software, its procedures for testing, and its operational characteristics? The leading quality-related social issue deals with expectations: As a society, do we want to encourage people to believe that systems are infallible, that data errors are impossible? By heightening awareness of system failure, do we inhibit the development of all systems, which in the end contribute to social well-being? The leading quality-related political issue concerns the laws of responsibility and accountability, what they should be, and how they should be applied."},{"chapter":4,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"4.1","diff":"3","number":"90","ref":"122, 124-125","question":"How does the use of electronic voting machines act as a \"double-edged sword?\" What moral dimensions are raised by this use of information technology?","aacsb":"Ethical understanding and reasoning abilities","answer":"Electronic voting machines can be seen as beneficial by making voting easy to accomplish and tabulate. However, it may be easier to tamper with electronic voting machines than with countable paper ballots. In terms of information rights, it seems possible that methods could be set up to determine how an individual has voted and to store and disseminate this knowledge. Manufacturers of voting machines claim property rights to the voting software, which means that if the software is protected from inspection, there is no regulation in how the software operates or how accurate it is. In terms of accountability and control, if an electronic voting system malfunctions, will it be the responsibility of the government, of the company manufacturing the machines or software, or the programmers who programmed the software? The dimension of system quality raises questions of how the level of accuracy of the machines is to be judged and what level is acceptable? In terms of quality of life, while it may make voting easier and quicker, does the vulnerability to abuse of these systems pose a threat to the democratic principle of one person, one vote?"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"1","number":"1","ref":"163","question":"IT infrastructure technology is purely a set of physical devices and software applications that are required to operate the entire enterprise.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"2","diff":"2","chapter":5,"ref":"166","question":"Client/server computing is a widely used form of centralized processing.","case":"Content Objective: 5.1","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"3","diff":"3","chapter":5,"ref":"166-167","question":"In two-tiered client/server architecture, the processing is split between two types of servers.","case":"Content Objective: 5.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"3","number":"4","ref":"167","question":"N-tier computing is a multi-tier, load-balancing scheme for Web-based applications in which significant parts of Web site content, logic, and processing are performed by smaller, less expensive servers located nearby the user.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"5","diff":"2","chapter":5,"ref":"167","question":"Application server software is responsible for locating and managing stored Web pages.","case":"Content Objective: 5.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"2","number":"6","ref":"167","question":"An application server may reside on the same computer as a Web server or on its own dedicated computer.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","diff":"2","number":"7","ref":"167-168","question":"Enterprise integration requires software that can link disparate applications and enable data to flow freely among different parts of the business.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"8","diff":"2","chapter":5,"ref":"176","question":"The mainframe market has grown steadily over the past decade.","case":"Content Objective: 5.2","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"9","diff":"1","chapter":5,"ref":"176-177","question":"The operating system is used to manage the computer's activities.","case":"Content Objective: 5.1","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"2","number":"10","ref":"187","question":"SANs create large central pools of storage that can be rapidly accessed and shared by multiple servers.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"2","number":"11","ref":"178","question":"Like an ASP, a Web hosting service provides shared applications to subscribed users, but does this through a Web portal.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"12","diff":"2","chapter":5,"ref":"181","question":"Autonomic computing is implemented primarily with enterprise or ISP servers.","case":"Content Objective: 5.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"1","number":"13","ref":"185-186","question":"Java software is designed to run on any computer or computing device, regardless of the specific microprocessor or operating system it uses.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"2","number":"14","ref":"186","question":"Web services can exchange information between two different systems regardless of the operating system or programming languages on which the systems are based.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"1","number":"15","ref":"187","question":"Whereas XML is limited to describing how data should be presented in the form of Web pages, HTML can perform presentation, communication, and data storage tasks.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"1","number":"16","ref":"187","question":"Hypertext markup language specifies how text, graphics, video, and sound are placed on a Web page document.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"2","number":"17","ref":"187","question":"The collection of Web services that are used to build a firm's software systems constitutes what is known as a service-oriented architecture.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"2","number":"18","ref":"189","question":"Today most business firms have discontinued operating their legacy systems, replacing these with inexpensive Web services and hosted software.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":5,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","diff":"1","number":"19","ref":"194","question":"Scalability refers to the ability of a computer, product, or system to expand to serve a large number of users without breaking down.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"1","chapter":5,"ref":"196","question":"TCO refers to the original cost of purchased technology: both hardware and software.","case":"Content Objective: 5.5","answer":"false"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"networking","index":"A"},{"value":"telephone","index":"B"},{"value":"VOIP","index":"C"},{"value":"telecommunications","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"21","ref":"164","question":"Which type of infrastructure services provides voice and video connectivity to employees, customers, and suppliers?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"operating system software","index":"A"},{"value":"computing platforms to provide a coherent digital environment","index":"B"},{"value":"physical facility management to manage the facilities housing physical components","index":"C"},{"value":"IT management services to plan and develop the infrastructure and provide project management","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"22","ref":"163-164","question":"Which of the following is NOT an IT infrastructure service component?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"4, 5, 3, 2, 1","index":"A"},{"value":"5, 4, 2, 3, 1","index":"B"},{"value":"4, 5, 2, 3, 1","index":"C"},{"value":"5, 4, 2, 1, 3","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"23","ref":"164-168","question":"Place the following eras of IT infrastructure evolution in order, from earliest to most recent: (1) Cloud Computing Era (2) Client/Server, (3) Enterprise Era, (4) Personal Computer, and (5) Mainframe and Minicomputer.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"allowed computers to be customized to the specific needs of departments or business units.","index":"A"},{"value":"enabled decentralized computing.","index":"B"},{"value":"offered new, powerful machines at lower prices than mainframes.","index":"C"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"24","ref":"166","question":"The introduction of the minicomputer:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"the work of the entire network is centralized.","index":"A"},{"value":"the work of the entire network is balanced over several levels of servers.","index":"B"},{"value":"processing is split between clients and servers.","index":"C"},{"value":"processing is handled by multiple, geographically remote clients.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"25","ref":"167","question":"In a multi-tiered network:","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"service-oriented architecture.","index":"A"},{"value":"on-demand architecture.","index":"B"},{"value":"multi-tiered client/server architecture.","index":"C"},{"value":"two-tiered client/server architecture.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"26","ref":"166-167","question":"A client computer networked to a server computer, with processing split between the two types of machines, is called a(n):","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"computing power doubles every 18 months.","index":"A"},{"value":"transistors decrease in size 50% every two years.","index":"B"},{"value":"data storage costs decrease by 50% every 18 months.","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"27","ref":"168-170","question":"Interpretations of Moore's law assert that:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"the width of a fingernail.","index":"A"},{"value":"a human hair.","index":"B"},{"value":"a virus.","index":"C"},{"value":"an atom.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"28","ref":"171","question":"Today's nanotechnology-produced computer transistors are roughly equivalent in size to:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"network economics","index":"A"},{"value":"law of mass digital storage and Moore's law","index":"B"},{"value":"declining communications costs, universal standards, and the Internet","index":"C"},{"value":"all of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"29","ref":"168-174","question":"Which of the following factors provides an understanding of why computing resources today are ever more available than in previous decades?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"network standards.","index":"A"},{"value":"telecommunications standards.","index":"B"},{"value":"technology standards.","index":"C"},{"value":"Internet standards.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"30","ref":"174","question":"Specifications that establish the compatibility of products and the ability to communicate in a network are called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"Internet and web technologies","index":"A"},{"value":"Technology standards","index":"B"},{"value":"Linux and open-source software","index":"C"},{"value":"Client/server technologies","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"31","ref":"174","question":"________ unleash powerful economies of scale and result in declines in manufactured computer products.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"Unix.","index":"A"},{"value":"Linux.","index":"B"},{"value":"OS X.","index":"C"},{"value":"COBOL.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"32","ref":"174","question":"The multitasking, multi-user, operating system developed by Bell Laboratories that operates on a wide variety of computing platforms is","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","option":[{"value":"TCP/IP","index":"A"},{"value":"COBOL","index":"B"},{"value":"Ethernet","index":"C"},{"value":"ASCII","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"33","ref":"174","question":"The network standard for connecting desktop computers into local area networks that enabled the widespread adoption of client/server computing and local area networks and further stimulated the adoption of personal computers is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"operating system software.","index":"A"},{"value":"application software.","index":"B"},{"value":"data management software.","index":"C"},{"value":"network software.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"34","ref":"176-177","question":"Software that manages the resources of the computer is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"server area","index":"A"},{"value":"storage area","index":"B"},{"value":"scalable architecture","index":"C"},{"value":"service-oriented architecture","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"35","ref":"177","question":"A SAN is a ________ network.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"Dell, HP/Compaq, and IBM.","index":"A"},{"value":"Cisco, Lucent, and Nortel.","index":"B"},{"value":"Seagate, Maxtor, and Western Digital.","index":"C"},{"value":"IBM, Oracle, and Sun.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"36","ref":"177","question":"The leading networking hardware providers include","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"traditional mainframe-based business information systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"electronic spreadsheets used on a PC.","index":"B"},{"value":"any pre-1990 Wintel systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"systems found on older ASPs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"37","ref":"179","question":"As referred to in the text, legacy systems are","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","option":[{"value":"can only be run on the older mainframe computers.","index":"A"},{"value":"are too expensive to redesign.","index":"B"},{"value":"integrate well using new Web services technologies.","index":"C"},{"value":"contain valuable data that would be lost during redesign.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"38","ref":"179","question":"Legacy systems are still used because they","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"co-location.","index":"A"},{"value":"edge computing.","index":"B"},{"value":"grid computing.","index":"C"},{"value":"utility computing.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"39","ref":"179","question":"Connecting geographically remote computers in a single network to create a \"virtual supercomputer\" is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"netbooks","index":"A"},{"value":"digital e-book readers","index":"B"},{"value":"cell phones","index":"C"},{"value":"laptops","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"40","ref":"179","question":"Which of the following is NOT an example of the new mobile digital computing platforms?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"cost savings.","index":"A"},{"value":"increased accuracy.","index":"B"},{"value":"speed of computation.","index":"C"},{"value":"agility.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"41","ref":"179-180","question":"The business case for using grid computing involves all of the following EXCEPT","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"on-demand","index":"A"},{"value":"grid","index":"B"},{"value":"edge","index":"C"},{"value":"autonomic","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"42","ref":"181","question":"Which type of computing refers to firms purchasing computing power from remote providers and paying only for the computing power they use?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"massive unused data centers","index":"A"},{"value":"underutilized mainframe computers","index":"B"},{"value":"networked computers with idle resources","index":"C"},{"value":"networks with low usage","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"43","ref":"181","question":"Which of the following does grid computing utilize to create enormous supercomputing power?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"spyware protection software that runs and updates itself automatically.","index":"A"},{"value":"software programmed to run on any hardware platform.","index":"B"},{"value":"cell phones taking on the functions of handheld computers.","index":"C"},{"value":"programming languages that allow non-programmers to create custom applications.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"44","ref":"181","question":"An example of autonomic computing is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"grid computing.","index":"A"},{"value":"utility computing.","index":"B"},{"value":"virtualization","index":"C"},{"value":"autonomic computing.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"45","ref":"181","question":"An industry-wide effort to develop systems that can configure, optimize, tune, and heal themselves when broken, and protect themselves from outside intruders and self-destruction is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","option":[{"value":"cloud computing.","index":"A"},{"value":"autonomic computing.","index":"B"},{"value":"virtualization.","index":"C"},{"value":"multicore processing.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"46","ref":"184","question":"The process of presenting a set of computing resources (such as computing power or data storage) so that they can all be accessed in ways that are not restricted by physical configuration or geographic location is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"software packages","index":"A"},{"value":"mashups","index":"B"},{"value":"outsourced","index":"C"},{"value":"open source","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"47","ref":"184","question":"Which type of software is created and updated by a worldwide community of programmers and available for free?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"primarily concerned with the tasks of end users.","index":"A"},{"value":"designed for specific machines and specific microprocessors.","index":"B"},{"value":"an example of open-source software.","index":"C"},{"value":"especially useful for processing numeric data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"48","ref":"185","question":"Linux is:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"It plays a major role in the back office running local area networks.","index":"A"},{"value":"It is available in free versions downloadable from the Internet.","index":"B"},{"value":"It has garnered 80 percent of the server operating system market.","index":"C"},{"value":"Linux applications are embedded in cell phones, smartphones, netbooks, and other handheld devices.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"49","ref":"185","question":"Which of the following statements about Linux is NOT true?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"UDDI","index":"A"},{"value":"widgets","index":"B"},{"value":"Ajax","index":"C"},{"value":"Java","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"50","ref":"186","question":"Which of the following is a technique used to allow users to interact with a Web page without having to wait for the Web server to reload the Web page?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"JVM.","index":"A"},{"value":"Web browser.","index":"B"},{"value":"FTP client.","index":"C"},{"value":"All of the above.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"51","ref":"186","question":"A software tool with a graphical user interface for displaying Web pages and for accessing the Web and other Internet resources is called a:","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"Web services.","index":"A"},{"value":"EAI software.","index":"B"},{"value":"SOA.","index":"C"},{"value":"SOAP.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"52","ref":"186","question":"Sets of loosely coupled software components that exchange information with each other using standard Web communication standards and languages are referred to as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"a Java Virtual Machine to be installed on the computer.","index":"A"},{"value":"a Java Virtual Machine to be installed on the server hosting the Java applet.","index":"B"},{"value":"a miniature program to be downloaded to the user's computer.","index":"C"},{"value":"no specialized software, as Java is platform-independent.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"53","ref":"186","question":"Running a Java program on a computer requires","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"XML","index":"A"},{"value":"HTML","index":"B"},{"value":"SOAP","index":"C"},{"value":"UDDI","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"54","ref":"187","question":"What is the foundation technology for Web services?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"Web services.","index":"A"},{"value":"EAI software.","index":"B"},{"value":"SOA.","index":"C"},{"value":"SOAP.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"55","ref":"187","question":"A set of self-contained services that communicate with each other to create a working software application is called:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"Amazon.com's operation of hundreds of services, such as billing or customer interface, delivered by different application servers","index":"A"},{"value":"E*Trade's use of lower-cost Linux servers that delivered increased computer performance","index":"B"},{"value":"Thermos's use of hosted Oracle systems software running on Oracle's computers","index":"C"},{"value":"None of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"56","ref":"187-188","question":"Which of the following is an example of an SOA environment?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"Web services.","index":"A"},{"value":"applets.","index":"B"},{"value":"widgets.","index":"C"},{"value":"mashups.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"57","ref":"189","question":"The small software programs that can be added to Web pages or placed on the desktop to provide additional functionality are referred to as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"integrated software.","index":"A"},{"value":"Ajax.","index":"B"},{"value":"mashups.","index":"C"},{"value":"virtual software.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"58","ref":"189","question":"Software applications that are based on combining different online software applications are called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"purchasing a software package","index":"A"},{"value":"programming the new software in-house","index":"B"},{"value":"leasing the software over the Internet","index":"C"},{"value":"outsourcing the software programming to an overseas vendor","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"59","ref":"189-191","question":"Your firm needs to implement electronic timesheet software and needs to keep within a small budget. Which of the following would be the most costly method of implementing this new software?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"software packages.","index":"A"},{"value":"mashups.","index":"B"},{"value":"outsourced software.","index":"C"},{"value":"open source software.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"60","ref":"190","question":"Prewritten, commercially available sets of software programs that eliminate the need for a firm to write its own software programs for certain functions, are referred to as","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"SOA","index":"A"},{"value":"SLA","index":"B"},{"value":"TCO","index":"C"},{"value":"RFQ","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"61","ref":"191","question":"A formal contract between customers and their service providers that outlines the specific responsibilities of the service provider and to the customer is called a(n)","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"supplying online access over networks to storage devices and storage area network technology.","index":"A"},{"value":"managing combinations of applications, networks, systems, storage, and security as well as providing Web site and systems performance monitoring to subscribers over the Internet.","index":"B"},{"value":"hosting and managing access to software applications delivered over the Internet to clients on a subscription basis.","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"62","ref":"191","question":"SaaS refers to","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","option":[{"value":"outsourcing.","index":"A"},{"value":"scaling.","index":"B"},{"value":"service-oriented architecture.","index":"C"},{"value":"application integration.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"63","ref":"191","question":"The practice of contracting custom software development to an outside firm is commonly referred to as","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Content Objective: 5.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"64","option":[{"value":"increased competition from traditional industry leaders such as Microsoft and SAP","index":"A"},{"value":"continuing to differentiate its product and develop complementary new products and services","index":"B"},{"value":"maintaining 24/7 availability for clients","index":"C"},{"value":"moving into a more scalable, on-demand environment","index":"D"}],"chapter":5,"ref":"192","question":"Which of the following is not a challenge being faced by Salesforce.com, as discussed in the chapter case?","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"modality","index":"A"},{"value":"scalability","index":"B"},{"value":"expandability","index":"C"},{"value":"disintermediation","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"65","ref":"194","question":"Which of the following refers to the ability of a computer, product, or system to expand to serve a larger number of users without breaking down?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"Perform a TCO analysis.","index":"A"},{"value":"Benchmark your services.","index":"B"},{"value":"Hold focus groups to assess your services.","index":"C"},{"value":"Analyze sales returns on key investments.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"66","ref":"194","question":"How would you determine the market demand for your firm's IT services?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"your firm's business strategy","index":"A"},{"value":"the IT investments made by competitor firms","index":"B"},{"value":"market demand for your firm's services","index":"C"},{"value":"your firm's organizational culture","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"67","ref":"195","question":"Which of the following is not one of the main six factors to consider when evaluating how much your firm should spend on IT infrastructure?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"Use Web services to join the two systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"Move one firm into using the other's system in order to centralize management and support services.","index":"B"},{"value":"Develop single ERP system that encompasses the information needs and business processes of both firms.","index":"C"},{"value":"Purchase a hosted, on-demand ERP system that encompasses the needs and processes of both firms.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"68","ref":"196-197","question":"Your firm, an auto parts manufacturer, has just merged with an automobile engine manufacturer, and the two companies have different SCM systems. Which of the following strategies would be the most likely course to help to reduce the TCO of the merged firms' technology investments?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"total cost of ownership","index":"A"},{"value":"return on investment","index":"B"},{"value":"breakeven point","index":"C"},{"value":"cost benefit analysis","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"69","ref":"196","question":"Which model can be used to analyze the direct and indirect costs to help firms determine the actual cost of specific technology implementations?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"5.5","option":[{"value":"20","index":"A"},{"value":"40","index":"B"},{"value":"60","index":"C"},{"value":"80","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"70","ref":"196","question":"Hardware and software acquisition costs account for about ________ percent of TCO.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","diff":"2","number":"71","ref":"166","question":"The ________ PC is a computer using the Windows operating system software on a computer with an Intel microprocessor became the standard PC in the Personal Computer Era.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Wintel"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","diff":"1","number":"72","ref":"171","question":"________ uses individual atoms and molecules to create computer chips and other devices thinner than a human hair.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Nanotechnology"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.2","diff":"3","number":"73","ref":"172","question":"________ states that the value or power of a network grows exponentially as a function of the number of network members.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Metcalfe's Law"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"176","question":"________ are ultrathin computers consisting of a circuit board with processors, memory, and network connections that are stored in racks.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Blade servers"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.1","diff":"2","number":"75","ref":"179","question":"________ systems are generally older transaction processing systems created for mainframe computers that continue to be used to avoid the high cost of replacing or redesigning them.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Legacy"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","diff":"2","number":"76","ref":"181","question":"________ computing is an industry-wide effort to develop systems that can configure, optimize, tune, heal, and protect themselves from outside intruders and self-destruction.\n￼","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Autonomic"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.3","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"184","question":"A(n) ________ is an integrated circuit to which two or more processors have been attached for enhanced performance and reduced power consumption.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"multicore processor"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"78","diff":"2","chapter":5,"ref":"184","question":"________ can boost server utilization rates to 70 percent or higher.","case":"Content Objective: 5.3","answer":"Virtualization"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"2","number":"79","ref":"187","question":"________ provides a standard format for data exchange, enabling Web services to pass data from one process to another.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"XML"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"5.4","diff":"1","number":"80","ref":"191","question":"________ takes place when a firm contracts custom software development or maintenance of existing legacy programs to outside firms.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Outsourcing"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"objective":"5.1","aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"81","ref":"163-164","question":"List and describe the major components of IT infrastructure.","case":"Analysis","answer":"Computer hardware platforms: consists of technology for computer processing and includes client and server machines and mainframes.\nComputer software platforms: includes system software, application software, and enterprise applications.\nData management and storage includes database management software and hardware for storage, such as disk arrays, tape libraries, and SANs.\nNetworking and telecommunications platforms include telecommunication services for voice lines and Internet access, as well as cellular phone services.\nInternet platforms: includes hardware, software, and management services for maintaining Web sites, intranets, and extranets.\nConsulting and system integration services: includes consulting services and staff for maintaining legacy systems and integrating older systems with new infrastructure technologies. Diff: 2"},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"5.4","diff":"2","number":"82","ref":"184-185","question":"Briefly explain why corporations are increasingly interested in using Unix or Linux for their operating system.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Linux is an inexpensive and robust open-source relative of Unix. Unix and Linux constitute the backbone of corporate infrastructure throughout much of the world because they are scalable, reliable, and much less expensive than mainframe operating systems. They can also run on many different types of processors. The major providers of Unix operating systems are IBM, HP, and Sun with slightly different and partially incompatible versions.\nAlthough Windows continues to dominate the client marketplace, many corporations have begun to explore Linux as a low-cost desktop operating system provided by commercial vendors such as RedHat Linux and Linux-based desktop productivity suites such as Sun's StarOffice. Linux is also available in free versions downloadable from the Internet as open-source software. The rise of open-source software, particularly Linux and the applications it supports at the client and server level, has profound implications for corporate software platforms: cost, reduction, reliability and resilience, and integration, because Linux works on all the major hardware platforms from mainframes to servers to clients. Linux has the potential to break Microsoft's monopoly on the desktop. Sun's StarOffice has an inexpensive Linux-based version that competes with Microsoft's Office productivity suite."},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"5.3","diff":"2","number":"83","ref":"179-181","question":"Distinguish between grid computing, cloud computing, and on-demand computing.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Grid computing involves connecting geographically remote computers into a single network to create a computational grid that combines the computing power of all the computers on the network with which to attack large computing problems. In cloud computing, hardware and software capabilities are provided as services over the Internet. With on-demand computing firms to purchase processing power from large computer service firms and either pay subscription fees or pay only for the power they use."},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"5.4","diff":"3","number":"84","ref":"184-191","question":"Identify and describe five or more of the current trends in contemporary software platforms.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"1. Growing use of Linux and open-source software. Open-source software is produced and maintained by a global community of programmers and is downloadable for free. Linux is a powerful, resilient open-source operating system that can run on multiple hardware platforms and is used widely to run Web servers.\n2. Java is an operating-system and hardware-independent programming language that is the leading interactive programming environment for the Web.\n3. Web services and service-oriented architecture. Software for enterprise integration includes enterprise applications and middleware such as enterprise application integration (EAI) software and Web services. Unlike EAI software, Web services are loosely coupled software components based on open Web standards that are not product-specific and can work with any application software and operating system. They can be used as components of Web-based applications linking the systems of two different organizations or to link disparate systems of a single company.\n4. Ajax, a new software techniques for enabling Web applications.\n5. Mashups, or combining Web applications to create new products.\n6. Widgets, small software programs that can be added to Web pages or placed on the desktop\nto provide additional functionality.\n7. Software outsourcingcompanies are purchasing their new software applications from outside sources, including application software packages, by outsourcing custom application development to an external vendor (that may be offshore), or by renting software services from an application service provider."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"85","diff":"3","chapter":5,"ref":"187","question":"Distinguish between Simple Object Access Protocol (SOAP), Web Services Description Language (WSDL), and Universal Description, Discovery, and Integration (UDDI).","case":"Analysis Objective: 5.4","answer":"Simple Object Access Protocol (SOAP) is a set of rules for structuring messages that enables applications to pass data and instructions to one another. Web Services Description Language (WSDL) is a common framework for describing the tasks performed by a Web service and the commands and data it will accept so that it can be used by other applications. Universal Description, Discovery, and Integration (UDDI) enable a Web service to be listed in a directory of Web services so that it can be easily located."},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"5.5","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"194","question":"What is scalability? Why is it essential to the success of the modern business firm?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Scalability is the ability of the computer, product, or system to expand to survey larger numbers of users without breaking down. It is important because as firms grow, they can quickly outgrow their infrastructure. As firms shrink, they can get stuck with excessive infrastructure purchased in better times. Any modern company must be able to make plans for the future, even though that future may be different than what was expected. Computer equipment is expensive, though dropping in price, and budgets must be planned to allow for new purchases, upgrades, and training. It is generally assumed that a successful company will need more computer capacity for more people as it follows a path to continued success."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"87","diff":"3","chapter":5,"ref":"194-197","question":"You are starting a market research company with a single business partner and are planning the hardware and software need for the two of you. Which factors should play into your decision of how much to spend on these investments?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 5.5","answer":"Using the competitive forces model for IT infrastructure investment, the most relevant factors in this decision are:\n• The firm's business strategy. What capabilities we will want to have over the next five years?\n• Alignment of IT strategy. How does our IT strategy match up with the business plan?\n• IT assessment. What are the current technology levels for the services we are offering and our business type? We would probably not need to be at the bleeding edge, but not behind the times either.\n• Competitor firm services. What technology-enabled capabilities do our competitors have? We would want to match services with our competitors.\n• Competitor firm IT investments. How much are competitor firms investing in their technology?\nBecause this is a startup, one other factor may not play such a large role: That of market demand for services. However, finding out what the market demand for competitor's services may uncover ways that this new company could have a competitive advantage."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"88","diff":"3","chapter":5,"ref":"174-175","question":"Explain why standards are so important in information technology? What standards have been important for the growth of Internet technologies?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 5.2","answer":"Standards are important because they result in different manufacturer's creating products that can be used either with each other or to communicate with each other. For example, without standards, each light-bulb manufacturer would have to also create specific light-bulb sockets for use with their light-bulbs. In the same way, computers and computer technology have been enabled through standards. Standards have allowed many different manufacturers to contribute to the same, standardized definitions of a technological application. For example, the ASCII data standards made it possible for computer machines from different manufacturers to exchange data, and standardized software languages have enabled programmers to write programs that can be used on different machines.\nThe standards that have been important for the growth of the Internet include TCP/IP, as a networking standard, and WWW standards for displaying information as Web pages, including HTML."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"89","diff":"3","chapter":5,"ref":"179-184","question":"An ad-hoc group of oceanographers needs to set up a system to analyze massive amounts of data on ocean temperatures. The technology and hardware for gathering the data and transmitting the data to a central computer is in place. What additional hardware might they need? What techniques might they use to make their research more efficient and lower costs?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 5.3","answer":"To store their data they may want to use a SAN. To process their data, they will need a supercomputer or grid computing. To lower costs, they could look at on-demand or utility computing as well as virtualization and implementing multicore processors."},{"chapter":5,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"5.5","diff":"3","number":"90","ref":"193-197","question":"A small design agency you are consulting for will be creating client Web sites and wants to purchase a Web server so they can host the sites themselves. How will you advise them on this purchase?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"They need to understand total cost of ownership: the costs will go beyond the cost of the server, but they will also need to purchase the server software and any application software they will be using. They will also need someone in their IT department to manage and maintain the computers. They will also incur facilities costs for running the computer. They need to have a backup plan should the server fail. The design agency will need to add up all the potential costs and risks. Additionally, they need to prepare for their plan if they need more servers? Will they eventually have to run and maintain their own server farm? What if one of their clients' sites is more popular than anticipated and the server has difficulty handling the load? How quickly can they add servers or processing power? The company should look at collocation, Web hosting services, and ASPs to see if their needs will be better met this way."},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","diff":"1","number":"1","ref":"210","question":"A grouping of characters into a word, a group of words, or a complete number is called a record.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"2","diff":"1","chapter":6,"ref":"210","question":"Each characteristic or quality describing a particular entity is called an attribute.","case":"Content Objective: 6.3","answer":"true"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","diff":"2","number":"3","ref":"211","question":"Program-data dependence refers to the coupling of data stored in files and software programs that use this data such that changes in programs require changes to the data.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"4","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"212","question":"A DBMS separates the logical and physical views of the data.","case":"Content Objective: 6.1","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"5","diff":"1","chapter":6,"ref":"214","question":"Every record in a file should contain at least one key field.","case":"Content Objective: 6.3","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"6","diff":"1","chapter":6,"ref":"215","question":"Many applications today require databases that can store and retrieve multimedia.","case":"Content Objective: 6.2","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"215","question":"One of the drawbacks to OODBMS are that they cannot work with applets.","case":"Content Objective: 6.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","diff":"2","number":"8","ref":"215","question":"OODBMS are slower than relational DBMS.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","diff":"1","number":"9","ref":"217","question":"A data dictionary is a language associated with a database management system that end users and programmers use to manipulate data in the database.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","diff":"1","number":"10","ref":"219","question":"In a relational database, complex groupings of data must be streamlined to eliminate awkward many-to-many relationships.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"11","diff":"1","chapter":6,"ref":"223","question":"A data warehouse may be updated by a legacy system.","case":"Content Objective: 6.4","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"12","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"225","question":"A data warehouse is typically comprised of several smaller data marts.","case":"Content Objective: 6.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","diff":"2","number":"13","ref":"226","question":"OLAP is a key tool of BI.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","diff":"2","number":"14","ref":"226-227","question":"OLAP enables users to obtain online answers to ad-hoc questions in a fairly rapid amount of time, except when the data are stored in very large databases.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"15","diff":"3","chapter":6,"ref":"229","question":"Predictive analysis is synonymous with data mining.","case":"Content Objective: 6.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","diff":"2","number":"16","ref":"230","question":"In a Web-based database, middleware is used to transfer information from the organization's internal database back to the Web server for delivery in the form of a Web page to the user.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"17","diff":"1","chapter":6,"ref":"231","question":"A Web interface requires changes to the internal database.","case":"Content Objective: 6.4","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"18","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"231","question":"Common Gateway Interface is a specification for processing data on a Web server.","case":"Content Objective: 6.4","answer":"true"},{"chapter":6,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"6.5","diff":"2","number":"19","ref":"233","question":"Data administration is a special organizational function that manages the policies and procedures through which data can be managed as an organizational resource.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"1","chapter":6,"ref":"234","question":"Data cleansing is the same process as data scrubbing.","case":"Content Objective: 6.5","answer":"true"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"6.1","option":[{"value":"data inconsistency","index":"A"},{"value":"program-data independence","index":"B"},{"value":"lack of flexibility in creating ad-hoc reports","index":"C"},{"value":"poor security","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"21","ref":"211-212","question":"Which of the following is NOT one of the main problems with a traditional file environment?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","option":[{"value":"enforcing referential integrity.","index":"A"},{"value":"uncoupling program and data.","index":"B"},{"value":"utilizing a data dictionary.","index":"C"},{"value":"minimizing isolated files with repeated data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"22","ref":"213","question":"A DBMS reduces data redundancy and inconsistency by","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 6.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"23","option":[{"value":"the entity CUSTOMER with the attribute PRODUCT","index":"A"},{"value":"the entity CUSTOMER with the attribute PURCHASE","index":"B"},{"value":"the entity PRODUCT with the attribute PURCHASE","index":"C"},{"value":"the entity PRODUCT with the attribute CUSTOMER","index":"D"}],"chapter":6,"ref":"210","question":"Which of the following best illustrates the relationship between entities and attributes?","diff":"3","answer":"b"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"field.","index":"A"},{"value":"tuple.","index":"B"},{"value":"key field.","index":"C"},{"value":"attribute.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"24","ref":"210","question":"A characteristic or quality describing an entity is called a(n)","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 6.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"25","option":[{"value":"library card catalog.","index":"A"},{"value":"cash register receipt.","index":"B"},{"value":"doctor's office invoice.","index":"C"},{"value":"list of sales totals on a spreadsheet.","index":"D"}],"chapter":6,"ref":"210-211","question":"Which of the following non-digital data storage items is most similar to a database?","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","option":[{"value":"batch processing","index":"A"},{"value":"data redundancy","index":"B"},{"value":"data independence","index":"C"},{"value":"online processing","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"26","ref":"211","question":"The confusion created by ________ makes it difficult for companies to create customer relationship management, supply chain management, or enterprise systems that integrate data from different sources.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","option":[{"value":"redundancy","index":"A"},{"value":"repetition","index":"B"},{"value":"independence","index":"C"},{"value":"partitions","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"27","ref":"211","question":"Duplicate data in multiple data files is called data ________.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"physical database available for different logical views.","index":"A"},{"value":"logical database available for different analytical views.","index":"B"},{"value":"physical database available for different analytical views.","index":"C"},{"value":"relational database available for different physical views.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"28","ref":"212","question":"A DBMS makes the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"shows how data are organized and structured on the storage media.","index":"A"},{"value":"presents an entry screen to the user.","index":"B"},{"value":"allows the creation of supplementary reports.","index":"C"},{"value":"presents data as they would be perceived by end users.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"29","ref":"212","question":"The logical view","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"DB2.","index":"A"},{"value":"Oracle.","index":"B"},{"value":"Microsoft SQL Server.","index":"C"},{"value":"Microsoft Access.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"30","ref":"213","question":"DBMS for midrange computers include all of the following EXCEPT","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"OODBMS.","index":"A"},{"value":"pre-digital DBMS.","index":"B"},{"value":"relational DBMS.","index":"C"},{"value":"hierarchical DBMS.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"31","ref":"213","question":"The type of logical database model that treats data as if they were stored in two-dimensional tables is the","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"DBMS for small handheld computing devices.","index":"A"},{"value":"Internet DBMS.","index":"B"},{"value":"mainframe relational DBMS.","index":"C"},{"value":"DBMS for midrange computers.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"32","ref":"213","question":"Oracle Database Lite is a(n)","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"DBMS for small handheld computing devices.","index":"A"},{"value":"Internet DBMS.","index":"B"},{"value":"desktop relational DBMS.","index":"C"},{"value":"DBMS for midrange computers.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"33","ref":"213","question":"Microsoft SQL Server is a(n)","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"field.","index":"A"},{"value":"row.","index":"B"},{"value":"column.","index":"C"},{"value":"table.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"34","ref":"214","question":"In a table for customers, the information about a single customer would reside in a single","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"tuple.","index":"A"},{"value":"row.","index":"B"},{"value":"entity.","index":"C"},{"value":"field.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"35","ref":"214","question":"In a relational database, a record is referred to in technical terms as a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"primary key.","index":"A"},{"value":"key field.","index":"B"},{"value":"primary field.","index":"C"},{"value":"unique ID.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"36","ref":"214","question":"A field identified in a table as holding the unique identifier of the table's records is called the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"primary key.","index":"A"},{"value":"key field.","index":"B"},{"value":"primary field.","index":"C"},{"value":"unique ID.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"37","ref":"214","question":"A field identified in a record as holding the unique identifier for that record is called the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"select, project, and where.","index":"A"},{"value":"select, join, and where.","index":"B"},{"value":"select, project, and join.","index":"C"},{"value":"select, from, and join.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"38","ref":"215","question":"In a relational database, the three basic operations used to develop useful sets of data are","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"combines relational tables to provide the user with more information than is otherwise available.","index":"A"},{"value":"creates a subset consisting of columns in a table.","index":"B"},{"value":"identifies the table from which the columns will be selected.","index":"C"},{"value":"creates a subset consisting of all records in the file that meet stated criteria.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"39","ref":"215","question":"The select operation","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"combines relational tables to provide the user with more information than is otherwise available.","index":"A"},{"value":"identifies the table from which the columns will be selected.","index":"B"},{"value":"creates a subset consisting of columns in a table.","index":"C"},{"value":"organizes elements into segments.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"40","ref":"215","question":"The join operation","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"combines relational tables to provide the user with more information than is otherwise available.","index":"A"},{"value":"creates a subset consisting of columns in a table.","index":"B"},{"value":"organizes elements into segments.","index":"C"},{"value":"identifies the table from which the columns will be selected.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"41","ref":"215","question":"The project operation","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"relational DBMS","index":"A"},{"value":"hierarchical DBMS","index":"B"},{"value":"object-relational DBMS","index":"C"},{"value":"OODBMS","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"42","ref":"215","question":"Which of the following database types is useful for storing java applets as well as processing large numbers of transactions?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"hierarchical DBMS.","index":"A"},{"value":"relational DBMS.","index":"B"},{"value":"network DBMS.","index":"C"},{"value":"object-oriented DBMS.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"43","ref":"215","question":"The type of database management approach that can handle multimedia is the","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"assigning attributes to the data.","index":"A"},{"value":"creating an inventory of data contained in the database.","index":"B"},{"value":"presenting data as end users or business specialists would perceive them.","index":"C"},{"value":"maintaining data in updated form.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"44","ref":"217","question":"The data dictionary serves as an important data management tool by","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"data dictionary.","index":"A"},{"value":"data definition diagram.","index":"B"},{"value":"entity-relationship diagram.","index":"C"},{"value":"relationship dictionary.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"45","ref":"217","question":"An automated or manual file that stores information about data elements and data characteristics such as usage, physical representation, ownership, authorization, and security is the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"a data access language.","index":"A"},{"value":"a data manipulation language.","index":"B"},{"value":"structured Query language.","index":"C"},{"value":"a data definition language.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"46","ref":"217","question":"The specialized language programmers use to add and change data in the database is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","option":[{"value":"Access.","index":"A"},{"value":"DB2.","index":"B"},{"value":"SQL.","index":"C"},{"value":"Crystal Reports.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"47","ref":"217","question":"The most prominent data manipulation language today is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","option":[{"value":"retrieve and display data.","index":"A"},{"value":"display data in an easier-to-read format.","index":"B"},{"value":"display data in graphs.","index":"C"},{"value":"perform predictive analysis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"48","ref":"219","question":"DBMSs typically include report-generating tools in order to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"normalization.","index":"A"},{"value":"data scrubbing.","index":"B"},{"value":"data cleansing.","index":"C"},{"value":"data defining.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"49","ref":"219","question":"The process of streamlining data to minimize redundancy and awkward many-to-many relationships is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"data dictionary.","index":"A"},{"value":"intersection relationship diagram.","index":"B"},{"value":"entity-relationship diagram.","index":"C"},{"value":"data definition diagram.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"50","ref":"220","question":"A schematic of the entire database that describes the relationships in a database is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"two short marks.","index":"A"},{"value":"one short mark.","index":"B"},{"value":"a crow's foot.","index":"C"},{"value":"a crow's foot topped by a short mark.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"51","ref":"220","question":"A one-to-one relationship between two entities is symbolized in a diagram by a line that ends with","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"two short marks.","index":"A"},{"value":"one short mark.","index":"B"},{"value":"a crow's foot.","index":"C"},{"value":"a crow's foot topped by a short mark.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"52","ref":"220","question":"A one-to-many relationship between two entities is symbolized in a diagram by a line that ends with","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"partitioned","index":"A"},{"value":"normalized","index":"B"},{"value":"replicated","index":"C"},{"value":"networked","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"53","ref":"221","question":"In what type of a database system is the entire central database duplicated at all remote locations?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.3","option":[{"value":"lack of flexibility","index":"A"},{"value":"susceptibility to data inconsistency","index":"B"},{"value":"poor responsiveness to local users","index":"C"},{"value":"requires more expensive computers","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"54","ref":"222","question":"Which of the following is a main disadvantage to a distributed database system?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"historical data from legacy systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"current data.","index":"B"},{"value":"internal and external data sources.","index":"C"},{"value":"historic and current internal data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"55","ref":"223","question":"A data warehouse is composed of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"a data mart typically focuses on a single subject area or line of business.","index":"A"},{"value":"all the information is historical.","index":"B"},{"value":"a data mart uses a Web interface.","index":"C"},{"value":"all of the information belongs to a single company.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"56","ref":"225","question":"A data mart usually can be constructed more rapidly and at lower cost than a data warehouse because","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"DSS.","index":"A"},{"value":"business intelligence.","index":"B"},{"value":"OLAP.","index":"C"},{"value":"data mining.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"57","ref":"226","question":"Tools for consolidating, analyzing, and providing access to vast amounts of data to help users make better business decisions are known as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"predictive analysis.","index":"A"},{"value":"SQL.","index":"B"},{"value":"OLAP.","index":"C"},{"value":"data mining.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"58","ref":"226","question":"The tool that enables users to view the same data in different ways using multiple dimensions is","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"users to obtain online answers to ad-hoc questions in a rapid amount of time.","index":"A"},{"value":"users to view both logical and physical views of data.","index":"B"},{"value":"programmers to quickly diagram data relationships.","index":"C"},{"value":"programmers to normalize data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"59","ref":"226-227","question":"OLAP is a tool for enabling","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"quickly compare transaction data gathered over many years.","index":"A"},{"value":"find hidden relationships in data.","index":"B"},{"value":"obtain online answers to ad hoc questions in a rapid amount of time.","index":"C"},{"value":"summarize massive amounts of data into much smaller, traditional reports.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"60","ref":"228","question":"Data mining is a tool for allowing users to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"events linked over time.","index":"A"},{"value":"patterns that describe a group to which an item belongs.","index":"B"},{"value":"occurrences linked to a single event.","index":"C"},{"value":"undiscovered groupings.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"61","ref":"228","question":"In terms of data relationships, associations refers to","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"OLAP","index":"A"},{"value":"Text mining","index":"B"},{"value":"Web mining","index":"C"},{"value":"Web content mining","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"62","ref":"229","question":"________ tools are used to analyze large unstructured data sets, such as e-mail, memos, survey responses, etc., to discover patterns and relationships.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","option":[{"value":"CGI.","index":"A"},{"value":"HTML.","index":"B"},{"value":"Java.","index":"C"},{"value":"SQL.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"63","ref":"230-231","question":"An alternative to using application server software for interfacing between a Web server and back-end databases is","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.5","option":[{"value":"information policy.","index":"A"},{"value":"data definition file.","index":"B"},{"value":"data quality audit.","index":"C"},{"value":"data governance policy.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"64","ref":"231","question":"The organization's rules for sharing, disseminating, acquiring, standardizing, classifying, and inventorying information is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.5","option":[{"value":"data administration.","index":"A"},{"value":"database administration.","index":"B"},{"value":"information policy administration.","index":"C"},{"value":"data auditing.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"65","ref":"233","question":"The special organizational function whose responsibilities include the technical and operational aspects of managing data, including physical database design and maintenance, is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"6.5","option":[{"value":"data normalization","index":"A"},{"value":"data accuracy","index":"B"},{"value":"data redundancy","index":"C"},{"value":"data inconsistency","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"66","ref":"234","question":"Which common database challenge is illustrated by the text's discussion of receiving multiple pieces of the same direct mail advertising?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.5","option":[{"value":"data auditing.","index":"A"},{"value":"defragmentation.","index":"B"},{"value":"data scrubbing.","index":"C"},{"value":"data optimization.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"67","ref":"234","question":"Detecting and correcting data in a database or file that are incorrect, incomplete, improperly formatted, or redundant is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":6,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"6.5","option":[{"value":"program-data dependence","index":"A"},{"value":"data redundancy","index":"B"},{"value":"scalability","index":"C"},{"value":"data quality","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"68","ref":"232","question":"As discussed in the Interactive Session: Technology, what problem was MySpace facing in its data management?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Content Objective: 6.5","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"69","option":[{"value":"establishes logical relationships between data.","index":"A"},{"value":"structures data.","index":"B"},{"value":"normalizes data.","index":"C"},{"value":"enforces consistency among different sets of data.","index":"D"}],"chapter":6,"ref":"234","question":"Data cleansing not only corrects errors but also","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 6.5","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"70","option":[{"value":"surveying entire data files","index":"A"},{"value":"surveying samples from data files","index":"B"},{"value":"surveying data definition and query files","index":"C"},{"value":"surveying end users about their perceptions of data quality","index":"D"}],"chapter":6,"ref":"234","question":"Which of the following is NOT a method for performing a data quality audit?","diff":"3","answer":"c"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","diff":"1","number":"71","ref":"210","question":"Databases record information about general categories of information referred to as ________.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"entities"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","diff":"2","number":"72","ref":"211","question":"Data ________ describes a situation in which the same attribute of a data entity may have different values.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"inconsistency"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.1","diff":"1","number":"73","ref":"212","question":"A(n) ________ view shows data as it is actually organized and structured on the data storage media.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"physical"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"74","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"217","question":"DBMS have a(n) ________ capability to specify the structure of the content of the database.","case":"Content Objective: 6.2","answer":"data definition"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.2","diff":"3","number":"75","ref":"220","question":"RDBMSs use ________ rules to ensure that relationships between coupled tables remain consistent.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"referential integrity"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"76","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"221","question":"A(n) ________ database is one that is stored in more than one physical location.","case":"Content Objective: 6.3","answer":"distributed"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"228","question":"In ________, a data mining tool discovers different groupings within data, such as finding affinity groups for bank cards.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"clustering"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","diff":"2","number":"78","ref":"229","question":"The discovery and analysis of useful patterns and information from hypertext documents on the Internet is called ________.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Web mining"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.4","diff":"1","number":"79","ref":"230","question":"A(n) ________ is software that handles all application operations between browser-based computers and a company's back-end business applications or databases.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"application server"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"6.5","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"231","question":"________ are the formal rules governing the maintenance, distribution, and use of information in an organization.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Information policies"},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"6.5","diff":"2","number":"81","ref":"231-234","question":"The small publishing company you work for wants to create a new database for storing information about all of their author contracts. What factors will influence how you design the database?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Student answers will vary, but should include some assessment of data quality; business processes and user needs; and relationship to existing IT systems. Key points to include are:\nData accuracy when the new data is input, establishing a good data model, determining which data is important and anticipating what the possible uses for the data will be, beyond looking up contract information, technical difficulties linking this system to existing systems, new business processes for data input and handling, and contracts management, determining how end users will use the data, making data definitions consistent with other databases, what methods to use to cleanse the data."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"82","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"209-210, 213-215","question":"When you design the new contracts database for the publishing house mentioned above, what fields do you anticipate needing? Which of these fields might be in use in other databases used by the company?","case":"Synthesis Objective: 6.1","answer":"Author first name, author last name, author address, agent name and address, title of book, book ISBN, date of contract, amount of money, payment schedule, date contract ends.\nOther databases might be an author database (author names, address, and agent details), a book title database (title and ISBN of book), and financial database (payments made)."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"6.1","diff":"2","number":"83","ref":"211","question":"List at least three conditions that contribute to data redundancy and inconsistency.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Data redundancy occurs when different divisions, functional areas, and groups in an organization independently collect the same piece of information. Because it is collected and maintained in so many different places, the same data item may have: (1) different meanings in different parts of the organization, (2) different names may be used for the same item, and (3) different descriptions for the same condition. In addition, the fields into which the data is gathered may have different field names, different attributes, or different constraints."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"84","diff":"2","chapter":6,"ref":"216-217","question":"List and describe three main capabilities or tools of a DBMS.","case":"Analysis Objective: 6.2","answer":"A data definition capability to specify the structure of the content of the database. This capability would be used to create database tables and to define the characteristics of the fields in each table.\nA data dictionary to store definitions of data elements in the database and their characteristics. In large corporate databases, the data dictionary may capture additional information, such as usage; ownership; authorization; security; and the individuals, business functions, programs, and reports that use each data element.\nA data manipulation language, such as SQL, that is used to add, change, delete, and retrieve the data in the database. This language contains commands that permit end users and programming specialists to extract data from the database to satisfy information requests and develop applications."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"6.2","diff":"3","number":"85","ref":"219-220","question":"What types of relationships are possible in a relational database? Describe and give an example of each.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"A one-to-one relationship occurs when each record in one table has only one related record in a second table. An example might be a table of salespeople and a separate table of company cars. Each salesperson can only have one car, or be related to the one car in the database.\nA one-to-many relationship occurs when a record in one table has many related records in a second table. An example might be a table of salespeople and clients. Each salesperson may have several clients.\nA many-to-many relationship occurs when records in one table have many related records in a second table, and the records in the second table have many related records in the first table. An example might be a clients table and a products table. Clients may buy more than one product, and products are sold to more than one client."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"6.2","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"215","question":"Identify and describe three basic operations used to extract useful sets of data from a relational database.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"The select operation creates a subset consisting of all records (rows) in the table that meets stated criteria. The join operation combines relational tables to provide the user with more information than is available in individual tables. The project operation creates a subset consisting of columns in a table, permitting the user to create new tables that contain only the information required."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"6.4","diff":"3","number":"87","ref":"213, 222-231","question":"Describe the ways in which database technologies could be used by an office stationery supply company to achieve low-cost leadership.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Sales databases could be used to make the supply chain more efficient and minimize warehousing and transportation costs. You can also use sales databases to determine what supplies are in demand by which customers, and whether needs are different in different geographical areas. DSS databases using business intelligence could be used to predict future trends in office supply needs, to help anticipate demand, and to determine the most efficient methods of transportation and delivery."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"6.4","diff":"3","number":"88","ref":"222-231","question":"Describe the ways in which database technologies could be used by an office stationery supply company to achieve product differentiation.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Product databases could be made available to customers for greater convenience when ordering online. Databases could be used to track customer preferences and to help anticipate customer desires. Sales databases could also help a client anticipate when they would need to re- supply, providing an additional service. Data mining could help anticipate trends in sales or other factors to help determine new services and products to sell to the clients."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"6.4","diff":"3","number":"89","ref":"228-229","question":"What makes data mining an important business tool? What types of information does data mining produce? In what type of circumstance would you advise a company to use data mining?","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Data mining is one of the data analysis tools that helps users make better business decisions and is one of the key tools of business intelligence. Data mining allows users to analyze large amounts of data and find hidden relationships between data that otherwise would not be discovered. For example, data mining might find that a customer that buys product X is ten times more likely to buy product Y than other customers.\nData mining finds information such as:\n• Associations or occurrences that are linked to a single event.\n• Sequences, events that are linked over time.\n• Classification, patterns that describe the group to which an item belongs, found by examining existing items that have been classified and by inferring a set of rules.\n• Clusters, unclassified but related groups.\nI would advise a company to use data mining when they are looking for new products and services, or when they are looking for new marketing techniques or new markets. Data mining might also be helpful when trying to analyze unanticipated problems with sales whose causes are difficult to identify."},{"chapter":6,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"6.4","diff":"2","number":"90","ref":"226-229","question":"What are the differences between data mining and OLAP? When would you advise a company to use OLAP?","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Data mining uncovers hidden relationships and is used when you are trying to discover data and new relationships. It is used to answer questions such as: Are there any product sales that are related in time to other product sales?\nIn contrast, OLAP is used to analyze multiple dimensions of data and is used to find answers to complex, but known, questions, such as: What were sales of a productbroken down by month and geographical region, and how did those sales compare to sales forecasts?"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"1","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"249","question":"Telephone networks are fundamentally different from computer networks.","case":"Content Objective: 7.1","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"2","diff":"1","chapter":7,"ref":"249","question":"Increasingly, voice, video, and data communications are all based on Internet technology.","case":"Content Objective: 7.1","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"3","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"249","question":"To connect two computers together in the same office, you must have a computer network.","case":"Content Objective: 7.1","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"4","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"250","question":"An NOS must reside on a dedicated server computer in order to manage a network.","case":"Content Objective: 7.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"2","number":"5","ref":"250","question":"A hub is a networking device that connects network components and are used to filter and forward data to specified destinations on the network.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"2","number":"6","ref":"252","question":"In a client/server network, a network server provides every connected client with an address so it can be found by others on the network.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"252","question":"Central large mainframe computing has largely replaced client/server computing.","case":"Content Objective: 7.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"1","number":"8","ref":"252","question":"Circuit switching makes much more efficient use of the communications capacity of a network than does packet switching.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"1","number":"9","ref":"253","question":"A protocol is a standard set of rules and procedures for the control of communications in a network.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"1","number":"10","ref":"254","question":"Two computers using TCP/IP can communicate even if they are based on different hardware and software platforms.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","diff":"3","number":"11","ref":"256","question":"In a ring topology, one station transmits signals, which travel in both directions along a single transmission segment.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","diff":"2","number":"12","ref":"257","question":"Coaxial cable is similar to that used for cable television and consists of thickly insulated copper wire.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"13","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"257-258","question":"Fiber-optic cable is more expensive and harder to install than wire media.","case":"Content Objective: 7.2","answer":"true"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","diff":"2","number":"14","ref":"259","question":"The number of cycles per second that can be sent through any telecommunications medium is measured in kilobytes.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"15","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"265","question":"The success of the Internet is in part due to its design as an infinitely scalable network capable of handling millions of users.","case":"Evaluation Objective: 7.3","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"16","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"267","question":"VoIP technology delivers video information in digital form using packet switching.","case":"Content Objective: 7.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","diff":"2","number":"17","ref":"276","question":"Web 2.0 is the collaborative effort led by the World Wide Web Consortium to add a layer of meaning atop the existing Web to reduce the amount of human involvement in searching for and processing Web information.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","diff":"2","number":"18","ref":"281","question":"Wi-Fi enables users to freely roam from hotspot to hotspot even if the hotspot is using different Wi-Fi network services.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"19","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"281","question":"WiMax has a wireless access range of up to 300 feet.","case":"Content Objective: 7.4","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"1","chapter":7,"ref":"283","question":"RFID has been exceptionally popular because of its low implementation costs.","case":"Content Objective: 7.5","answer":"false"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","option":[{"value":"hub.","index":"A"},{"value":"switch.","index":"B"},{"value":"router.","index":"C"},{"value":"NIC.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"21","ref":"250","question":"A device that acts as a connection point between computers and can filter and forward data to a specified destination is called a","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Content Objective: 7.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"22","option":[{"value":"TCP/IP, HTML, and HTTP","index":"A"},{"value":"TCP/IP, HTTP, and packet switching","index":"B"},{"value":"Client/server computing, packet switching, and the development of communications standards for linking networks and computers","index":"C"},{"value":"Client/server computing, packet switching, and HTTP","index":"D"}],"chapter":7,"ref":"252","question":"The Internet is based on which three key technologies?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","option":[{"value":"multiplexing.","index":"A"},{"value":"packet switching.","index":"B"},{"value":"packet routing.","index":"C"},{"value":"ATM.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"23","ref":"252","question":"The method of slicing digital messages into parcels, transmitting them along different communication paths, and reassembling them at their destinations is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","option":[{"value":"peer-to-peer","index":"A"},{"value":"wireless","index":"B"},{"value":"packet-switched","index":"C"},{"value":"circuit-switched","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"24","ref":"252","question":"The telephone system is an example of a ________ network.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Content Objective: 7.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"25","option":[{"value":"Packets travel independently of each other.","index":"A"},{"value":"Packets are routed through many different paths.","index":"B"},{"value":"Packet switching requires point-to-point circuits.","index":"C"},{"value":"Packets include data for checking transmission errors.","index":"D"}],"chapter":7,"ref":"252","question":"Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of packet switching?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","option":[{"value":"disassembling and reassembling of packets during transmission.","index":"A"},{"value":"establishing an Internet connection between two computers.","index":"B"},{"value":"moving packets over the network.","index":"C"},{"value":"sequencing the transfer of packets.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"26","ref":"253","question":"In TCP/IP, IP is responsible for","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","option":[{"value":"a device that handles the switching of voice and data in a local area network.","index":"A"},{"value":"a standard set of rules and procedures for control of communications in a network.","index":"B"},{"value":"a communications service for microcomputer users.","index":"C"},{"value":"the main computer in a telecommunications network.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"27","ref":"253","question":"In a telecommunications network architecture, a protocol is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","option":[{"value":"physical layer, application layer, transport layer, and the network interface layer.","index":"A"},{"value":"physical layer, application layer, Internet layer, and the network interface layer.","index":"B"},{"value":"application layer, transport layer, Internet layer, and the network interface layer.","index":"C"},{"value":"application layer, hardware layer, Internet layer, and the network interface layer.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"28","ref":"253-254","question":"The four layers of the TCP/IP reference model are","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"laser","index":"A"},{"value":"optical","index":"B"},{"value":"digital","index":"C"},{"value":"analog","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"29","ref":"254","question":"Which signal types are represented by a continuous waveform?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"a modem.","index":"A"},{"value":"a router.","index":"B"},{"value":"DSL.","index":"C"},{"value":"twisted wire.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"30","ref":"255","question":"To use an analog telephone system for sending digital data, you must us","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"microwave","index":"A"},{"value":"LAN","index":"B"},{"value":"WAN","index":"C"},{"value":"MAN","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"31","ref":"255","question":"Which type of network is used to connect digital devices within a half-mile or 500-meter radius?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"peer-to-peer","index":"A"},{"value":"wireless","index":"B"},{"value":"LAN","index":"C"},{"value":"ring","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"32","ref":"256","question":"Which type of network treats all processors equally, and allows peripheral devices to be shared without going to a separate server?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 7.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"33","option":[{"value":"wireless network in infrastructure mode","index":"A"},{"value":"domain-based LAN","index":"B"},{"value":"peer-to-peer network","index":"C"},{"value":"campus area network","index":"D"}],"chapter":7,"ref":"256","question":"Which type of network would be most appropriate for a business that comprised three employees and a manager located in the same office space, whose primary need is to share documents?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"signals are broadcast to the next station.","index":"A"},{"value":"signals are broadcast in both directions to the entire network.","index":"B"},{"value":"multiple hubs are organized in a hierarchy.","index":"C"},{"value":"messages pass from computer to computer in a loop.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"34","ref":"256","question":"In a bus network","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"star","index":"A"},{"value":"bus","index":"B"},{"value":"domain","index":"C"},{"value":"peer-to-peer","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"35","ref":"256","question":"All network components connect to a single hub in a ________ network.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"bus.","index":"A"},{"value":"star.","index":"B"},{"value":"ring.","index":"C"},{"value":"mesh.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"36","ref":"256","question":"The most common Ethernet topology is","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"CAN.","index":"A"},{"value":"MAN.","index":"B"},{"value":"WAN.","index":"C"},{"value":"LAN.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"37","ref":"256","question":"A network that spans a city, and sometimes its major suburbs as well, is called a","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"local area network.","index":"A"},{"value":"intranet.","index":"B"},{"value":"peer-to-peer network.","index":"C"},{"value":"wide area network.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"38","ref":"256","question":"A network that covers entire geographical regions is most commonly referred to as a(n):","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"Cell phones","index":"A"},{"value":"Microwaves","index":"B"},{"value":"Satellites","index":"C"},{"value":"WANs","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"39","ref":"258","question":"________ work(s) by using radio waves to communicate with radio antennas placed within adjacent geographic areas.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"number of frequencies that can be broadcast through a medium.","index":"A"},{"value":"number of cycles per second that can be sent through a medium.","index":"B"},{"value":"difference between the highest and lowest frequencies that can be accommodated on a single channel.","index":"C"},{"value":"total number of bytes that can be sent through a medium per second.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"40","ref":"259","question":"Bandwidth is the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","option":[{"value":"bps.","index":"A"},{"value":"Hertz.","index":"B"},{"value":"baud.","index":"C"},{"value":"gigaflops.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"41","ref":"259","question":"The total amount of digital information that can be transmitted through any telecommunications medium is measured in","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"operate over existing telephone lines to carry voice, data, and video.","index":"A"},{"value":"operate over coaxial lines to deliver Internet access.","index":"B"},{"value":"are very-high-speed data lines typically leased from long-distance telephone companies.","index":"C"},{"value":"have up to twenty-four 64-Kbps channels.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"42","ref":"260","question":"Digital subscriber lines","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"operate over existing telephone lines to carry voice, data, and video.","index":"A"},{"value":"operate over coaxial lines to deliver Internet access.","index":"B"},{"value":"are very-high-speed data lines typically leased from long-distance telephone companies.","index":"C"},{"value":"have up to twenty-four 64-Kbps channels.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"43","ref":"260","question":"T lines","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"TCP/IP","index":"A"},{"value":"FTP","index":"B"},{"value":"packet-switching","index":"C"},{"value":"HTTP","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"44","ref":"260","question":"Which protocol is the Internet based on?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"HTML","index":"A"},{"value":"DNS","index":"B"},{"value":"IP","index":"C"},{"value":"HTTP","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"45","ref":"260","question":"What service converts IP addresses into more recognizable alphanumeric names?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"top-level domain.","index":"A"},{"value":"second-level domain.","index":"B"},{"value":"host name.","index":"C"},{"value":"domain extension.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"46","ref":"260","question":"The child domain of the root is the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"\"http://\", myspace, blogging, com","index":"A"},{"value":"\"http://\", com, blogging, myspace","index":"B"},{"value":"\".\", com, blogging, myspace","index":"C"},{"value":"\".\", myspace, blogging, com","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"47","ref":"261","question":"In the domain name \"http://myspace.blogging.com\", what are the root, top-level, second- level, and third-level domains, respectively?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"None (no one \"owns\" the Internet)","index":"A"},{"value":"W3C","index":"B"},{"value":"ICANN","index":"C"},{"value":"IAB","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"48","ref":"262","question":"Which organization helps define the overall structure of the Internet?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"update the packet transmission protocols for higher bandwidth.","index":"A"},{"value":"create more IP addresses.","index":"B"},{"value":"allow for different levels of service.","index":"C"},{"value":"support Internet2.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"49","ref":"265","question":"IPv6 is being developed in order to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"FTP","index":"A"},{"value":"LISTSERV","index":"B"},{"value":"Telnet","index":"C"},{"value":"World Wide Web","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"50","ref":"263","question":"Which of the following services enables logging on to one computer system and working on another?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"chat","index":"A"},{"value":"cellular","index":"B"},{"value":"Web","index":"C"},{"value":"wireless","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"51","ref":"267","question":"Instant messaging is a type of ________ service.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"cannot restrict Internet use.","index":"A"},{"value":"need specialized software to determine which types of material are acceptable.","index":"B"},{"value":"may need to maintain a database of acceptable Web sites.","index":"C"},{"value":"need to base their Internet use policies on the needs of the organization and culture.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"52","ref":"268-269","question":"The need in some cases for employees to have access to sexually explicit material on the Internet, such as medical researchers, suggests that companies","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"Wireless networks","index":"A"},{"value":"Intranets","index":"B"},{"value":"Virtual private networks","index":"C"},{"value":"Unified communications","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"53","ref":"270","question":"________ integrate(s) disparate channels for voice communications, data communications, instant messaging, e-mail, and electronic conferencing into a single experience.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"is an encrypted private network configured within a public network.","index":"A"},{"value":"is more expensive than a dedicated network.","index":"B"},{"value":"provides secure, encrypted communications using Telnet.","index":"C"},{"value":"is an Internet-based service for delivering voice communications.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"54","ref":"270","question":"A VPN","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"URL","index":"A"},{"value":"HTTP","index":"B"},{"value":"DNS","index":"C"},{"value":"HTML","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"55","ref":"271","question":"Web browser software requests Web pages from the Internet using which protocol?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"uniform resource locator.","index":"A"},{"value":"unified resource locator.","index":"B"},{"value":"third level domain.","index":"C"},{"value":"root domain.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"56","ref":"271","question":"Together, a protocol prefix, a domain name, a directory path, and a document name, are called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"Microsoft IIS.","index":"A"},{"value":"ASP.net.","index":"B"},{"value":"Apache HTTP server.","index":"C"},{"value":"Netscape.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"57","ref":"272","question":"The open-source Web server that controls 70 percent of the market is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"FTP","index":"A"},{"value":"RSS","index":"B"},{"value":"HTTP","index":"C"},{"value":"Bluetooth","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"58","ref":"275","question":"What technology allows people to have content pulled from Web sites and fed automatically to their computers?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"router","index":"A"},{"value":"server","index":"B"},{"value":"firewall","index":"C"},{"value":"switch","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"59","ref":"277","question":"To keep internal data secure, a company employing an extranet must be sure to put a ________ in place","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","option":[{"value":"intranet.","index":"A"},{"value":"extranet.","index":"B"},{"value":"enterprise network.","index":"C"},{"value":"virtual private network.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"60","ref":"277","question":"A network that connects authorized customers, suppliers, and other business partners to portions of a firm's internal network is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"2.5G","index":"A"},{"value":"3G","index":"B"},{"value":"3.5G","index":"C"},{"value":"4G","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"61","ref":"278","question":"Which generation of network are wireless cellular phone systems entering?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"is the major European digital cellular standard.","index":"A"},{"value":"is more expensive than GSM.","index":"B"},{"value":"transmits over several frequencies.","index":"C"},{"value":"uses the 1.9 GHz band.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"62","ref":"278","question":"CDMA","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"I-mode.","index":"A"},{"value":"IEEE 802.11b.","index":"B"},{"value":"WiFi.","index":"C"},{"value":"Bluetooth.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"63","ref":"279","question":"The most appropriate wireless networking standard for creating PANs is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"four","index":"A"},{"value":"six","index":"B"},{"value":"eight","index":"C"},{"value":"ten","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"64","ref":"279","question":"Bluetooth can be used to link up to ________ devices within a 10-meter area using low- power, radio-based communication.","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"54 Mbps in the 5-GHz frequency range.","index":"A"},{"value":"11 Mbps in the 2.4-GHz frequency range.","index":"B"},{"value":"54 Mbps in the 2.4-GHz frequency range.","index":"C"},{"value":"722 Kbps in the 2.4-GHz frequency range.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"65","ref":"280","question":"The Wi-Fi 802.11a standard can transmit up to","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"touch points.","index":"A"},{"value":"hotspots.","index":"B"},{"value":"hot points.","index":"C"},{"value":"wireless hubs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"66","ref":"281","question":"One or more access points positioned on a ceiling, wall, or other strategic spot in a public place to provide maximum wireless coverage for a specific area are referred to as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"IEEE 802.15.","index":"A"},{"value":"IEEE 802.11.","index":"B"},{"value":"IEEE 802.16.","index":"C"},{"value":"IEEE 802.20.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"67","ref":"281","question":"The IEEE standard for the WiMax is","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","option":[{"value":"30 meters.","index":"A"},{"value":"500 meters.","index":"B"},{"value":"30 miles.","index":"C"},{"value":"5 miles.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"68","ref":"281","question":"The WiMax standard can transmit up to a distance of approximately","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"7.5","option":[{"value":"have their own power source.","index":"A"},{"value":"have a range of several feet.","index":"B"},{"value":"enable data to be rewritten and modified.","index":"C"},{"value":"are used in automated toll-collection systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"69","ref":"283","question":"Passive RFID tags","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":7,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"7.5","option":[{"value":"transactions","index":"A"},{"value":"supply chain management","index":"B"},{"value":"lowering network costs","index":"C"},{"value":"enabling client communication","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"70","ref":"282-283","question":"Based on your reading of the examples in the chapter, what would be the best use of RFID for a business?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"2","number":"71","ref":"250","question":"The ________ is special software that routes and manages communications on the network and coordinates networks resources.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"network operating system"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"2","number":"72","ref":"250-251","question":"A(n) ________ is a device that forwards packets of data through different networks, ensuring that the data gets to the right address.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"router"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.1","diff":"2","number":"73","ref":"252","question":"Prior to the development of ________, computer networks used leased, dedicated telephone circuits to communicate with other computers in remote locations.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"packet switching"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"254","question":"A(n) ________ signal is a discrete, binary waveform that transmits data coded into two discrete states such as 1-bits and 0-bits.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"digital"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"75","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"256","question":"________ is the manner in which the components of a network are connected.","case":"Content Objective: 7.2","answer":"Topology"},{"type":2,"question":"________ is the dominant LAN standard at the physical network level.\n￼CASE: Content Objective: 7.2","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"256","number":"76","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Ethernet"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"260","question":"A(n) ________ is a commercial organization with a permanent connection to the Internet that sells temporary connections to retail subscribers.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Internet service provider"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.3","diff":"2","number":"78","ref":"261","question":"The backbone networks of the Internet are typically owned by long-distance telephone companies called ________.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"network service providers"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"79","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"271","question":"A(n) ________ is software for locating and managing stored Web pages.","case":"Content Objective: 7.3","answer":"Web server"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"7.4","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"280","question":"A(n) ________ is a box consisting of a radio receiver/transmitter and antennas that links to a wired network, router, or hub.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"access point"},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"7.1","diff":"2","number":"81","ref":"252","question":"How does packet switching work?\n￼￼","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Packet switching is a method of slicing digital messages into parcels called packets, sending the packets along different communication paths as they become available, and then reassembling the packets once they arrive at their destinations. Packet switching makes much more efficient use of the communications capacity of a network than did circuit-switching. In packet-switched networks, messages are first broken down into small fixed bundles of data called packets. The packets include information for directing the packet to the right address and for checking transmission errors along with the data. The packets are transmitted over various communications channels using routers, each packet traveling independently. Packets of data originating at one source will be routed through many different paths and networks before being reassembled into the original message when they reach their destinations."},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"7.1","diff":"3","number":"82","ref":"253-254","question":"Identify the layers of the Department of Defense reference model for TCP/IP, and describe how this model works.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The application layer enables client application programs to access the other layers and defines the protocols that applications use to exchange data. One of these application protocols is the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP), which is used to transfer Web page files. The transport layer is responsible for providing the application layer with communication and packet services. This layer includes TCP and other protocols. The Internet layer is responsible for addressing, routing, and packaging data packets called IP datagrams. The Internet Protocol is one of the protocols used in this layer. At the bottom of the reference model, the network interface layer is responsible for placing packets on and receiving them from the network medium, which could be any networking technology. Data sent from one computer to the other passes downward through all four layers, starting with the sending computer's application layer and passing through the network interface layer. After the data reach the recipient host computer, they travel up the layers and are reassembled into a format the receiving computer can use. If the receiving computer finds a damaged packet, it asks the sending computer to retransmit it. This process is reversed when the receiving computer responds."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"83","diff":"3","chapter":7,"ref":"255-259","question":"You have been hired by a tax preparation firm to set up a network connecting several new branches in a metropolitan area. What type of network hardware and transmission media will you choose and why?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 7.2","answer":"Because of security issues, I wouldn't choose wireless transmission. The offices themselves can each have an Ethernet-based LAN, and they can connect to each other and to an Intranet via a secure, encrypted VPN over the Internet. Network hardware anticipated is: coaxial cable, network server, a switch. Because the LANs will be connected through a VPN, a router may not be needed. In anticipation of the need for a lot of data transmission, the connection to the Internet will be through cable modems. A firewall, or several, for security purposes is anticipated."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"84","diff":"3","chapter":7,"ref":"249-250","question":"You have been hired by a small new Web design firm to set up a network for its single office location. The network is primarily needed for exchanging files, accessing and managing beta Web sites on their Web server, and connecting to the Internet. The firm hires many freelancers who come into the office on an ad-hoc basis and it does not have a lot of money to spend on infrastructure. What type of network will you recommend?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 7.2","answer":"I would recommend a mixed Ethernet and wireless network. The Ethernet LAN would connect the Web servers and primary workstations and connect via cable service to the Internet. Freelancers could connect wirelessly via access points."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"85","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"265-277","question":"What types of capabilities does the Internet provide businesses and what Internet protocols or technologies support these? Which have proven the most valuable to businesses thus far?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 7.3","answer":"The Internet provides ways to transfer files (FTP), work on remote computers (Telnet), distribute information in the form of pages (The Web), have real-time text-based conversations (instant messaging, chat), collaborate (wikis), communicate and share data with suppliers (extranets, Web-based applications), conduct group discussions (newsgroups), real-time voice conversations (chat, VOIP), send text messages (e-mail) and create lower cost networks (TCP/IP, extranets, intranets, VPN).\nProbably the two most important effects the Internet has had are the effects on network costs and ease of setting up a network using TCP/IP and Internet-based technologies, and e-mail, allowing near-instant documented messaging. E-mail has been a valuable alternative to post office mail."},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"7.3","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"267-270","question":"What are the business advantages of using voice over IP (VoIP) technology?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Business can lower costs by using the Internet to deliver voice information, avoiding the tolls charged by local and long-distance telephone networks. They can lower costs from not having to create a separate telephone network. VOIP enables communication by supporting Internet conference calls using video. VOIP also provides flexibility - phones can be added or moved to different offices without rewiring or reconfiguring the network."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"87","diff":"2","chapter":7,"ref":"263-264","question":"Describe and explain the idea of \"network neutrality.\" Are you in favor of network neutrality? Why or why not?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 7.3","answer":"Network neutrality describes the current equal access by users to Internet bandwidth, regardless of the services they are using on the Internet. Network neutrality is the idea that Internet service providers must allow customers equal access to content and applications, regardless of the source or nature of the content. Presently, the Internet is indeed neutral: all Internet traffic is treated equally on a first-come, first-serve basis by Internet backbone owners. The Internet is neutral because it was built on phone lines, which are subject to ‘common carriage' laws. These laws require phone companies to treat all calls and customers equally. For example, someone using the Internet to download large movie files pays the same rate as someone accessing their e-mail. Now telecommunications and cable companies want to be able to charge differentiated prices based on the amount of bandwidth consumed by content being delivered over the Internet. Student opinions will vary; one might be: I support network neutrality because the risk of censorship increases when network operators can selectively block or slow access to certain content."},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"7.3","diff":"2","number":"88","ref":"265-274","question":"Describe the current trends and movements in Internet technology and content.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"One upcoming change is the move to IPv6, a new addressing scheme that will allow for billions more addresses. Other technological changes are being worked on by Internet2 and Next-Generation Internet (NGI); consortia representing 200 universities, private businesses, and government agencies in the United States that are working on a new, robust, high-bandwidth version of the Internet. A current trend in Internet content is Web 2.0 Web 2.0, second- generation interactive Internet-based services that enable people to collaborate, share information, and create new services online like mashups, blogs, RSS, and wikis. With Web 2.0, the Web is not just a collection of destination sites but a source of data and services that can be combined to create applications users need. Web 2.0 software applications run on the Web itself instead of the desktop and bring the vision of Web-based computing closer to realization. Another potential change or trend in Internet content is the Web 3.0 or Semantic Web, a collaborative effort led by the World Wide Web Consortium to make Web searching more efficient by reducing the amount of human involvement in searching for and processing Web information. The Semantic Web is still in its infancy. Further development requires extensive work to establish specific meanings for data on the Web, categories for classifying the data, and relationships between classification categories. Once some of this work takes place, computers will be able to make more sense of the Web, intelligent agents will be capable of performing sophisticated search tasks, and data in Web pages will be able to be processed automatically. Another technological change can be seen in the way the Internet is being accessed. Mobile wireless broadband Internet access is the fastest-growing form of Internet access in 2008."},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"7.5","diff":"1","number":"89","ref":"283","question":"How are RFID systems used in inventory control and supply chain management?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"In inventory control and supply chain management, RFID systems capture and manage more detailed information about items in warehouses or in production than bar coding systems. If a large number of items are shipped together, RFID systems track each pallet, lot, or even unit item in the shipment. This technology may help companies improve receiving and storage operations by enhancing their ability to \"see\" exactly what stock is stored in warehouses or on retail store shelves."},{"chapter":7,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"7.5","diff":"1","number":"90","ref":"283-284","question":"What are wireless sensor networks? How do they work and what are they used for?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Wireless sensor networks (WSNs) are networks of interconnected wireless devices that are embedded into the physical environment to provide measurements of many points over large spaces. These devices have built-in processing, storage, and radio frequency sensors and antennas. They are linked into an interconnected network that routes the data they capture to a computer for analysis. These networks range from hundreds to thousands of nodes. Because wireless sensor devices are placed in the field for years at a time without any maintenance or human intervention, they must have very low power requirements and batteries capable of lasting for years. Wireless sensor networks are valuable in areas such as monitoring environmental changes; monitoring traffic or military activity; protecting property; efficiently operating and managing machinery and vehicles; establishing security perimeters; monitoring supply chain management; or detecting chemical, biological, or radiological material."},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"1","ref":"295","question":"The potential for unauthorized access is usually limited to the communications lines of a network.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"2","ref":"296","question":"Computers using cable modems to connect to the Internet are more open to penetration than those connecting via dial-up.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"3","ref":"297","question":"Wireless networks are vulnerable to penetration because radio frequency bands are easy to scan.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"4","diff":"3","chapter":8,"ref":"297","question":"The range of Wi-Fi networks can be extended up to two miles by using external antennae.","case":"Content Objective: 8.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"3","number":"5","ref":"300","question":"The WEP specification calls for an access point and its users to share the same 40-bit encrypted password.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"1","number":"6","ref":"300","question":"Viruses can be spread through e-mail.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":8,"ref":"300","question":"Computer worms spread much more rapidly than computer viruses.","case":"Content Objective: 8.1","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"8","ref":"302","question":"One form of spoofing involves forging the return address on an e-mail so that the e-mail message appears to come from someone other than the sender.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"9","ref":"302","question":"Sniffers enable hackers to steal proprietary information from anywhere on a network, including e-mail messages, company files, and confidential reports.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"10","ref":"302-303","question":"DoS attacks are used to destroy information and access restricted areas of a company's information system.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"11","diff":"3","chapter":8,"ref":"303","question":"The most economically damaging kinds of computer crime are e-mail viruses.","case":"Content Objective: 8.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"12","ref":"307","question":"Zero defects cannot be achieved in larger software programs because fully testing programs that contain thousands of choices and millions of paths would require thousands of years.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","diff":"2","number":"13","ref":"312","question":"An acceptable use policy defines the acceptable level of access to information assets for different users.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"1","number":"14","ref":"316","question":"Biometric authentication is the use of physical characteristics such as retinal images to provide identification.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"15","diff":"2","chapter":8,"ref":"318","question":"Packet filtering catches most types of network attacks.","case":"Content Objective: 8.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"2","number":"16","ref":"318","question":"NAT conceals the IP addresses of the organization's internal host computers to deter sniffer programs.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"17","diff":"2","chapter":8,"ref":"319","question":"SSL is a protocol used to establish a secure connection between two computers.","case":"Content Objective: 8.4","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"2","number":"18","ref":"320","question":"Public key encryption uses two keys.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":8,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"2","number":"19","ref":"321","question":"Fault-tolerant computers contain redundant hardware, software, and power supply components.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"2","chapter":8,"ref":"321","question":"High-availability computing is also referred to as fault tolerance.","case":"Content Objective: 8.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"\"Security\"","index":"A"},{"value":"\"Controls\"","index":"B"},{"value":"\"Benchmarking\"","index":"C"},{"value":"\"Algorithms\"","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"21","ref":"295","question":"________ refers to policies, procedures, and technical measures used to prevent unauthorized access, alternation, theft, or physical damage to information systems.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"\"Legacy systems\"","index":"A"},{"value":"\"SSID standards\"","index":"B"},{"value":"\"Vulnerabilities\"","index":"C"},{"value":"\"Controls\"","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"22","ref":"295","question":"________ refers to all of the methods, policies, and organizational procedures that ensure the safety of the organization's assets, the accuracy and reliability of its accounting records, and operational adherence to management standards.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"23","option":[{"value":"less vulnerable to damage","index":"A"},{"value":"more secure","index":"B"},{"value":"vulnerable to many more kinds of threats","index":"C"},{"value":"more critical to most businesses","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"295","question":"Large amounts of data stored in electronic form are ________ than the same data in manual form.","diff":"1","answer":"c"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"are usually bound up in legacy systems that are difficult to access and difficult to correct in case of error.","index":"A"},{"value":"are not secure because the technology to secure them did not exist at the time the files were created.","index":"B"},{"value":"have the potential to be accessed by large numbers of people and by groups outside of the organization.","index":"C"},{"value":"are frequently available on the Internet.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"24","ref":"295-296","question":"Electronic data are more susceptible to destruction, fraud, error, and misuse because information systems concentrate data in computer files that","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"25","option":[{"value":"tapping; sniffing; message alteration; radiation.","index":"A"},{"value":"hacking; vandalism; denial of service attacks.","index":"B"},{"value":"theft, copying, alteration of data; hardware or software failure.","index":"C"},{"value":"unauthorized access; errors; spyware.","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"295","question":"Specific security challenges that threaten the communications lines in a client/server environment include","diff":"3","answer":"a"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"26","option":[{"value":"tapping; sniffing; message alteration; radiation.","index":"A"},{"value":"hacking; vandalism; denial of service attacks.","index":"B"},{"value":"theft, copying, alteration of data; hardware or software failure.","index":"C"},{"value":"unauthorized access; errors; spyware.","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"295","question":"Specific security challenges that threaten clients in a client/server environment include","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"27","option":[{"value":"tapping; sniffing; message alteration; radiation.","index":"A"},{"value":"hacking; vandalism; denial of service attacks.","index":"B"},{"value":"theft, copying, alteration of data; hardware or software failure.","index":"C"},{"value":"unauthorized access; errors; spyware.","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"295","question":"Specific security challenges that threaten corporate servers in a client/server environment include","diff":"3","answer":"b"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"it was designed to be easily accessible.","index":"A"},{"value":"everyone uses the Internet.","index":"B"},{"value":"Internet standards are universal.","index":"C"},{"value":"it changes so rapidly.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"28","ref":"296","question":"The Internet poses specific security problems because","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"29","option":[{"value":"radiation.","index":"A"},{"value":"bandwidth theft.","index":"B"},{"value":"hackers.","index":"C"},{"value":"natural disasters, such as floods and fires.","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"296-297","question":"The main security problem on the Internet is","diff":"1","answer":"c"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"worm.","index":"A"},{"value":"Trojan horse.","index":"B"},{"value":"bug.","index":"C"},{"value":"pest.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"30","ref":"300","question":"An independent computer program that copies itself from one computer to another over a network is called a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"viruses that use Microsoft Outlook to spread to other systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"worms attached to e-mail that spread from computer to computer.","index":"B"},{"value":"multipartite viruses that can infect files as well as the boot sector of the hard drive.","index":"C"},{"value":"Trojan horses used to create bot nets.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"31","ref":"301","question":"Sobig.F and MyDoom.A are","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"32","option":[{"value":"Trojan horse","index":"A"},{"value":"virus","index":"B"},{"value":"worm","index":"C"},{"value":"spyware","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"301","question":"In 2004, ICQ users were enticed by a sales message from a supposed anti-virus vendor. On the vendor's site, a small program called Mitglieder was downloaded to the user's machine. The program enabled outsiders to infiltrate the user's machine. What type of malware is this an example of?","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"snooping.","index":"A"},{"value":"spoofing.","index":"B"},{"value":"sniffing.","index":"C"},{"value":"war driving.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"33","ref":"302","question":"Redirecting a Web link to a different address is a form of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"worm.","index":"A"},{"value":"Trojan horse.","index":"B"},{"value":"virus.","index":"C"},{"value":"spyware.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"34","ref":"302","question":"A key logger is a type of","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"by infecting Web search bots with malware","index":"A"},{"value":"by using Web search bots to infect other computers","index":"B"},{"value":"by causing other people's computers to become \"zombie\" PCs following a master computer","index":"C"},{"value":"by infecting corporate servers with \"zombie\" Trojan horses that allow undetected access through a back door","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"35","ref":"303","question":"How do hackers create a botnet?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"DDoS","index":"A"},{"value":"DoS","index":"B"},{"value":"pharming","index":"C"},{"value":"phishing","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"36","ref":"303","question":"Using numerous computers to inundate and overwhelm the network from numerous launch points is called a ________ attack.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"37","option":[{"value":"knowingly accessing a protected computer to commit fraud","index":"A"},{"value":"accessing a computer system without authority","index":"B"},{"value":"illegally accessing stored electronic communication","index":"C"},{"value":"threatening to cause damage to a protected computer","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"304","question":"Which of the following is NOT an example of a computer used as a target of crime?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"38","option":[{"value":"theft of trade secrets","index":"A"},{"value":"intentionally attempting to intercept electronic communication","index":"B"},{"value":"unauthorized copying of software","index":"C"},{"value":"breaching the confidentiality of protected computerized data","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"304","question":"Which of the following is NOT an example of a computer used as an instrument of crime?","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"spoofing.","index":"A"},{"value":"spinning.","index":"B"},{"value":"snooping.","index":"C"},{"value":"sniffing.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"39","ref":"304","question":"Phishing is a form of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"setting up bogus Wi-Fi hot spots.","index":"A"},{"value":"setting up fake Web sites to ask users for confidential information.","index":"B"},{"value":"pretending to be a legitimate business's representative in order to garner information about a security system.","index":"C"},{"value":"using e-mails for threats or harassment.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"40","ref":"304","question":"Phishing involves","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"Trojan horses that appears to the user to be a legitimate commercial software application.","index":"A"},{"value":"e-mail messages that mimic the e-mail messages of a legitimate business.","index":"B"},{"value":"fraudulent Web sites that mimic a legitimate business's Web site.","index":"C"},{"value":"bogus wireless networks that look legitimate to users.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"41","ref":"304","question":"Evil twins are","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"redirecting users to a fraudulent Web site even when the user has typed in the correct address in the Web browser.","index":"A"},{"value":"pretending to be a legitimate business's representative in order to garner information about a security system.","index":"B"},{"value":"setting up fake Web sites to ask users for confidential information.","index":"C"},{"value":"using e-mails for threats or harassment.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"42","ref":"305","question":"Pharming involves","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 8.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"43","option":[{"value":"wireless network","index":"A"},{"value":"employees","index":"B"},{"value":"authentication procedures","index":"C"},{"value":"lack of data encryption","index":"D"}],"chapter":8,"ref":"306","question":"You have been hired as a security consultant for a legal firm. Which of the following constitutes the greatest threat, in terms of security, to the firm?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"sniffing","index":"A"},{"value":"social engineering","index":"B"},{"value":"phishing","index":"C"},{"value":"pharming","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"44","ref":"306","question":"Tricking employees to reveal their passwords by pretending to be a legitimate member of a company is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","option":[{"value":"issue bug fixes","index":"A"},{"value":"issue patches","index":"B"},{"value":"re-release software","index":"C"},{"value":"issue updated versions","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"45","ref":"307","question":"How do software vendors correct flaws in their software after it has been distributed?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.2","option":[{"value":"requires financial institutions to ensure the security of customer data.","index":"A"},{"value":"specifies best practices in information systems security and control.","index":"B"},{"value":"imposes responsibility on companies and management to safeguard the accuracy of financial information.","index":"C"},{"value":"outlines medical security and privacy rules.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"46","ref":"308","question":"The HIPAA Act of 1997","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.2","option":[{"value":"requires financial institutions to ensure the security of customer data.","index":"A"},{"value":"specifies best practices in information systems security and control.","index":"B"},{"value":"imposes responsibility on companies and management to safeguard the accuracy of financial information.","index":"C"},{"value":"outlines medical security and privacy rules.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"47","ref":"309","question":"The Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.2","option":[{"value":"requires financial institutions to ensure the security of customer data.","index":"A"},{"value":"specifies best practices in information systems security and control.","index":"B"},{"value":"imposes responsibility on companies and management to safeguard the accuracy of financial information.","index":"C"},{"value":"outlines medical security and privacy rules.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"48","ref":"309","question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.2","option":[{"value":"voice-mail.","index":"A"},{"value":"spreadsheets.","index":"B"},{"value":"instant messages.","index":"C"},{"value":"e-mail.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"49","ref":"309","question":"The most common type of electronic evidence is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.2","option":[{"value":"defragmented","index":"A"},{"value":"ambient","index":"B"},{"value":"forensic","index":"C"},{"value":"recovery","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"50","ref":"310","question":"Electronic evidence on computer storage media that is not visible to the average user is called ________ data.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","option":[{"value":"can be classified as input controls, processing controls, and output controls.","index":"A"},{"value":"govern the design, security, and use of computer programs and the security of data files in general throughout the organization.","index":"B"},{"value":"apply to all computerized applications and consist of a combination of hardware, software, and manual procedures that create an overall control environment.","index":"C"},{"value":"include software controls, computer operations controls, and implementation controls.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"51","ref":"310","question":"Application controls","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","option":[{"value":"Software","index":"A"},{"value":"Administrative","index":"B"},{"value":"Data security","index":"C"},{"value":"Implementation","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"52","ref":"311","question":"________ controls ensure that valuable business data files on either disk or tape are not subject to unauthorized access, change, or destruction while they are in use or in storage.","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","option":[{"value":"security policy.","index":"A"},{"value":"AUP.","index":"B"},{"value":"risk assessment.","index":"C"},{"value":"business impact analysis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"53","ref":"311","question":"Analysis of an information system that rates the likelihood of a security incident occurring and its cost is included in a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","option":[{"value":"security policy.","index":"A"},{"value":"AUP.","index":"B"},{"value":"risk assessment.","index":"C"},{"value":"business impact analysis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"54","ref":"311","question":"Statements ranking information risks and identifying security goals are included in a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","option":[{"value":"security policy.","index":"A"},{"value":"AUP.","index":"B"},{"value":"risk assessment.","index":"C"},{"value":"business impact analysis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"55","ref":"314","question":"An analysis of the firm's most critical systems and the impact a system's outage would have on the business is included in a(n)","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"are one of the most effective security tools.","index":"A"},{"value":"may hinder employee productivity.","index":"B"},{"value":"are costly to implement.","index":"C"},{"value":"are often disregarded by employees.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"56","ref":"316","question":"Rigorous password systems","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"device the size of a credit card that contains access permission data.","index":"A"},{"value":"type of smart card.","index":"B"},{"value":"gadget that displays passcodes.","index":"C"},{"value":"electronic marker attached to a digital authorization file.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"57","ref":"316","question":"An authentication token is a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"is inexpensive.","index":"A"},{"value":"is used widely in Europe for security applications.","index":"B"},{"value":"can use a person's face as a unique, measurable trait.","index":"C"},{"value":"only uses physical traits as a measurement.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"58","ref":"316","question":"Biometric authentication","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"enforce a security policy on traffic between its network and the Internet.","index":"A"},{"value":"check the accuracy of all transactions between its network and the Internet.","index":"B"},{"value":"create an enterprise system on the Internet.","index":"C"},{"value":"check the content of all incoming and outgoing e-mail messages.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"59","ref":"317","question":"A firewall allows the organization to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"stateful inspection","index":"A"},{"value":"intrusion detection system","index":"B"},{"value":"application proxy filtering","index":"C"},{"value":"packet filtering","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"60","ref":"318","question":"In which technique are network communications are analyzed to see whether packets are part of an ongoing dialogue between a sender and a receiver?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"Stateful inspections","index":"A"},{"value":"Intrusion detection systems","index":"B"},{"value":"Application proxy filtering technologies","index":"C"},{"value":"Packet filtering technologies","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"61","ref":"318","question":"________ use scanning software to look for known problems such as bad passwords, the removal of important files, security attacks in progress, and system administration errors.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"TCP/IP and SSL.","index":"A"},{"value":"S-HTTP and CA.","index":"B"},{"value":"HTTP and TCP/IP.","index":"C"},{"value":"SSL, TLS, and S-HTTP.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"62","ref":"319","question":"Currently, the protocols used for secure information transfer over the Internet are","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"only those viruses active on the Internet and through e-mail.","index":"A"},{"value":"any virus.","index":"B"},{"value":"any virus except those in wireless communications applications.","index":"C"},{"value":"only those viruses already known when the software is written.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"63","ref":"319","question":"Most antivirus software is effective against","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"SSL","index":"A"},{"value":"symmetric key encryption","index":"B"},{"value":"public key encryption","index":"C"},{"value":"private key encryption","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"64","ref":"320","question":"In which method of encryption is a single encryption key sent to the receiver so both sender and receiver share the same key?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"uses third-party CAs to validate a user's identity.","index":"A"},{"value":"uses digital signatures to validate a user's identity.","index":"B"},{"value":"uses tokens to validate a user's identity.","index":"C"},{"value":"are used primarily by individuals for personal correspondence.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"65","ref":"320","question":"A digital certificate system","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"computer system is malfunctioning.","index":"A"},{"value":"computer system is not operational.","index":"B"},{"value":"corporation or organization is not operational.","index":"C"},{"value":"computer is not online.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"66","ref":"321","question":"Downtime refers to periods of time in which a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"more processing time.","index":"A"},{"value":"a large server network.","index":"B"},{"value":"fault-tolerant computer systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"dedicated phone lines.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"67","ref":"321","question":"Online transaction processing requires","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"high availability computing","index":"A"},{"value":"deep-packet inspection","index":"B"},{"value":"application proxy filtering","index":"C"},{"value":"stateful inspection","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"68","ref":"322","question":"In controlling network traffic to minimize slow-downs, a technology called ________ is used to examine data files and sort low-priority data from high-priority data.","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"high availability computing.","index":"A"},{"value":"recovery oriented computing.","index":"B"},{"value":"fault tolerant computing.","index":"C"},{"value":"disaster recovery planning.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"69","ref":"322","question":"The development and use of methods to make computer systems recover more quickly after mishaps is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","option":[{"value":"MISs","index":"A"},{"value":"CSOs","index":"B"},{"value":"MSSPs","index":"C"},{"value":"CAs","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"70","ref":"322","question":"Smaller firms can outsource security functions to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"71","ref":"297","question":"A practice in which eavesdroppers drive by buildings or park outside and try to intercept wireless network traffic is referred to as ________.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"war driving"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"1","number":"72","ref":"300","question":"Malicious software programs referred to as ________ include a variety of threats such as computer viruses, worms, and Trojan horses.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"malware"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.1","diff":"1","number":"73","ref":"304","question":"________ is a crime in which an imposter obtains key pieces of personal information to impersonate someone else.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Identity theft"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"309-310","question":"________ is the scientific collection, examination, authentication, preservation, and analysis of data held on or retrieved from computer storage media in such a way that the information can be used as evidence in a court of law.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Computer forensics"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","diff":"3","number":"75","ref":"310","question":"On the whole, ________ controls apply to all computerized applications and consist of a combination of hardware, software, and manual procedures that create an overall control environment.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"general"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.3","diff":"2","number":"76","ref":"314","question":"A(n) ________ examines the firm's overall security environment as well as the controls governing individual information systems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"MIS audit"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"3","number":"77","ref":"315","question":"________ consists of all the policies and procedures a company uses to prevent improper entry to systems by unauthorized insiders and outsiders.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Access control"},{"type":2,"question":"________ refers to the ability to know that a person is who he or she claims to be.\n￼￼CASE: Content Objective: 8.4","diff":"2","chapter":8,"ref":"316","number":"78","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Authentication"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"3","number":"79","ref":"319","question":"Comprehensive security management products, with tools for firewalls, VPNs, intrusion detection systems, and more, are called ________ systems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"unified threat management"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"8.4","diff":"1","number":"80","ref":"325","question":"When errors are discovered in software programs, the sources of the errors are found and eliminated through a process called ________.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"debugging"},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"8.1","diff":"2","number":"81","ref":"295-300","question":"Discuss the issue of security challenges on the Internet as that issue applies to a global enterprise. List at least five Internet security challenges.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Large public networks, including the Internet, are more vulnerable because they are virtually open to anyone and because they are so huge that when abuses do occur, they can have an enormously widespread impact. When the Internet becomes part of the corporate network, the organization's information systems can be vulnerable to actions from outsiders. Computers that are constantly connected to the Internet via cable modem or DSL line are more open to penetration by outsiders because they use a fixed Internet address where they can be more easily identified. The fixed Internet address creates the target for hackers. To benefit from electronic commerce, supply chain management, and other digital business processes, companies need to be open to outsiders such as customers, suppliers, and trading partners. Corporate systems must be extended outside the organization so that employees working with wireless and other mobile computing devices can access them. This requires a new security culture and infrastructure, allowing corporations to extend their security policies to include procedures for suppliers and other business partners."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"8.2","diff":"3","number":"82","ref":"295-325","question":"How can a firm's security policies contribute and relate to the six main business objectives? Give examples.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Operational excellence: Security policies are essential to operational excellence. A firm's daily transactions can be severely disrupted by cybercrime such as hackers. A firm's efficiency relies on accurate data. In addition, information assets have tremendous value, and the repercussions can be devastating if they are lost, destroyed, or placed in the wrong hands.\nNew products, services, business models. Security policies protect a company's ideas for new products and services, which could be stolen by competitors. Additionally, enhanced security could be seen by a customer as a way to differentiate your product.\nCustomer and supplier intimacy: Customers rely on your security if they enter personal data into your information system, for example, credit card information into your e-commerce site. The information you receive from customers and suppliers directly affects how able you are to customize your product, service, or communication with them.\nImproved decision making: Secure systems make data accuracy a priority, and good decision making relies on accurate and timely data. Lost and inaccurate data would lead to compromised decision making.\nCompetitive advantage: The knowledge that your firm has superior security than another would, on an otherwise level playing field, make your firm more attractive to do business with. Also, improved decision-making, new products and services, which are also affected by security (see above), will contribute to a firm's competitive advantage. Strong security and control also increase employee productivity and lower operational costs.\nSurvival: New laws and regulations make keeping your security system up-to-data a matter of survival. Inadequate security and control may result in serious legal liability. Firms have been destroyed by errors in security policies."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"83","diff":"2","chapter":8,"ref":"295-306","question":"Three major concerns of system builders and users are disaster, security, and human error. Of the three, which do you think is most difficult to deal with? Why?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 8.1","answer":"Disaster might be the most difficult because it is unexpected, broad-based, and frequently life threatening. In addition, the company cannot know if the disaster plan will work until a disaster occurs, and then it's too late to make corrections.\nSecurity might be the most difficult because it is an ongoing problem, new viruses are devised constantly, and hackers get smarter every day. Furthermore, damage done by a trusted employee from inside cannot be obviated by system security measures.\nHuman error might be most difficult because it isn't caught until too late, and the consequences may be disastrous. Also, administrative error can occur at any level and through any operation or procedure in the company."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"8.1","diff":"3","number":"84","ref":"297-300","question":"What are the security challenges faced by wireless networks?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Wireless networks are vulnerable because radio frequency bands are easy to scan. Both Bluetooth and Wi-Fi networks are susceptible to hacking by eavesdroppers. Local area networks (LANs) using the 802.11 standard can be easily penetrated by outsiders armed with laptops, wireless cards, external antennae, and hacking software. Hackers use these tools to detect unprotected networks, monitor network traffic, and, in some cases, gain access to the Internet or to corporate networks. Wi-Fi transmission technology was designed to make it easy for stations to find and hear one another. The service set identifiers (SSIDs) identifying the access points in a Wi-Fi network are broadcast multiple times and can be picked up fairly easily by intruders' sniffer programs. Wireless networks in many locations do not have basic protections against war driving, in which eavesdroppers drive by buildings or park outside and try to intercept wireless network traffic. A hacker can employ an 802.11 analysis tool to identify the SSID. An intruder that has associated with an access point by using the correct SSID is capable of accessing other resources on the network, using the Windows operating system to determine which other users are connected to the network, access their computer hard drives, and open or copy their files. Intruders also use the information they have gleaned to set up rogue access points on a different radio channel in physical locations close to users to force a user's radio NIC to associate with the rogue access point. Once this association occurs, hackers using the rogue access point can capture the names and passwords of unsuspecting users."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"8.3","diff":"2","number":"85","ref":"307, 325","question":"Why is software quality important to security. What specific steps can an organization take to ensure software quality?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Software errors pose a constant threat to information systems, causing untold losses in productivity. Growing complexity and size of software programs, coupled with demands for timely delivery to markets, have contributed to an increase in software flaws or vulnerabilities. A major problem with software is the presence of hidden bugs or program code defects. Studies have shown that it is virtually impossible to eliminate all bugs from large programs. Flaws in commercial software not only impede performance but also create security vulnerabilities that open networks to intruders. To correct software flaws once they are identified, the software vendor creates small pieces of software called patches to repair the flaws without disturbing the proper operation of the software. Organizations must maintain best efforts to both make sure purchased software is up to date and make sure their own software and programming is as bug- free as possible by employing software metrics and rigorous software testing. Ongoing use of metrics allows the information systems department and end users to jointly measure the performance of the system and identify problems as they occur. Examples of software metrics include the number of transactions that can be processed in a specified unit of time, online response time, the number of payroll checks printed per hour, and the number of known bugs per hundred lines of program code. For metrics to be successful, they must be carefully designed, formal, objective, and used consistently. Early, regular, and thorough testing will contribute significantly to system quality. Good testing begins before a software program is even written by using a walkthrough– a review of a specification or design document by a small group of people carefully selected based on the skills needed for the particular objectives being tested. Once developers start writing software programs, coding walkthroughs also can be used to review program code. However, code must be tested by computer runs. When errors are discovered, the source is found and eliminated through a process called debugging."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"8.4","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"310-322","question":"Hackers and their companion viruses are an increasing problem, especially on the Internet. What are the most important measurers for a firm to take to protect itself from this? Is full protection feasible? Why or why not?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"For protection, a company must institute good security measures, which will include firewalls, investigation of personnel to be hired, physical and software security and controls, antivirus software, and internal education measures. These measures are best put in place at the time the system is designed, and careful attention paid to them. A prudent company will engage in disaster protection measures, frequent updating of security software, and frequent auditing of all security measures and of all data upon which the company depends. Full protection may not be feasible in light of the time and expenses involved, but a risk analysis can provide insights into which areas are most important and vulnerable. These are the areas to protect first."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"8.3","diff":"3","number":"87","ref":"310-325","question":"You have just been hired as a security consultant by MegaMalls Inc., a national chain of retail malls, to make sure that the security of their information systems is up to par. Outline the steps you will take to achieve this.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"1. Establish what data and processes are important and essential to the company. Determine what external and internal information is essential to the different employee roles in the company.\n2. Conduct an MIS audit, a security audit, and create a risk assessment analysis\n3. Establish what legal/governmental/industry standards need to be adhered to and which\ninternational standards are relevant.\n4. Conduct a business impact analysis and determine a disaster recovery and business continuity plan.\n5. Create a security policy that defines an acceptable use policy, authorization policies and processes.\n6. Plan for any change management needed.\n7. Determine how the success of your policy will be measured and set up means for measuring\nthis.\n8. Implement such policies\n9. Measure and evaluate the effectiveness of the policy and make any additional adjustments."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"8.4","diff":"2","number":"88","ref":"320-321","question":"What is a digital certificate? How does it work?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Digital certificates are data files used to establish the identity of users and electronic assets for protection of online transactions. A digital certificate system uses a trusted third party, known as a certification authority, to validate a user's identity. The CA verifies a digital certificate user's identity offline. This information is put into a CA server, which generates an encrypted digital certificate containing owner identification information and a copy of the owner's public key. The certificate authenticates that the public key belongs to the designated owner. The CA makes its own public key available publicly either in print or perhaps on the Internet. The recipient of an encrypted message uses the CA's public key to decode the digital certificate attached to the message, verifies it was issued by the CA, and then obtains the sender's public key and identification information contained in the certificate. Using this information, the recipient can send an encrypted reply. The digital certificate system would enable, for example, a credit card user and a merchant to validate that their digital certificates were issued by an authorized and trusted third party before they exchange data. Public key infrastructure (PKI), the use of public key cryptography working with a certificate authority, is now widely used in e- commerce."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"8.4","diff":"2","number":"89","ref":"321-322","question":"Define a fault-tolerant computer system and a high-availability computer system. How do they differ? When would each be used?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Both systems use backup hardware resources. Fault-tolerant computer systems contain extra memory chips, processors, and disk storage devices that can back the system up and keep it running to prevent a system failure. High-availability computing places the emphasis on quick recovery from a system crash. A high-availability system includes redundant servers, mirroring, load balancing, clustering, storage area networks, and a good disaster recovery plan. The main difference between them is that fault-tolerant computer systems don't go down; high-availability computer systems go down, but can recover quickly.\nCompanies needing a technology platform with 100 percent, 24-hr system availability, use fault-tolerant computer systems. High-availability computing environments are a minimum requirement for firms with heavy electronic commerce processing or that depend on digital networks for their internal operations."},{"chapter":8,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"8.2","diff":"3","number":"90","ref":"295-325","question":"How is the security of a firm's information system and data affected by its people, organization, and technology? Is the contribution of one of these dimensions any more important than the other? Why?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"There are various technological essentials to protecting an information system: firewalls, authentication, encryption, anti-virus protection etc. Without technology implemented correctly, there is no security. A firm's employees are its greatest threat, in terms of embezzlement and insider fraud, errors, and lax enforcement of security policies. Probably the most important dimension is organization, because this is what determines a firm's business processes and policies. The firm's information policies can most enhance security by stressing intelligent design of security systems, appropriate use of security technology, the usability of its security processes."},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.1","diff":"2","number":"1","ref":"341","question":"Companies can use configuration tables provided by the enterprise software to tailor a particular aspect of the system to the way it does business","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.1","diff":"2","number":"2","ref":"341","question":"Enterprise systems use a client/server architecture and have not yet been redesigned to take advantage of the Web.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"3","diff":"1","chapter":9,"ref":"342","question":"Enterprise systems can improve management reporting and decision making.","case":"Content Objective: 9.1","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"4","ref":"343","question":"The upstream portion of the supply chain consists of the organizations and processes for distributing and delivering products to the final customers.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"5","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"344","question":"Supply chain inefficiencies can waste as much as 25 percent of a company's operating costs.","case":"Content Objective: 9.2","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"6","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"344","question":"Safety stock acts as an inexpensive buffer for the lack of flexibility in the supply chain.","case":"Content Objective: 9.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"7","ref":"344","question":"The bullwhip effect is the distortion of information about the demand for a product as it passes from one entity to the next across the supply chain.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"8","ref":"346","question":"Supply chain execution systems enable the firm to generate demand forecasts for a product and to develop sourcing and manufacturing plans for that product.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"9","ref":"348","question":"In the pre-Internet environment, supply chain coordination was hampered by the difficulties of making information flow smoothly among different internal supply chain processes.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"1","number":"10","ref":"349","question":"Intranets can be used to integrate information from isolated business processes within the firm to help them manage their internal supply chains.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"11","ref":"350","question":"In a push-based model, actual customer orders or purchases trigger events in the supply chain.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"12","ref":"350","question":"In a pull-based model, production master schedules are based on forecasts of demand for products.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"13","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"351","question":"Dell Inc. is an example of a push-based model.","case":"Content Objective: 9.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"14","ref":"351","question":"Total supply chain costs represent the majority of operating expenses for many businesses and in some industries approach 75 percent of the total operating budget.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"15","diff":"1","chapter":9,"ref":"354","question":"All CRM packages contain modules for PRM and ERM.","case":"Content Objective: 9.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","diff":"3","number":"16","ref":"354","question":"Major CRM application software vendors include Siebel Systems, PeopleSoft, SAP, and Salesforce.com.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"17","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"355","question":"Cross-selling markets complementary products to customers.","case":"Content Objective: 9.3","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","diff":"2","number":"18","ref":"357","question":"CRM software can help organizations identify high-value customers for preferential treatments.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":9,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","diff":"2","number":"19","ref":"359","question":"Analytical CRM uses a customer data warehouse and tools to analyze customer data collected from the firm's customer touch points and from other sources.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"360","question":"Enterprise systems require fundamental changes in the way the business operates.","case":"Content Objective: 9.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.1","option":[{"value":"customer and supplier intimacy","index":"A"},{"value":"new products, services, and business models","index":"B"},{"value":"improved decision making","index":"C"},{"value":"survival","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"21","ref":"337-338","question":"From your reading of the Tasty Baking Company case study, the firm implemented new information systems in order to achieve which of the main six business objectives?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.4","option":[{"value":"willingness to normalize data","index":"A"},{"value":"adopting many changes in their business processes","index":"B"},{"value":"limiting changes to the software","index":"C"},{"value":"enforcing strict project management standards","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"22","ref":"337","question":"From your reading of the Tasty Baking Company case study, what enabled the firm to take maximum advantage of the new enterprise software's capabilities?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.1","option":[{"value":"process management software.","index":"A"},{"value":"ERP systems.","index":"B"},{"value":"groupware.","index":"C"},{"value":"application software.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"23","ref":"339","question":"A suite of integrated software modules for finance and accounting, human resources, manufacturing and production, and sales and marketing that allows data to be used by multiple functions and business processes best describes","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.1","option":[{"value":"Process management","index":"A"},{"value":"PRM","index":"B"},{"value":"Enterprise","index":"C"},{"value":"CRM","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"24","ref":"340","question":"________ software is built around thousands of predefined business processes from all functional areas.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"9.1","option":[{"value":"Enterprise systems help firms respond rapidly to customer requests for information or products.","index":"A"},{"value":"Enterprise system data have standardized definitions and formats that are accepted by the entire organization.","index":"B"},{"value":"Enterprise software is expressly built to allow companies to mimic their unique business practices.","index":"C"},{"value":"Enterprise software includes analytical tools to evaluate overall organizational performance.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"25","ref":"341","question":"Which of the following is NOT true about enterprise systems?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"It does not speed product time to market.","index":"A"},{"value":"It is an inefficient use of raw materials.","index":"B"},{"value":"It increases sales costs.","index":"C"},{"value":"It increases inventory costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"26","ref":"344","question":"Why is overstocking warehouses not an effective solution for a problem of low availability?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 9.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"27","option":[{"value":"Select the functions of the system you wish to use.","index":"A"},{"value":"Select the business processes you wish to automate.","index":"B"},{"value":"Map the company's business processes to the software's business processes.","index":"C"},{"value":"Map the software's business processes to the company's business processes.","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"341","question":"You have been asked to implement enterprise software for a manufacturer of kitchen appliances. What is the first step you should take?","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.1","option":[{"value":"configuration tables.","index":"A"},{"value":"project workbooks.","index":"B"},{"value":"data dictionaries.","index":"C"},{"value":"middleware.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"28","ref":"341","question":"When tailoring a particular aspect of a system to the way a company does business, enterprise software can provide the company with","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 9.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"29","option":[{"value":"customizes the software to match all of its business processes.","index":"A"},{"value":"uses only the processes in the software that match its own processes.","index":"B"},{"value":"changes the way it works to match the software's business processes.","index":"C"},{"value":"selects only the software that best matches its existing business processes.","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"341","question":"In order to achieve maximum benefit from an enterprise software package, a business","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"affect both very small companies and large, global corporations.","index":"A"},{"value":"were difficult to address before the Internet.","index":"B"},{"value":"result when firms produce complex products and services.","index":"C"},{"value":"result when firms implement full-scale supply-chain management systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"30","ref":"342","question":"Supply chain complexity and scale","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"distribution channel.","index":"A"},{"value":"supply chain.","index":"B"},{"value":"value chain.","index":"C"},{"value":"marketing channel.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"31","ref":"342","question":"A network of organizations and business processes for procuring raw materials, transforming these materials into intermediate and finished products, and distributing the finished products to customers is called a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"upstream materials.","index":"A"},{"value":"raw materials.","index":"B"},{"value":"secondary products.","index":"C"},{"value":"intermediate products.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"32","ref":"343","question":"Components or parts of finished products are referred to as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"supplier's internal supply chain.","index":"A"},{"value":"external supply chain.","index":"B"},{"value":"upstream portion of the supply chain.","index":"C"},{"value":"downstream portion of the supply chain.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"33","ref":"343","question":"A company's suppliers, supplier's suppliers, and the processes for managing relationships with them is the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"supplier's internal supply chain.","index":"A"},{"value":"external supply chain.","index":"B"},{"value":"upstream portion of the supply chain.","index":"C"},{"value":"downstream portion of the supply chain.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"34","ref":"343","question":"A company's organizations and processes for distributing and delivering products to the final customers is the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"inaccurate or untimely information.","index":"A"},{"value":"poor integration between systems of suppliers, manufacturers, and distributors.","index":"B"},{"value":"inefficient or inaccurate MIS.","index":"C"},{"value":"unforeseeable events.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"35","ref":"344","question":"Uncertainties arise in any supply chain because of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"safety stock","index":"A"},{"value":"continuous replenishment","index":"B"},{"value":"just-in-time strategies","index":"C"},{"value":"demand planning","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"36","ref":"344","question":"Which of the following traditional solutions enables manufacturers to deal with uncertainties in the supply chain?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"just-in-time","index":"A"},{"value":"stockless","index":"B"},{"value":"bullwhip","index":"C"},{"value":"safety stock","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"37","ref":"344","question":"A scheduling system for minimizing inventory by having components arrive exactly at the moment they are needed and finished goods shipped as soon as they leave the assembly line best describes a ________ strategy.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"replenishment","index":"A"},{"value":"bullwhip","index":"B"},{"value":"ripple","index":"C"},{"value":"exponential","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"38","ref":"344","question":"A distortion of information about the demand for a product as it passes from one entity to the next across the supply chain is called the ________ effect.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"push; pull","index":"A"},{"value":"demand; continual","index":"B"},{"value":"upstream; downstream","index":"C"},{"value":"planning; execution","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"39","ref":"346","question":"Supply chain software can be classified as either supply chain ________ systems or supply chain ________ systems.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"demand","index":"A"},{"value":"delivery","index":"B"},{"value":"planning","index":"C"},{"value":"execution","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"40","ref":"346","question":"Systems that enable a firm to generate demand forecasts for a product and to develop sourcing and manufacturing plans for that product best describes supply chain ________ systems.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"track the physical status of goods.","index":"A"},{"value":"identify the transportation mode to use for product delivery.","index":"B"},{"value":"track the financial information involving all parties.","index":"C"},{"value":"track the status of orders.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"41","ref":"346","question":"Supply chain planning systems","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"distribution management","index":"A"},{"value":"replenishment planning","index":"B"},{"value":"demand planning","index":"C"},{"value":"order planning","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"42","ref":"346","question":"Which supply chain planning function determines how much product is needed to satisfy all customer demands?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"demand","index":"A"},{"value":"delivery","index":"B"},{"value":"planning","index":"C"},{"value":"execution","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"43","ref":"346","question":"Supply chain ________ systems manage the flow of products through distribution centers and warehouses to ensure that products are delivered to the right locations in the most efficient manner.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"transport operations.","index":"A"},{"value":"advanced scheduling and manufacturing planning.","index":"B"},{"value":"demand planning.","index":"C"},{"value":"order planning.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"44","ref":"346","question":"Capabilities of supply chain planning systems would NOT include","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 9.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"45","option":[{"value":"customer and supplier intimacy","index":"A"},{"value":"operational excellence","index":"B"},{"value":"improved decision making","index":"C"},{"value":"survival","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"347","question":"From your reading of the Procter & Gamble case study, the company implemented a multi- echelon inventory optimization system to achieve which of the main six business objectives?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"pull-based model","index":"A"},{"value":"build-to-stock","index":"B"},{"value":"push-based","index":"C"},{"value":"replenishment-driven","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"46","ref":"350","question":"A supply chain driven by actual customer orders or purchases follows a ________ model.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"supply-driven","index":"A"},{"value":"demand-driven","index":"B"},{"value":"replenishment-driven","index":"C"},{"value":"push-based","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"47","ref":"350","question":"A build-to-order supply-chain model is also called a ________ model.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","option":[{"value":"pull-based technology","index":"A"},{"value":"Internet technology","index":"B"},{"value":"supply chain management systems","index":"C"},{"value":"just-in-time supply-chain technologies","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"48","ref":"351","question":"Concurrent supply chains are made possible by which technology?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 9.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"49","option":[{"value":"improved customer service and responsiveness.","index":"A"},{"value":"cost reduction.","index":"B"},{"value":"reduced inventory levels.","index":"C"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"351","question":"Companies with effective supply chain management systems can expect","diff":"1","answer":"d"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"point of presence","index":"A"},{"value":"touch point","index":"B"},{"value":"sales point","index":"C"},{"value":"client channel","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"50","ref":"353","question":"A ________ is a method of interaction with a customer, such as telephone or customer service desk.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"e-mail","index":"A"},{"value":"Web site","index":"B"},{"value":"intranet","index":"C"},{"value":"retail store","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"51","ref":"353","question":"Which of the following would NOT be considered a contact point?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"SCM","index":"A"},{"value":"SFA","index":"B"},{"value":"ERM","index":"C"},{"value":"PRM","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"52","ref":"354","question":"________ modules use many of the same data, tools, and systems as CRM to enhance collaboration between a company and its selling partners.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"SCM","index":"A"},{"value":"SFA","index":"B"},{"value":"ERM","index":"C"},{"value":"PRM","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"53","ref":"354","question":"________ modules deal with issues such as setting objectives, employee performance management, and performance-based compensation.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"marketing.","index":"A"},{"value":"account management.","index":"B"},{"value":"advertising.","index":"C"},{"value":"public relations.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"54","ref":"354","question":"Customer relationship management systems typically provide software and online tools for sales, customer service, and","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Content Objective: 9.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"55","option":[{"value":"assigning and managing customer service requests.","index":"A"},{"value":"capturing prospect and customer data.","index":"B"},{"value":"identifying profitable and unprofitable customers.","index":"C"},{"value":"managing sales prospect and contact information.","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"354","question":"SFA modules in CRM systems would provide tools for","diff":"1","answer":"d"},{"case":"Content Objective: 9.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"56","option":[{"value":"assigning and managing customer service requests.","index":"A"},{"value":"sales quote generation.","index":"B"},{"value":"identifying profitable and unprofitable customers.","index":"C"},{"value":"managing sales prospect and contact information.","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"354","question":"Customer service modules in CRM systems provide tools for","diff":"1","answer":"a"},{"case":"Content Objective: 9.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"57","option":[{"value":"managing an advice telephone line.","index":"A"},{"value":"sales quote generation.","index":"B"},{"value":"identifying profitable and unprofitable customers.","index":"C"},{"value":"managing sales prospect and contact information.","index":"D"}],"chapter":9,"ref":"355","question":"Marketing modules in CRM systems would provide tools for","diff":"1","answer":"c"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"Enterprise","index":"A"},{"value":"ERM","index":"B"},{"value":"PRM","index":"C"},{"value":"ERP","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"58","ref":"354","question":"________ software deals with employee issues that are closely related to CRM, such as setting objectives, employee performance management, performance-based compensation, and employee training?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"operational CRM.","index":"A"},{"value":"direct marketing.","index":"B"},{"value":"cross-selling.","index":"C"},{"value":"cross-channel promotions.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"59","ref":"355","question":"Selling a customer with a checking account a home improvement loan is an example of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"returns management","index":"A"},{"value":"lead management","index":"B"},{"value":"account management","index":"C"},{"value":"events management","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"60","ref":"358","question":"Which of the following is an important capability for service processes that is found in most major CRM software products?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"returns management","index":"A"},{"value":"lead management","index":"B"},{"value":"channel promotions management","index":"C"},{"value":"events management","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"61","ref":"358","question":"Which of the following is an important capability for sales processes that is found in most major CRM software products?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"operational CRM","index":"A"},{"value":"analytical CRM","index":"B"},{"value":"SCM","index":"C"},{"value":"SFA","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"62","ref":"359","question":"Customer relationship management applications dealing with the analysis of customer data to provide information for improving business performance best describes ________ applications.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"include tools for marketing automation.","index":"A"},{"value":"provide consolidated data for operational CRM applications.","index":"B"},{"value":"are based on data warehouses consolidated from operational CRM applications.","index":"C"},{"value":"provide customer-facing applications.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"63","ref":"359","question":"Analytical CRM applications","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"identifying buying patterns.","index":"A"},{"value":"calculating CLTV.","index":"B"},{"value":"salesforce automation.","index":"C"},{"value":"pinpointing unprofitable customers.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"64","ref":"359","question":"Operational CRM applications include tools for","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"CLTV.","index":"A"},{"value":"analytical CRM.","index":"B"},{"value":"operational CRM.","index":"C"},{"value":"demand planning.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"65","ref":"359","question":"Analyzing sales representative and customer service representative productivity is an example of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"churn rate","index":"A"},{"value":"CLTV","index":"B"},{"value":"cost per lead","index":"C"},{"value":"cost per sale","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"66","ref":"359","question":"Which metric is based on the relationship between the revenue produced by a specific customer, the expenses incurred in acquiring and servicing that customer, and the expected life of the relationship between the customer and the company?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","option":[{"value":"switching costs.","index":"A"},{"value":"churn rate.","index":"B"},{"value":"CLTV.","index":"C"},{"value":"switch rate.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"67","ref":"360","question":"The measurement of the number of customers who stop using or purchasing products or services from a company is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.4","option":[{"value":"The total implementation cost of a large system might amount to four to five times the initial purchase price for the software.","index":"A"},{"value":"Enterprise applications introduce \"switching costs.\"","index":"B"},{"value":"Enterprise applications are based on organization-wide definitions of data.","index":"C"},{"value":"Enterprise applications are best implemented when few changes in business processes are required.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"68","ref":"360-361","question":"Which of the following statements about enterprise applications is NOT true?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.4","option":[{"value":"PRM software","index":"A"},{"value":"SFA software","index":"B"},{"value":"ERP suites","index":"C"},{"value":"Service platforms","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"69","ref":"362","question":"________ integrate(s) multiple applications from multiple business functions, business units, or business partners to deliver a seamless experience for the customer, employee, manager, or business partner and provide a greater degree of cross-functional integration than the traditional enterprise applications.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"9.5","option":[{"value":"e-business suites","index":"A"},{"value":"ERP systems","index":"B"},{"value":"middleware","index":"C"},{"value":"legacy systems","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"70","ref":"361","question":"Enterprise application vendors have created ________ to make their own customer relationship management, supply chain management, and enterprise systems work closely together with each other.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.1","diff":"2","number":"71","ref":"340-341","question":"________ consists of a set of interdependent software modules that support basic internal business processes for finance and accounting, human resources, manufacturing and production, and sales and marketing.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Enterprise software"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"1","number":"72","ref":"342","question":"The ________ is a network of organizations and business processes for procuring raw materials, transforming these materials into intermediate and finished products, and distributing the finished products to customers.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"supply chain"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"73","ref":"344","question":"In a(n) ________ strategy, components arrive exactly at the moment they are needed, and finished goods are shipped as they leave the assembly line.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"just-in-time"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"346","question":"________ is used to determine how much product a business needs to make to satisfy all of its customers' demands.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Demand planning"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"75","ref":"350","question":"With new flows of information made possible by Web-based tools, supply chain management can more easily follow a(n) ________ model.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"pull-based"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","diff":"2","number":"76","ref":"354","question":"________ modules in CRM systems help sales staff increase their productivity by focusing sales efforts on the most profitable customers, those who are good candidates for sales and services.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Sales force automation, SFA"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.3","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"359","question":"________ CRM includes customer-facing applications such as tools for sales force automation, call center and customer service support, and marketing automation.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Operational"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"78","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"355","question":"________ is the marketing of complementary products to customers.","case":"Content Objective: 9.3","answer":"Cross-selling"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.5","diff":"2","number":"79","ref":"362","question":"Enterprise-wide ________ provide a greater degree of cross-functional integration than the traditional enterprise applications.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"service platforms"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"9.5","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"363","question":"________ can integrate information from enterprise applications and disparate in-house legacy systems, presenting it to users through a Web interface so that the information appears to be coming from a single source.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Portal software"},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.1","diff":"2","number":"81","ref":"340-360","question":"Identify and describe three major enterprise applications.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Enterprise systems, customer relationship management, and supply chain management are three enterprise applications. Enterprise systems are based on a suite of integrated software modules and a common central database. Enterprise systems utilize enterprise software to support financial and accounting, human resources, manufacturing and production, and sales and marketing processes. Enterprise systems provide many benefits including an enterprise-enabled organization, improved management reporting and decision making, a unified information systems technology platform, and more efficient operations and customer-driven business processes.\nSupply chain management systems help an organization better manage its supply chain, including planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning items. Supply chain management software can be categorized as a supply chain planning system or as a supply chain execution system. A supply chain planning system enables a firm to generate demand forecasts for a product and to develop sourcing and manufacturing plans for that product. A supply chain execution system manages the flow of products through distribution centers and warehouses to ensure that products are delivered to the right locations in the most efficient manner. Supply chain management benefits include improved customer service and responsiveness, cost reduction, and cash utilization.\nCustomer relationship management systems help firms maximize the benefits of their customer assets. These systems capture and consolidate data from all over the organization and then distribute the results to various systems and customer touch points across the enterprise. Customer relationship management systems can be classified as operational or as analytical. Operational CRM refers to customer-facing applications, such as sales force automation, call center and customer service support, and marketing automation. Analytical CRM refers to customer relationship management applications dealing with the analysis of customer data to provide information for improving business performance. Benefits include increased customer satisfaction, reduced direct marketing costs, more effective marketing, and lower costs for customer acquisition and retention."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"9.1","diff":"2","number":"82","ref":"339-342, 360-361","question":"What are the benefits of enterprise systems? What are the challenges of enterprise systems?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Benefits include creating an enterprise-enabled organization, providing firmwide knowledge-based management processes, providing a unified information system technology platform and environment, and enabling more efficient operations and customer-driven business processes. Challenges include a daunting implementation process, surviving a cost-benefit analysis, inflexibility, and realizing strategic value."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"83","diff":"2","chapter":9,"ref":"346","question":"Identify two classifications for supply chain software. For each classification, identify five capabilities.","case":"Analysis Objective: 9.2","answer":"Supply chain planning systems and supply chain execution systems are two classifications for supply chain software. Supply chain planning systems enable a firm to generate demand forecasts for a product and develop sourcing and manufacturing plans for that product. Capabilities include order planning, advanced scheduling and manufacturing planning, demand planning, distribution planning, and transportation planning. Supply chain execution systems manage the flow of products through distribution centers and warehouses to ensure that products are delivered to the right locations. Capabilities include order commitments, final production, replenishment, distribution management, and reverse distribution."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.2","diff":"2","number":"84","ref":"348-350","question":"What additional complexities are faced in global supply chains? How does the Internet help in managing global supply chains?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Global supply chains typically span greater geographic distances and time differences than domestic supply chains and have participants from a number of different countries. Although the purchase price of many goods might be lower abroad, there are often additional costs for transportation, inventory, and local taxes or fees. Performance standards may vary from region to region or from nation to nation. Supply chain management may need to reflect foreign government regulations and cultural differences. All of these factors impact how a company takes orders, plans distribution, organizes warehousing, and manages inbound and outbound logistics throughout the global markets it services. The Internet helps companies manage many aspects of their global supply chains, including sourcing, transportation, communications, and international finance. As goods are being sourced, produced, and shipped, communication is required among retailers, manufacturers, contractors, agents, and logistics providers. Many, especially smaller companies, still share product information over the phone, via e-mail, or through faxes. These methods slow down the supply chain and also increase errors and uncertainty. With Internet technology, supply chain members communicate through a Web-based system. Firms use intranets to improve coordination among their internal supply chain processes, and they use extranets to coordinate supply chain processes shared with their business partners. Using intranets and extranets, all members of the supply chain are instantly able to communicate with each other, using up-to-date information to adjust purchasing, logistics, manufacturing, packaging, and schedules."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.2","diff":"1","number":"85","ref":"350-351","question":"Identify two supply chain models. Which is better?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Push-based and pull-based models were discussed in the textbook. Push-based refers to a supply chain driven by production master schedules based on forecasts or best guesses of demand for products. Pull-based refers to a supply chain driven by actual customer orders or purchases so that members of the supply chain produce and deliver only what customers have ordered. Pull-based models are better."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.3","diff":"1","number":"86","ref":"359","question":"Identify two types of customer relationships management applications.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Operational CRM and analytical CRM are two aspects. Operational CRM refers to customer-facing applications, such as sales force automation, call center and customer service support, and marketing automation. Analytical CRM refers to customer relationship management applications dealing with the analysis of customer data to provide information for improving business performance."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"9.3","diff":"2","number":"87","ref":"360","question":"Identify five benefits of customer relationship management systems.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Benefits include: better customer service, make call centers more efficient, cross-sell products more effectively, help sales staff close deals faster, simplify marketing and sales processes, acquire new profitable customers, sell additional products and services, provide customer information for developing new products, increase product utilization, reduce sales and marketing costs, identify and retain profitable customers, optimize service delivery costs, retain high-lifetime value customers, improve customer loyalty, improve response rates to direct mail, increase product profitability, respond quickly to market opportunities."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"9.4","diff":"3","number":"88","ref":"340-342, 360-361","question":"You have been hired by Santori, Inc., a small company that imports and distributes an Italian sparkling water. The company is interested in what benefits an enterprise system would bring. Would an enterprise system be appropriate for this company? What steps would you take in determining this?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"An enterprise system may be too expensive, although there are enterprise software packages that are available to smaller companies. A hosted enterprise application might be the most economical way to implement an enterprise system. To determine whether this would be beneficial to Santori, I would first look at their existing business processes. It would be ideal to determine if their efficiency meets benchmarks in their industry and allows them to be competitive with other businesses in their niche. Then I would review existing hosted applications to see how the applications business processes matched up with Santori's. It would be important to compare the costs of instituting new business processes with the benefits and cost-savings."},{"chapter":9,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"9.2","diff":"3","number":"89","ref":"342-352","question":"Plant Away is an Oregon-based retailer and distributor of trees and shrubs. They have hundreds of smaller nurseries based around the country that grow the plant stock. The majority of their business is conducted online: Consumers purchase typically small quantities of products online and Plant Away coordinates the shipping from the most appropriate nursery. What unique problems might you anticipate they have in their supply chain? What might remedy these problems?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Typical problems in supply chains arise from unforeseeable events. In a plant nursery, variations in the weather, growing season, plant diseases, crop output would be uncertainties. Other problems might be interstate regulations governing plants allowed in different states, and making sure plants survive and are healthy during transportation. It would be very important to have up-to-date forecasting of the weather or growing seasons that could anticipate possible problems, and analyze and determine the best transportation routes."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"90","diff":"3","chapter":9,"ref":"352-359","question":"You have been hired by Croydon Visiting Nurse Services, whose business processes are all manual, paper-based processes. How might a CRM system benefit them?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 9.3","answer":"A CRM system that includes patient's health records would allow any nurse to take over if another needed replacement. Assuming that the nurses had access via laptops or other PDAs to the system, a new nurse would have instant access to the patients needs. The CRM might also be able to record which types of treatments or products customers were most interested in or gave the greatest benefit to customers, and help anticipate needs. Additionally, with PRM capabilities, products needed by the nursing service would be more easily anticipated, ordered, and delivered. Since the employees work in the field, or away from a central office, Internet-based communications might provide tools for reviewing employee performance."},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"1","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"375","question":"E-commerce refers to the use of any networking technologies to transact business.","case":"Content Objective: 10.3","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"2","diff":"3","chapter":10,"ref":"375","question":"Retail consumer e-commerce is still growing at single-digit rates.","case":"Content Objective: 10.3","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"3","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"380","question":"The Internet shrinks information asymmetry.","case":"Content Objective: 10.1","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","diff":"1","number":"4","ref":"380","question":"Information asymmetry exists when one party in a transaction has more information for the transaction than the other party.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","diff":"2","number":"5","ref":"380","question":"All previous mass media in modern history, including the printing press, use a broadcast model where content is created in a central location by experts.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"6","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"383","question":"Disintermediation provides major benefits to the distributor.","case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.1","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"7","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"383","question":"In general, for digital goods, the marginal cost of producing another unit is about zero.","case":"Content Objective: 10.1","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","diff":"2","number":"8","ref":"385","question":"An information broker provides product, pricing, and availability information to individuals and businesses and generates revenue from advertising or from directing buyers to sellers.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","diff":"1","number":"9","ref":"386","question":"A banner ad opens a new window automatically and does not disappear until the user clicks on it.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"10","diff":"1","chapter":10,"ref":"387","question":"Podcasting allows subscribers to listen to live, streaming radio and other audio content.","case":"Analysis Objective: 10.2","answer":"false"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","diff":"2","number":"11","ref":"387","question":"An online syndicator aggregates content or applications from multiple sources, packaging them for distribution, and reselling them to third-party Web sites.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","diff":"1","number":"12","ref":"391","question":"Web sites can gather bountiful detailed information about customer behavior and demographics.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"13","diff":"1","chapter":10,"ref":"391","question":"Companies rarely use Web pages to analyze customer information.","case":"Content Objective: 10.1","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"14","diff":"3","chapter":10,"ref":"392","question":"Amazon.com uses Web personalization as a major marketing tool.","case":"Content Objective: 10.2","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.4","diff":"2","number":"15","ref":"394","question":"EDI standards that take advantage of network communications have yet to be fully implemented at the industry level.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"16","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"394","question":"Web sites cannot currently provide customers with call center interaction.","case":"Content Objective: 10.3","answer":"false"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","diff":"3","number":"17","ref":"396","question":"Some Net marketplaces support contractual purchasing based on long-term relationships with designated suppliers.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","diff":"3","number":"18","ref":"397","question":"Exchanges proliferated during the early years of e-commerce, but many have failed, in part because they encouraged competitive bidding that drove prices down.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"19","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"397","question":"Automobile manufacturing is an example of a vertical market.","case":"Analysis Objective: 10.3","answer":"true"},{"chapter":10,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"10.5","diff":"1","number":"20","ref":"399","question":"Accumulated balance digital payment systems allow consumers to make instant online payments to merchants and other individuals based on stored value in a digital account.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"online advertising sales","index":"A"},{"value":"internet portals","index":"B"},{"value":"online book sales","index":"C"},{"value":"Internet service providers","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"21","ref":"375","question":"Through what channel did e-commerce first evolve?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"have essentially stagnated.","index":"A"},{"value":"show signs of stabilizing.","index":"B"},{"value":"have returned to solid growth.","index":"C"},{"value":"have returned to exponential growth.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"22","ref":"376","question":"Since the dot-com bubble burst of 2001, e-commerce revenues:","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"still in a revolutionary phase.","index":"A"},{"value":"widely accepted by consumers, although technology is still quickly changing.","index":"B"},{"value":"not yet fully accepted by consumers, although much of its driving technology is firmly in place.","index":"C"},{"value":"well entrenched as a form of modern commerce.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"23","ref":"376","question":"Based on your reading of the chapter, e-commerce is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 10.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"24","option":[{"value":"the same set of standards being used across the globe.","index":"A"},{"value":"plentiful, cheap information.","index":"B"},{"value":"the enabling of commerce worldwide.","index":"C"},{"value":"the availability of Internet technology everywhere and anytime.","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"376","question":"The quality of ubiquity, as it relates to e-commerce, is illustrated by","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"exchange.","index":"A"},{"value":"marketspace.","index":"B"},{"value":"online marketplace.","index":"C"},{"value":"e-hub.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"25","ref":"376","question":"A marketplace extended beyond traditional boundaries and removed from a temporal and geographic location is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"intranets","index":"A"},{"value":"HTTP","index":"B"},{"value":".NET and Web services","index":"C"},{"value":"dropping of computing hardware prices","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"26","ref":"377","question":"Which development is helping expand B2B e-commerce opportunities?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 10.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"27","option":[{"value":"growth of wireless Internet connections","index":"A"},{"value":"online, interactive models for newspapers and other traditional media","index":"B"},{"value":"use of blogs as a commercial medium","index":"C"},{"value":"transformation of the music recording industry","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"377","question":"Which of the following is NOT a recent development in e-commerce?","diff":"3","answer":"d"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"Ties between customer and businesses are being rethought.","index":"A"},{"value":"Technology players such as Yahoo! seek to dominate online advertising.","index":"B"},{"value":"New methods of advertising, such as blog advertising, are emerging.","index":"C"},{"value":"The market entry costs for online advertising services are extremely low.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"28","ref":"377","question":"How is the Internet and e-commerce causing severe disruption to the existing advertising business model?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"information density","index":"A"},{"value":"transparency","index":"B"},{"value":"richness","index":"C"},{"value":"social technology","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"29","ref":"378","question":"Which of the following is NOT one of the unique features of e-commerce technology?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"ubiquity","index":"A"},{"value":"personalization/customization","index":"B"},{"value":"richness","index":"C"},{"value":"interactivity","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"30","ref":"379","question":"The act of engaging consumers in a dialog that dynamically adjusts the experience to the individual describes which dimension of e-commerce technology?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"ubiquity","index":"A"},{"value":"personalization/customization","index":"B"},{"value":"richness","index":"C"},{"value":"interactivity","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"31","ref":"378","question":"The integration of video, audio, and text marketing messages into a single marketing message and consumer experience describes which dimension of e-commerce technology?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"price discrimination.","index":"A"},{"value":"search costs.","index":"B"},{"value":"menu costs.","index":"C"},{"value":"transparency costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"32","ref":"378","question":"The effort required to locate a suitable product is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"information density","index":"A"},{"value":"richness","index":"B"},{"value":"customization","index":"C"},{"value":"interactivity","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"33","ref":"379","question":"The lowered costs of information storage, processing, and communication, along with the improvement of data quality has resulted in which unique quality of e-commerce?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"richnesscomplexity and contentof a message.","index":"A"},{"value":"total amount and quantity of information delivered to consumers by merchants.","index":"B"},{"value":"total amount and quantity of information available to all market participants.","index":"C"},{"value":"amount of information available to reduce price transparency.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"34","ref":"379","question":"Information density refers to the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"customization","index":"A"},{"value":"opacity","index":"B"},{"value":"gouging","index":"C"},{"value":"discrimination","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"35","ref":"379","question":"Selling the same goods to different targeted groups at different prices is called price ________.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"transparency","index":"A"},{"value":"asymmetry","index":"B"},{"value":"complexity","index":"C"},{"value":"imbalance","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"36","ref":"380","question":"Information ________ exists when one party in a transaction has more information that is important for the transaction than the other party.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"pricing","index":"A"},{"value":"dynamic pricing","index":"B"},{"value":"menu","index":"C"},{"value":"switching","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"37","ref":"380-382","question":"The cost to a merchant of changing the price of a product is called a ________ cost.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"menu","index":"A"},{"value":"flexible","index":"B"},{"value":"dynamic","index":"C"},{"value":"asymmetric","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"38","ref":"382","question":"Varying a product's price according to the supply situation of the seller is called ________ pricing.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"lower search costs.","index":"A"},{"value":"stronger network effects.","index":"B"},{"value":"higher delayed gratification effects.","index":"C"},{"value":"higher transaction costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"39","ref":"382","question":"Compared to digital markets, traditional markets have","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"disintermediation.","index":"A"},{"value":"BPR.","index":"B"},{"value":"market segmentation.","index":"C"},{"value":"network effects.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"40","ref":"383","question":"Reducing the business process layers in a distribution channel is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"produced digitally.","index":"A"},{"value":"sold over digital networks.","index":"B"},{"value":"delivered digitally.","index":"C"},{"value":"used with digital equipment.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"41","ref":"383","question":"Digital goods are goods that are","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"greater pricing flexibility.","index":"A"},{"value":"lower marketing costs.","index":"B"},{"value":"higher production costs.","index":"C"},{"value":"higher inventory costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"42","ref":"383","question":"Compared to traditional goods, digital goods have","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","option":[{"value":"lower distributed delivery costs.","index":"A"},{"value":"higher marginal costs per unit.","index":"B"},{"value":"equivalent copying costs.","index":"C"},{"value":"similar inventory costs.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"43","ref":"384","question":"Compared to traditional markets, digital markets have","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 10.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"44","option":[{"value":"information broker","index":"A"},{"value":"transaction broker","index":"B"},{"value":"online service provider","index":"C"},{"value":"virtual storefront","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"385","question":"Which of the following Internet business models does Amazon.com use?","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 10.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"45","option":[{"value":"Amazon.com","index":"A"},{"value":"eBay.com","index":"B"},{"value":"CNN.com","index":"C"},{"value":"Motocross.com","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"385","question":"Which of the following businesses utilizes the content provider Internet business model?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"generate revenue from advertising or from directing buyers to sellers.","index":"A"},{"value":"save users money and time by processing online sales dealings.","index":"B"},{"value":"provide a digital environment where buyers and sellers can establish prices for products.","index":"C"},{"value":"sell physical products directly to consumers or individual businesses.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"46","ref":"385","question":"Transaction brokers","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"save users money and time by processing online sales dealings.","index":"A"},{"value":"provide a digital environment where buyers and sellers can establish prices for products.","index":"B"},{"value":"create revenue by providing digital content over the Web.","index":"C"},{"value":"sell physical products directly to consumers or individual businesses.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"47","ref":"385","question":"Online marketplaces","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"pop-up ad","index":"A"},{"value":"controlled ad","index":"B"},{"value":"portal ad","index":"C"},{"value":"banner ad","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"48","ref":"386","question":"Which of the following is an ad that opens automatically and does not disappear until the user clicks on it?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"49","option":[{"value":"to bypass broadcast regulations for advertising to children","index":"A"},{"value":"to gather data on MySpace users linking to them","index":"B"},{"value":"to take advantage of free advertising","index":"C"},{"value":"to create personal relationships with consumers","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"386","question":"Why are companies interested in setting up MySpace profiles for their products?","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 10.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"50","option":[{"value":"service provider","index":"A"},{"value":"content provider","index":"B"},{"value":"portal","index":"C"},{"value":"social network","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"387","question":"Which Internet business model is Photobucket most closely aligned with?","diff":"3","answer":"a"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"portal.","index":"A"},{"value":"online syndicator.","index":"B"},{"value":"content provider.","index":"C"},{"value":"information broker.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"51","ref":"387","question":"A \"supersite\" that provides a comprehensive entry point for a huge array of Internet resources and services is called a(n):","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"10.2","option":[{"value":"are an example of business-to-business electronic commerce.","index":"A"},{"value":"do not sell a physical product.","index":"B"},{"value":"are extensions of traditional bricks-and-mortar businesses.","index":"C"},{"value":"did not have an earlier existing bricks-and-mortar business before they went to the Internet.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"52","ref":"387-388","question":"Pure-play businesses","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"a click-and-mortar business.","index":"A"},{"value":"C2C electronic commerce.","index":"B"},{"value":"B2C electronic commerce.","index":"C"},{"value":"an online exchange.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"53","ref":"388","question":"eBay is an example of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"B2B electronic commerce.","index":"A"},{"value":"C2C electronic commerce.","index":"B"},{"value":"M-commerce.","index":"C"},{"value":"B2C electronic commerce.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"54","ref":"388","question":"Businesses retailing products and services directly via the Internet to individual consumers best describes","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"disintermediation.","index":"A"},{"value":"C2C electronic commerce.","index":"B"},{"value":"M-commerce.","index":"C"},{"value":"B2C electronic commerce.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"55","ref":"388","question":"Consumers selling goods and services electronically to other consumers best describes:","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 10.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"56","option":[{"value":"virtual storefront","index":"A"},{"value":"exchange","index":"B"},{"value":"transaction broker","index":"C"},{"value":"online marketplace","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"389","question":"Which Internet business model is JR.com most closely aligned with?","diff":"1","answer":"a"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"clickstream tracking","index":"A"},{"value":"customer tracking","index":"B"},{"value":"collaborative filtering","index":"C"},{"value":"filtering","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"57","ref":"391","question":"Tools that record customer activities at Web sites and store them in a log for further analysis are called ________ tools.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"blogrolls.","index":"A"},{"value":"dated entries.","index":"B"},{"value":"trackbacks.","index":"C"},{"value":"twitters.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"58","ref":"392","question":"A blog is typically composed of a series of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"clickstream tracking","index":"A"},{"value":"customer tracking","index":"B"},{"value":"collaborative filtering","index":"C"},{"value":"filtering","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"59","ref":"392","question":"Tools that compare user behavior and interests to make purchasing recommendations to users are called ________ tools.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 10.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"60","option":[{"value":"low-cost leadership","index":"A"},{"value":"product differentiation","index":"B"},{"value":"focus on market niche","index":"C"},{"value":"strengthen customer and supplier intimacy","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"393","question":"What strategy was implemented by Stonyfield Farm in its use of blogs?","diff":"3","answer":"d"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"service center.","index":"A"},{"value":"customer support department.","index":"B"},{"value":"call center.","index":"C"},{"value":"sales department.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"61","ref":"394","question":"The organizational department responsible for handling customer service issues is the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"the use of Internet technologies for electronic data transactions.","index":"A"},{"value":"the exchange between two organizations of standard transactions through a network.","index":"B"},{"value":"electronic data invoicing.","index":"C"},{"value":"electronic delivery infrastructure.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"62","ref":"394","question":"EDI is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"procurement.","index":"A"},{"value":"e-procurement.","index":"B"},{"value":"supply chain management.","index":"C"},{"value":"electronic commerce.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"63","ref":"394-395","question":"The process of sourcing goods and materials, negotiating with suppliers, paying for goods, and making delivery arrangements is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"private industrial network.","index":"A"},{"value":"e-hub.","index":"B"},{"value":"marketspace.","index":"C"},{"value":"exchange.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"64","ref":"395","question":"An extranet that links a large firm to its suppliers and other key business partners is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"65","option":[{"value":"transaction-oriented","index":"A"},{"value":"collaborative","index":"B"},{"value":"independent","index":"C"},{"value":"supply-chain oriented","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"396","question":"E-hubs are more ________ than private industrial networks.","diff":"3","answer":"a"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"focus on continuous business process coordination between companies for supply chain management.","index":"A"},{"value":"are industry owned or operate as independent intermediaries between buyers and sellers.","index":"B"},{"value":"are geared towards short-term spot purchasing.","index":"C"},{"value":"are more relationship oriented than private industrial networks.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"66","ref":"396","question":"Net marketplaces","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.3","option":[{"value":"exchange.","index":"A"},{"value":"vertical market.","index":"B"},{"value":"private exchange.","index":"C"},{"value":"e-hub.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"67","ref":"397","question":"A third-party Net marketplace that connects many buyers and suppliers for spot purchasing is called a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"68","option":[{"value":"location-based services","index":"A"},{"value":"financial services","index":"B"},{"value":"games and entertainment","index":"C"},{"value":"e-books","index":"D"}],"chapter":10,"ref":"397-399","question":"Which of the following is NOT one of the categories of services that are popular for m- commerce?","diff":"1","answer":"d"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.4","option":[{"value":"has become widely adopted.","index":"A"},{"value":"is still in its infancy.","index":"B"},{"value":"represents a major fraction of total e-commerce transactions.","index":"C"},{"value":"is growing, due to the emergence of 2G networks","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"69","ref":"397","question":"In the United States, m-commerce","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"10.5","option":[{"value":"Use of mobile handsets as payment devices is already well established in Europe, Japan, and South Korea.","index":"A"},{"value":"The cell phone in the United States is not connected to a wide network of financial institutions.","index":"B"},{"value":"Japanese cell phones act like mobile wallets, containing a variety of payment mechanisms.","index":"C"},{"value":"The three kinds of mobile payments systems used in Japan are mobile credit cards, mobile debit cards, and digital wallets.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"70","ref":"400-401","question":"Which of the following statements about m-commerce payments is NOT true?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","diff":"2","number":"71","ref":"376","question":"The ubiquity of the Internet reduces the costs of participating in a market. These costs are called ________ costs.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"transaction"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.1","diff":"2","number":"72","ref":"379","question":"________ refers to the ability of consumers to discover what merchants actually pay for products.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Cost transparency"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"73","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"380","question":"________ are the merchants' costs of changing prices.","case":"Content Objective: 10.1","answer":"Menu costs"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"385","question":"A(n) ________ provides an online meeting place where people with similar interests can communicate and find useful information.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"social network"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.2","diff":"1","number":"75","ref":"388","question":"A(n) ________ business model has the Web site as an extension of a traditional bricks-and- mortar business.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"clicks-and-mortar"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"76","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"396","question":"A(n) ________ is another term for a private industrial network.","case":"Content Objective: 10.3","answer":"private exchange"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.5","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"399","question":"A(n) ________ stores credit card and owner identification information and provides these data automatically during electronic commerce purchase transactions.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"digital wallet"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.4","diff":"1","number":"78","ref":"399","question":"Wireless ________ feature content and services optimized for mobile devices to steer users to the information they are most likely to need.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"portals"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.5","diff":"2","number":"79","ref":"400","question":"A(n) ________ payment system enables a consumer to make instant online payments based on the amount of money they have in a digital account.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"stored value"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"10.5","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"400","question":"A(n) ________ system extends the functionality of existing checking accounts so they can be used for online shopping payments.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"digital checking"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"81","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"375-388","question":"What is the most profound way in which e-commerce and the Internet has changed the relationship between companies and their customers? Support your answer.","case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.1","answer":"Answers will vary, one answer is: The most profound way in which e-commerce and the Internet has changed this relationship is in the shrinking of information asymmetry. An information asymmetry exists when one party in a transaction has more information that is important for the transaction than the other party. That information helps determine their relative bargaining power. In digital markets, consumers and suppliers can \"see\" the prices being charged for goods, and in that sense digital markets are said to be more \"transparent\" than traditional markets. For example, until auto retailing sites appeared on the Web, there was a pronounced information asymmetry between auto dealers and customers. Only the auto dealers knew the manufacturers' prices, and it was difficult for consumers to shop around for the best price. Auto dealers' profit margins depended on this asymmetry of information. Today's consumers have access to a legion of Web sites providing competitive pricing information, and three-fourths of U.S. auto buyers use the Internet to shop around for the best deal. Thus, the Web has reduced the information asymmetry surrounding an auto purchase. The Internet has also helped businesses seeking to purchase from other businesses reduce information asymmetries and locate better prices and terms."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"82","diff":"1","chapter":10,"ref":"384-388","question":"List and describe at least five different Internet business models. Which of these models do you think is the most risky for a dot-com business? Support your answer.","case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.2","answer":"The eight models are: virtual storefront, information broker, transaction broker, online marketplace, content provider, online service provider, virtual community, and portal. The choice of riskiest model will depend on the individual student."},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"10.3","diff":"3","number":"83","ref":"375-388","question":"\"Knowledge increases exponentially\" is a phrase with which we are all familiar. How does this concept apply to electronic business and the emergence of the digital firm? Support your contentions.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Student answers will vary. One answer might be: The exponential increases of knowledge refer to shared information. For example, once the concept of a wheel is established, inheritors of that knowledge do not have to \"reinvent the wheel.\" The Internet is a tool similar to the wheel: it is based on shared standards and universal tools. The Internet and shared networking technologies are allowing new techniques for attracting customers and selling customers to be developed and adapted very quickly. For example, although early Internet retailers had difficulty setting up secure credit card transactions and payment systems, today there are many systems in place as vendors step in to create shared tools for doing this. The Internet is fostering shared knowledge and as such propagating ever greater increases in that knowledge."},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"10.1","diff":"2","number":"84","ref":"379-380, 391-392","question":"Describe the use of personalization in e-commerce. What business value does personalization have?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"E-commerce technologies permit personalization: Merchants can target their marketing messages to specific individuals by adjusting the message to a person's name, interests, and past purchases. The technology also permits customization–changing the delivered product or service based on a user's preferences or prior behavior. Given the interactive nature of e-commerce technology, a great deal of information about the consumer's past purchases and behavior can be stored and used by online merchants. The result is a level of personalization and customization unthinkable with traditional commerce technologies. For instance, you may be able to shape what you see on television by selecting a channel, but you cannot change the content of the channel you have chosen. In contrast, the Wall Street Journal Online allows you to select the type of news stories you want to see first and gives you the opportunity to be alerted when certain events happen. Customer information also enables firms to create unique personalized Web pages that display content or ads for products or services of special interest to each user, improving the customer's experience and creating additional value. By using personalization technology to modify the Web pages presented to each customer, marketers achieve the benefits of using individual salespeople at dramatically lower costs. One technique for Web personalization is collaborative filtering, which compares information gathered about a specific user's behavior at a Web site to data about other customers with similar interests to predict what the user would like to see next. The software then makes recommendations to users based on their assumed interests.\nThe business value of personalization is reduced marketing costs, as you spend only the money to target customers that are more likely to be receptive and are more profitable, and improved sales results, from increased customer response to personalized sites that better server their own purposes and shopping needs."},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"10.5","diff":"2","number":"85","ref":"399-400","question":"List and describe five ways in which the individual consumer may pay for purchases on the Internet.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The principal electronic payment systems for electronic commerce for the individual are credit card, digital wallet, accumulated balance digital payment systems, stored value systems, digital cash, peer-to-peer payment systems, and electronic checks. Most consumers use their credit card."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"86","diff":"2","chapter":10,"ref":"388","question":"List and describe the three major types of electronic commerce. Which do you think is ultimately the most valuable to the individual consumer? Support your answer.","case":"Evaluation Objective: 10.3","answer":"Business-to-consumer, business-to-business, and consumer-to-consumer. All three are valuable to the consumer, but in the long run, business-to-business may be the most valuable to the individual consumer because it will reduce prices and increase both goods and services. (Other opinions, of course, are supportable.)"},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"10.2","diff":"2","number":"87","ref":"385, 387","question":"What methods could a portal use to generate revenue? Which do you think might be most successful, and why?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Advertising, subscriptions, selling collected marketing information, and directing buyers to sellers could all generate revenue. I would think the most successful method would be through collecting marketing information, because as a portal that links to large amounts of external information and attracts repeat customers, the portal would have the opportunity to gather a lot of information about each user."},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"10.2","diff":"3","number":"88","ref":"384-397","question":"You are consulting for Lucky's, a chain of gas stations. What types of e-commerce opportunities, if any, are relevant to Lucky's? Could Lucky's make use of any Internet business models for this opportunity?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"In terms of B2B e-commerce, Lucky's might be able to procure goods over the Internet, use a private industrial network to coordinate their supply chain with suppliers and manage inventory. Depending on the structure of the gasoline retail business, industry net marketplaces and exchanges might be of use.\nIn terms of B2C e-commerce, there are not many opportunities, as it is inefficient to sell gasoline over the Internet. However, a mobile payment system, similar to Mobil's SpeedPass payment system, is a way of offering more convenient services to customers. Additionally, Lucky's could make sure that it's stations are listed in popular location-based mobile services that help drivers find nearby gas stations."},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"10.3","diff":"3","number":"89","ref":"384-387, 391-394","question":"You have been hired as a marketing consultant by a law firm in Los Angeles that specializes in juvenile justice. What ways can you use the Internet as a marketing tool and to advertise the firm's services?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"For market research, you could advertise on search engines. You could pay for marketing research at relevant portals. You could also collect customer information from the company's Web site. You could monitor relevant blogs to see what issues are of concern in juvenile justice, so as to address these concerns in your advertising campaigns.\nTo advertise, you could advertise on search engine results and at relevant portals or legal information content providers, using banner ad or popup ads. If it were feasible, you could create a juvenile justice portal and blog for the company in order to attract users whom you could gather market research as well as promote your services."},{"chapter":10,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"10.4","diff":"2","number":"90","ref":"397-399","question":"Describe four types of applications that are especially well-suited for m-commerce.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Types of applications include location-based services, banking and financial services, wireless advertising, and games and entertainment. Location-based services such as Mobio and Where enable users to locate nearby restaurants and gasoline stations, find local entertainment and movie times, and call a cab, providing maps showing how to reach their locations. New York-based MeetMoi provides a dating service that helps users identify people who are nearby and looking for dates. Banks are rolling out services that let customers manage their bank accounts from their cell phones or other mobile devices. Citibank and Bank of America customers can use their cell phones to check account balances, transfer funds, and pay bills. Cell phone service providers who have information valuable to advertisers about where subscribers live, their location the moment they view ads, their age, and the games, music, and other services they use on their phones. When done right, mobile campaigns yield high response rates and increased consumer engagement. Games and entertainment are another popular area, with music, digital games, ringtones, and even films designed for cell phone screens."},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","diff":"2","number":"1","ref":"414","question":"Knowledge residing in the minds of employees that has not been documented is called explicit knowledge.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","diff":"1","number":"2","ref":"414","question":"Knowledge can reside in e-mail, voice mail, graphics, and unstructured documents as well as structured documents.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"3","diff":"1","chapter":11,"ref":"414","question":"Knowledge is universally applicable and easily moved.","case":"Content Objective: 11.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","diff":"1","number":"4","ref":"417","question":"The chief knowledge officer is the organizational role responsible for the firm's knowledge management program.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","diff":"3","number":"5","ref":"417","question":"COPs are formalized groups of professionals and employees within and outside the firm who have similar work-related activities and interests.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"6","diff":"1","chapter":11,"ref":"419","question":"Structured knowledge is explicit knowledge that exists in informal documents.","case":"Content Objective: 11.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","diff":"2","number":"7","ref":"419","question":"Semistructured information is all the knowledge in a firm that resides in the heads of experienced employees.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","diff":"1","number":"8","ref":"424","question":"Knowledge workers are primarily clerical and data workers who usually do not possess high levels of education.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"9","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"427","question":"VRML requires the use of a powerful server as well as large amounts of bandwidth.","case":"Content Objective: 11.3","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"10","diff":"1","chapter":11,"ref":"428","question":"Expert systems are the primary tools used for knowledge discovery.","case":"Content Objective: 11.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"11","ref":"438","question":"Intelligent agents can discover underlying patterns, categories, and behaviors in large data sets.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"1","number":"12","ref":"428","question":"Expert systems capture the knowledge of skilled employees in the form of a set of rules in a software system that can be used by others in the organization.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"13","ref":"452","question":"Given their limitations, expert systems are seldom used for making discrete, highly structured decision-making situations.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"14","ref":"431","question":"Expert systems work by applying a set of AND/OR rules against a knowledge base, both of which are extracted from human experts.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"15","diff":"1","chapter":11,"ref":"431","question":"Case-based reasoning is not well-suited for diagnostic systems in medicine.","case":"Content Objective: 11.4","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"16","ref":"431","question":"Fuzzy logic can describe a particular phenomenon or process linguistically and then represent that description in a small number of flexible rules.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"17","ref":"431-433","question":"Fuzzy logic systems \"learn\" patterns from large quantities of data by sifting through data, searching for relationships, building models, and correcting over and over again the model's own mistakes.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"chapter":11,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"18","ref":"434","question":"Because neural network applications cannot always explain why they arrive at a particular solution, they are not well suited for use in the medical profession.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"19","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"437","question":"Intelligent agents are used primarily for specific, repetitive and predictable tasks.","case":"Content Objective: 11.4","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"20","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"438","question":"Shopping bots are a form of intelligent agent.","case":"Content Objective: 11.4","answer":"true"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"content management system","index":"A"},{"value":"digital asset management system","index":"B"},{"value":"learning management system","index":"C"},{"value":"knowledge network system","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"21","ref":"411-412","question":"What type of knowledge management system did Procter & Gamble implement in order to increase the efficiency of their research and development organization?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"20","index":"A"},{"value":"40","index":"B"},{"value":"60","index":"C"},{"value":"80","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"22","ref":"413","question":"The percentage of gross domestic product of the United States that is produced by the knowledge and information sectors is estimated to be about ________ percent.","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"23","option":[{"value":"Without knowledge, collaboration is difficult.","index":"A"},{"value":"Knowledge doesn't exist without collaboration.","index":"B"},{"value":"Knowledge is useful only when shared with others.","index":"C"},{"value":"As knowledge increases, so does collaboration.","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"413","question":"Which of the following statements best describes the relationship between collaboration and knowledge management?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"information.","index":"A"},{"value":"data.","index":"B"},{"value":"wisdom.","index":"C"},{"value":"knowledge.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"24","ref":"414","question":"The flow of events or transactions captured by an organization's system describes","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"wisdom.","index":"A"},{"value":"information.","index":"B"},{"value":"data.","index":"C"},{"value":"tacit knowledge.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"25","ref":"414","question":"Expertise and experience of organizational members that has not been formally documented best describes","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"change management.","index":"A"},{"value":"knowledge networking.","index":"B"},{"value":"the knowledge value chain.","index":"C"},{"value":"organizational learning.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"26","ref":"414-415","question":"Changing organizational behavior by sensing and responding to new experience and knowledge is called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"knowledge culture.","index":"A"},{"value":"knowledge discovery.","index":"B"},{"value":"organizational and management capital.","index":"C"},{"value":"organizational routine.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"27","ref":"415","question":"The set of business processes, culture, and behavior required to obtain value from investments in information systems is one type of","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"wikis","index":"A"},{"value":"CAD","index":"B"},{"value":"document management","index":"C"},{"value":"LMS","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"28","ref":"416","question":"Which of the following systems digitizes, indexes, and tags documents according to a coherent framework?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"29","option":[{"value":"Knowledge-based core competencies are key organizational assets.","index":"A"},{"value":"Knowledge should be seen as similar to any other key asset, such as a financial asset or a production facility.","index":"B"},{"value":"Knowledge enables firms to become more efficient in their use of scarce resources.","index":"C"},{"value":"Knowledge is not subject to the law of diminishing returns as are physical assets.","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"414-415","question":"Which of the following statements is NOT an accurate description of the importance of knowledge to a firm?","diff":"3","answer":"b"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"Knowledge is hard to move.","index":"A"},{"value":"Knowledge is universally applicable.","index":"B"},{"value":"Knowledge works only in certain situations.","index":"C"},{"value":"Knowledge is intangible.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"30","ref":"414-415","question":"What is meant by the statement \"knowledge is sticky\"?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","option":[{"value":"Knowledge is a firm asset.","index":"A"},{"value":"Knowledge has different forms.","index":"B"},{"value":"Knowledge has no locations.","index":"C"},{"value":"Knowledge is situational.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"31","ref":"414-415","question":"Which of the following is NOT one of the main four dimensions of knowledge described in the chapter?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"32","option":[{"value":"acquire, store, disseminate, apply, feedback","index":"A"},{"value":"data and information acquisition, acquire, store, disseminate, apply","index":"B"},{"value":"acquire, disseminate, apply, feedback, management and organizational activities","index":"C"},{"value":"data and information acquisition, store, disseminate, feedback, apply","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"416","question":"In order, which are the value-adding steps in the knowledge business value chain?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"practice.","index":"A"},{"value":"professionals.","index":"B"},{"value":"interest.","index":"C"},{"value":"knowledge.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"33","ref":"417","question":"Informal social networks of professionals and employees within and outside the firm who have similar work-related activities and interests are called communities of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"management information systems, decision support systems, and transaction processing systems","index":"A"},{"value":"enterprise systems, customer support systems, and supply chain management systems","index":"B"},{"value":"database management systems, expert systems, and knowledge work systems","index":"C"},{"value":"enterprise-wide knowledge management systems, knowledge work systems, and intelligent techniques","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"34","ref":"418","question":"Which of the following are the three major types of knowledge management systems?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"KWS.","index":"A"},{"value":"LMS.","index":"B"},{"value":"wikis.","index":"C"},{"value":"CAD systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"35","ref":"418","question":"Specialized systems built for engineers, scientists, and other knowledge workers charged with discovering and creating new knowledge for a company are called","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"data mining.","index":"A"},{"value":"neural network.","index":"B"},{"value":"intelligent technique.","index":"C"},{"value":"business intelligence.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"36","ref":"418","question":"Fuzzy logic is a type of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"37","option":[{"value":"collaboration tools","index":"A"},{"value":"KWS","index":"B"},{"value":"document management","index":"C"},{"value":"LMS","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"418","question":"Which of the following is NOT a typical component or capability of an enterprise-wide knowledge management system?","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"38","option":[{"value":"request for proposals","index":"A"},{"value":"voice-mail","index":"B"},{"value":"videos","index":"C"},{"value":"e-mail","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"419","question":"Which of the following would NOT considered semistructured knowledge?","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"enterprise content management system","index":"A"},{"value":"digital asset management system","index":"B"},{"value":"knowledge network system","index":"C"},{"value":"VRML system","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"39","ref":"420","question":"You are advising a multimedia company on the best type of knowledge management system to help them archive digital video and sound clips. Which of the following will suit their needs?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"tagged","index":"A"},{"value":"linked","index":"B"},{"value":"tupled","index":"C"},{"value":"referenced","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"40","ref":"420","question":"Once a knowledge taxonomy is developed, documents are all ________ with the proper classification.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"blogs","index":"A"},{"value":"intranets","index":"B"},{"value":"wikis","index":"C"},{"value":"social bookmarking","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"41","ref":"421-422","question":"Which of the following is NOT a Web 2.0 tool firms are using to foster collaboration?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 11.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"42","option":[{"value":"They are inexpensive and easy to implement.","index":"A"},{"value":"Users are able to modify wiki content contributed by others.","index":"B"},{"value":"They are most appropriate for information that must be revised but does not need to be available 24/7.","index":"C"},{"value":"They can be used as a central repository for all types of corporate data such as spreadsheets and e-mail.","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"422","question":"Which of the following statements about the use of wikis by firms is NOT true?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"blogs","index":"A"},{"value":"wikis","index":"B"},{"value":"social bookmarking","index":"C"},{"value":"all of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"43","ref":"422","question":"Which of the following is a collaboration tool used to support knowledge management systems?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","option":[{"value":"investment workstation.","index":"A"},{"value":"organizational learning system.","index":"B"},{"value":"employee enrichment system.","index":"C"},{"value":"learning management system.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"44","ref":"422","question":"Tools for the management, delivery, tracking, and assessment of various types of employee learning best describes a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"office systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"schools and universities.","index":"B"},{"value":"imaging systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"data transferring systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"45","ref":"425","question":"Most knowledge workers require specialized knowledge work systems, but they also rely on","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"careful filing system","index":"A"},{"value":"financial analysis system","index":"B"},{"value":"CAD capability","index":"C"},{"value":"user-friendly interface","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"46","ref":"425","question":"A ________ is very important to a knowledge worker's system.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"Graphics programs","index":"A"},{"value":"Knowledge workstations","index":"B"},{"value":"Virtual simulators","index":"C"},{"value":"CAD stations","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"47","ref":"425","question":"________ often are designed and optimized for the specific tasks to be performed.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"provide engineers, designers, and factory managers with precise control over industrial design and manufacturing.","index":"A"},{"value":"provide an important source of expertise for organizations.","index":"B"},{"value":"allow groups to work together on documents.","index":"C"},{"value":"are high-end PCs used in the financial sector to analyze trading situations instantaneously and facilitate portfolio management.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"48","ref":"426","question":"CAD workstations","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"computer-aided design system","index":"A"},{"value":"3D visualization system","index":"B"},{"value":"investment workstations","index":"C"},{"value":"expert system","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"49","ref":"426-427","question":"Which of the following would NOT be classified as a knowledge work system?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"provide engineers, designers, and factory managers with precise control over industrial design and manufacturing.","index":"A"},{"value":"provide an important source of expertise for organizations.","index":"B"},{"value":"allow groups to work together on documents.","index":"C"},{"value":"provide architects, engineers, and medical workers with precise, photorealistic simulations of objects.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"50","ref":"427","question":"Virtual reality systems","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"provide engineers, designers, and factory managers with precise control over industrial design and manufacturing.","index":"A"},{"value":"provide an important source of expertise for organizations.","index":"B"},{"value":"allow groups to work together on documents.","index":"C"},{"value":"are used in the financial sector to analyze trading situations instantaneously and facilitate portfolio management.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"51","ref":"427","question":"Investment workstations","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","option":[{"value":"expert system","index":"A"},{"value":"case-based reasoning","index":"B"},{"value":"fuzzy logic","index":"C"},{"value":"neural network","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"52","ref":"427","question":"Which of the following systems is NOT used to capture tacit knowledge?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"knowledge networks","index":"A"},{"value":"case based reasoning","index":"B"},{"value":"computer-aided design","index":"C"},{"value":"VRML","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"53","ref":"427-428","question":"Which of the following is a type of intelligent technique?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"expert system","index":"A"},{"value":"transaction processing systems","index":"B"},{"value":"case-based reasoning","index":"C"},{"value":"data mining","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"54","ref":"428","question":"Which of the following techniques is used for knowledge discovery?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"fuzzy logic.","index":"A"},{"value":"neural networks.","index":"B"},{"value":"AI technology.","index":"C"},{"value":"genetic algorithms.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"55","ref":"428","question":"Technology that consists of computer-based systems that attempt to emulate human behavior is called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"a strategy for searching the rule base in case-based reasoning.","index":"A"},{"value":"the programming environment of an expert system.","index":"B"},{"value":"a method of organizing expert system knowledge into chunks.","index":"C"},{"value":"a strategy used to search through the rule base in an expert system by forward chaining or backward chaining.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"56","ref":"428","question":"An inference engine is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"a strategy for searching the rule base in an expert system that begins with information entered by the user.","index":"A"},{"value":"the programming environment of an expert system.","index":"B"},{"value":"a method of organizing expert system knowledge into chunks.","index":"C"},{"value":"a strategy for searching the rule base in an expert system that begins with a hypothesis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"57","ref":"428","question":"Forward chaining is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"a strategy for searching the rule base in an expert system that begins with information entered by the user.","index":"A"},{"value":"the programming environment of an expert system.","index":"B"},{"value":"a method of organizing expert system knowledge into chunks.","index":"C"},{"value":"a strategy for searching the rule base in an expert system that begins with a hypothesis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"58","ref":"452","question":"Backward chaining is","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"2.1","option":[{"value":"solve problems too difficult for human experts.","index":"A"},{"value":"are based on DO WHILE rules.","index":"B"},{"value":"work in very limited domains.","index":"C"},{"value":"share characteristics with mainframe computing.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"59","ref":"431","question":"Expert systems","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"60","option":[{"value":"there is no one expert who understands all the material contained within the encyclopedia.","index":"A"},{"value":"the knowledge changes radically over a short time.","index":"B"},{"value":"not all the knowledge in the encyclopedia can be represented in the form of IF-THEN rules.","index":"C"},{"value":"the knowledge is too general.","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"431","question":"It is unlikely you could represent the knowledge in the Encyclopedia Britannica with an expert system because:","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"policy development.","index":"A"},{"value":"classification.","index":"B"},{"value":"logic and control.","index":"C"},{"value":"high complexity.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"61","ref":"431","question":"Virtually all expert systems deal with problems of","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 11.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"62","option":[{"value":"their rule base is so complex.","index":"A"},{"value":"they rely on equipment that becomes outdated.","index":"B"},{"value":"their rules must be reprogrammed every time there is a change in the environment, which in turn may change the applicable rules.","index":"C"},{"value":"only the person who created the system knows exactly how it works, and may not be available when changes are needed.","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"431","question":"Expert systems are expensive and time-consuming to maintain because","diff":"3","answer":"c"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"CBR","index":"A"},{"value":"fuzzy logic","index":"B"},{"value":"data mining","index":"C"},{"value":"LMS","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"63","ref":"431","question":"In this technique, descriptions of past experiences of human specialists are stored in a database for later retrieval when the user encounters a situation with similar characteristics.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Evaluation Objective: 11.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"64","option":[{"value":"case-based reasoning.","index":"A"},{"value":"artificial intelligence.","index":"B"},{"value":"fuzzy logic.","index":"C"},{"value":"expert system.","index":"D"}],"chapter":11,"ref":"432-433","question":"You are an automotive engineer working on an application that will automatically parallel park a car. The intelligent technique you may find most useful is:","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"a neural network.","index":"A"},{"value":"an expert system.","index":"B"},{"value":"case-based reasoning.","index":"C"},{"value":"fuzzy logic.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"65","ref":"433","question":"Hardware and software that attempts to emulate the processing patterns of the biological brain best describes","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"develop solutions to particular problems using fitness, crossover, and mutation.","index":"A"},{"value":"represent knowledge as groups of characteristics.","index":"B"},{"value":"do not work for most problems.","index":"C"},{"value":"are based on logic.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"66","ref":"436","question":"Genetic algorithms","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"Genetic algorithms are designed to process large amounts of information.","index":"A"},{"value":"Genetic algorithms are a type of knowledge discovery, while neural networks are an intelligent technique.","index":"B"},{"value":"Neural networks are programmed to \"learn.\"","index":"C"},{"value":"All of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"67","ref":"433-437","question":"Which of the following describes a difference between neural networks and genetic algorithms?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"intelligent agents.","index":"A"},{"value":"intelligent techniques.","index":"B"},{"value":"business intelligence.","index":"C"},{"value":"AI hybrid systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"68","ref":"437","question":"Software programs that work in the background without direct human intervention to carry out specific, repetitive, and predictable tasks for individual users, business processes, or software applications, are called","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"fuzzy logic","index":"A"},{"value":"intelligent agents","index":"B"},{"value":"genetic algorithms","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"69","ref":"438","question":"What type of intelligent technique helped Procter & Gamble determine the most efficient methods for their trucks to deliver goods?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.4","option":[{"value":"CAD systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"virtual reality systems.","index":"B"},{"value":"fuzzy logic systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"intelligent agents.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"70","ref":"437-439","question":"To automate routine tasks to help firms search for and filter information for use in electronic commerce and supply chain management a firm would most likely use","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","diff":"1","number":"71","ref":"414","question":"________ is thought to be the collective and individual experience of applying knowledge to the solution of problems.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Wisdom"},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"11.1","diff":"1","number":"72","ref":"419","question":"________ is explicit knowledge that exists in formal documents, as well as in formal rules that organizations derive by observing experts and their decision-making behaviors.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"Structured knowledge"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"73","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"420","question":"________ are also known as expertise location and management systems.","case":"Content Objective: 11.2","answer":"Knowledge network systems"},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","diff":"2","number":"74","ref":"420","question":"A(n) ________ is a scheme for classifying information and knowledge in such a way that it can be easily accessed.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"taxonomy"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"75","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"422","question":"The user-created taxonomies created for shared bookmarks are called ________.","case":"Content Objective: 11.2","answer":"folksonomies"},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"11.2","diff":"2","number":"76","ref":"422","question":"A(n) ________ provides tools for the management, delivery, tracking, and assessment of various types of employee learning and training.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"learning management system, LMS"},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"11.3","diff":"1","number":"77","ref":"426","question":"________ automates the creation and revision of designs, using computers and sophisticated graphics software.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Computer aided design, CAD"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"78","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"428","question":"The model of human knowledge used by expert systems is called the ________.","case":"Content Objective: 11.4","answer":"knowledge base"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"79","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"428","question":"The strategy used to search through the rule base is called the ________.","case":"Content Objective: 11.4","answer":"inference engine"},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"11.4","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"437","question":"Systems that integrate genetic algorithms, fuzzy logic, neural networks, and expert systems are called ________ systems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"hybrid AI"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"81","diff":"1","chapter":11,"ref":"413-414","question":"What is knowledge management? What types of knowledge might a company such as a taxi service have, and could a taxi service benefit from knowledge management?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 11.1","answer":"Knowledge management is the set of processes developed in an organization to create, gather, store, disseminate, and apply the firm's knowledge. A taxi company's knowledge might include explicit knowledge, such as maps and routes between destinations. Tacit knowledge would include the experience of drivers, such as the best alternate routes between destinations or passenger needs. A taxi service might benefit from a system that gave drivers guides on routes that included alternate routes drivers had found. It might benefit from a learning management system that trained drivers for locations, destinations, and alternate routes."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"11.1","diff":"2","number":"82","ref":"415-418","question":"Briefly outline the knowledge management chain as it might apply to the online catalog system of a public library.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Steps in the knowledge management chain include:\nAcquisition: for an online catalog of a library this would be getting the book data into digital\nformat.\nStorage: This would involve the systems for storing this data, perhaps a central server. Dissemination: The library would need to determine how the card catalog information is\naccessed by the public or by staff.\nApplication: This would involve the card catalog becoming part of the library's business\nprocesses: for example, the card catalog would be linked to a system of borrowing, so that users would know from the card catalog whether a book was out on loan.\nManagement and organizational activities: This would entail using the system with a card catalog base for other services, perhaps linking up to a wider library system to share resources, information, or book loaning between systems."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.2","diff":"1","number":"83","ref":"418-439","question":"Identify the three major types of knowledge management systems. Provide two examples of each.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The major types of knowledge management systems are enterprise knowledge management systems, knowledge work systems, and intelligent techniques.\nEnterprise knowledge management systems include: enterprise content management systems, digital asset management systems, learning management systems, and knowledge networks. Knowledge work systems include: Computer-aided design systems, virtual reality systems, and financial investment workstations. Intelligent techniques include: Data mining, expert systems, case-based reasoning, fuzzy logic, neural networks, genetic algorithms, hybrid AI systems, and intelligent agents."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.2","diff":"2","number":"84","ref":"420-422","question":"How can knowledge be gathered from the personal and undocumented expertise of professionals within a firm? List at least four ways to gather and disseminate such knowledge.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The expertise and experience of firm employees can be gathered by documenting their experience through documenting best practices and frequently asked questions. You can also develop a referral system by providing a way for employees to find a company expert for the solution they are looking for. There is commercially available software for enterprise-wide knowledge network system, but other tools you can use include best-practices documents, FAQs, social bookmarking, collaboration tools, wikis, and blogs for helping gather and disseminate tacit knowledge."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"85","diff":"2","chapter":11,"ref":"424-425","question":"Why are knowledge workers so important to the digital firm? What are their functions and which of these do you feel is most critical to the success of the firm? Why?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 11.2","answer":"Student answers will vary, but should include an understanding of the three main functions of knowledge workers. An example answer is: Knowledge workers create new products or find ways to improve existing ones. Without them, the firm would stagnate and become less competitive in an environment that is always changing and is increasingly more competitive. In the modern economy, knowledge is truly power. The three major functions of knowledge workers are: keeping the organization up-to-date in knowledge as it develops in the external world; serving as internal consultants regarding their areas of knowledge and its opportunities; and acting as change agents as they evaluate, initiate, and promote new projects. The most important of these is to develop new knowledge as it applies to the making of products or services, as offering products and services is the mainstay of the corporation."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.3","diff":"2","number":"86","ref":"425","question":"Identify three important qualities or capabilities of knowledge work systems.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Knowledge work systems must give knowledge workers the specialized tools they need, such as powerful graphics, analytical tools, and communications and document- management tools. Knowledge work systems must provide a user-friendly interface to the KWS. These user-friendly interfaces save time by allowing the user to perform needed tasks and get to required information without having to spend a lot of time learning to use the computer. Knowledge work systems must be carefully designed to optimize the performance of the specific tasks of the pertinent knowledge worker."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"11.3","diff":"2","number":"87","ref":"426-427","question":"Discuss the concept of virtual reality, especially with regard to VRML and its applications in the business arena.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Virtual reality systems use interactive graphics software and hardware to create the illusion of reality in cyberspace. The original applications were in gaming, but new uses in education, science, and business are being developed and have great promise. Virtual reality applications are being developed for the Web using a standard called Virtual Reality Modeling Language (VRML), which can organize multiple media types to put users in a simulated real- world environment. VRML is platform independent, operates over a desktop computer, and requires little bandwidth. DuPont's HyperPlant is an example of a business application. HyperPlant allows users to go through three-dimensional models as if they were physically walking through a plant, which reduces errors during the construction of manufacturing structures."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"11.4","diff":"3","number":"88","ref":"431-437","question":"What is the difference between a neural network, fuzzy logic, and genetic algorithms? Which would be most useful to an organization of astronomers analyzing gamma ray emissions reaching Earth?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"A neural network attempts to emulate the processing patterns of the biological brain. The results are a program that can \"learn\" by comparing solutions to known problems to sets of data presented to it. Neural networks are used for solving complex, poorly understood problems for which large amounts of data have been collected. Fuzzy logic creates rules that use approximate or subjective values. It describes a particular phenomenon or process linguistically and then represents that logic in a small number of flexible rules. Genetic algorithms are problem-solving methods that use the model of living organisms adapting to their environment. Possible solutions are evaluated, the \"best\" choices are made, then more possible solutions are created by combining the factors involved in those first \"best\" choices, and choosing again. The process continues until an optimum solution is reached. These genetic algorithms are useful for finding the optimal solution for a specific problem by examining a very large number of alternative solutions for that problem. Student evaluations will vary. One answer is: I think a neural network would be of most use, because of its ability to analyze large amounts of data and find hidden relationships."},{"chapter":11,"type":2,"objective":"11.1","aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"89","ref":"413-428","question":"What do you see as the challenges in setting up a knowledge management system?","case":"Evaluation","answer":"Determining what knowledge will be the most effective or offer the most benefits to the company; defining taxonomies, gathering accurate knowledge, quantifying the system's success, change management and implementing business processes that incorporate the system. Diff: 3"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"90","diff":"3","chapter":11,"ref":"417-439","question":"You have been hired by a small architectural firm interested in implementing a knowledge management system. What features do you think would be of most benefit to them?","case":"Evaluation Objective: 11.2","answer":"Student answers will vary. The ability to store structured documents, such as plans, blueprints; collaboration tools, the ability to reference up-to-date local or national building codes, a system for storing case studies, best practices, and corporate standards. Also of importance is a knowledge work system or CAD to aid in engineering and design."},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"1","number":"1","ref":"452","question":"Unstructured decisions are novel and nonroutine, and there is no well-understood or agreed-on procedure for making them.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"1","number":"2","ref":"452","question":"A structured decision can be made by following a well-defined set of procedures. No \"feel\" or intuition is necessary.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"2","number":"3","ref":"452","question":"Middle management tends to face more unstructured decision scenarios, but may include some structured components.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"4","diff":"1","chapter":12,"ref":"453","question":"Unstructured decision making is most prevalent at lower organizational levels.","case":"Content Objective: 12.1","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"5","diff":"1","chapter":12,"ref":"453","question":"Rank-and-file employees tend to make more structured decisions.","case":"Content Objective: 12.1","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"1","number":"6","ref":"454","question":"The intelligence phase of decision making consists of discovering, identifying, and understanding the problems occurring in the organization.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"2","number":"7","ref":"454","question":"The implementation phase of Simon's decision making model includes choosing among solution alternatives.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"8","diff":"2","chapter":12,"ref":"454","question":"The first stage in Simon's decision-making process model is the design stage.","case":"Content Objective: 12.1","answer":"false"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"2","number":"9","ref":"454","question":"The classical model of management does not address what exactly managers do when they plan, decide things, and control the work of others.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","diff":"1","number":"10","ref":"457","question":"MIS typically produce fixed, regularly scheduled reports based on data extracted and summarized from the firm's underlying transaction processing systems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","diff":"1","number":"11","ref":"457","question":"DSS primarily address structured problems.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","diff":"2","number":"12","ref":"457","question":"The earliest DSS were data-driven.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"13","diff":"1","chapter":12,"ref":"462","question":"What-if analysis works forward from known or assumed conditions.","case":"Content Objective: 12.2","answer":"true"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"14","diff":"1","chapter":12,"ref":"463","question":"Backward sensitivity analysis software is used for goal seeking.","case":"Content Objective: 12.2","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","diff":"1","number":"15","ref":"465","question":"Data visualization technologies help distill large amounts of information into easily read textual lists.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","diff":"1","number":"16","ref":"465","question":"DSS are a special category of GIS.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","diff":"1","number":"17","ref":"465-466","question":"A geographic information system is a decision support system designed specifically to work with spatial information.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.5","diff":"1","number":"18","ref":"467","question":"GDSS facilitate the solution of unstructured problems by a set of decision makers working together as a group in either the same location or different locations.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"true"},{"chapter":12,"type":0,"case":"Content","objective":"12.5","diff":"3","number":"19","ref":"467-468","question":"Web-based tools for videoconferencing and electronic meetings are the primary tools for GDSS.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"false"},{"type":0,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"20","diff":"1","chapter":12,"ref":"468","question":"During a GDSS meeting, the attendees control the use of GDSS tools.","case":"Content Objective: 12.5","answer":"false"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"Employees had to craft most management reports by hand.","index":"A"},{"value":"Data was stored in unconnected sources.","index":"B"},{"value":"Data was not being acquired by the proper channels.","index":"C"},{"value":"Managers were unable to make good decisions about stocking stores.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"21","ref":"449-450","question":"Which of the following was NOT a challenge Eastern Mountain Sports was facing in its management information systems and decision making?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"22","option":[{"value":"Improved decision making creates better products.","index":"A"},{"value":"Improved decision making results in a large monetary value for the firm as numerous small daily decisions affecting efficiency, production, costs, and more add up to large annual values.","index":"B"},{"value":"Improved decision making enables senior executives to more accurately foresee future financial trends.","index":"C"},{"value":"Improved decision making strengthens customer and supplier intimacy, which reduces costs.","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"451","question":"Which of the following statements best describes the business value of improved decision making?","diff":"1","answer":"b"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","option":[{"value":"undocumented.","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured.","index":"B"},{"value":"documented.","index":"C"},{"value":"semistructured.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"23","ref":"452","question":"When there is no well-understood or agreed-on procedure for making a decision, it is said to be","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","option":[{"value":"structured","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured","index":"B"},{"value":"semistructured","index":"C"},{"value":"procedural","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"24","ref":"452","question":"The type of decision that can made by following a definite procedure is called a(n) ________ decision.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"25","option":[{"value":"structured","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured","index":"B"},{"value":"recurring","index":"C"},{"value":"nonrecurring","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"452","question":"Which type of decision is deciding whether to introduce a new product line?","diff":"1","answer":"b"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"26","option":[{"value":"structured","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured","index":"B"},{"value":"semistructured","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"452","question":"Which type of decision is calculating gross pay for hourly workers?","diff":"1","answer":"a"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"27","option":[{"value":"semistructured","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured","index":"B"},{"value":"structured","index":"C"},{"value":"undocumented","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"452","question":"The decision to approve a capital budget is an example of a(n) ________ decision.","diff":"2","answer":"b"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"28","option":[{"value":"procedural","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured","index":"B"},{"value":"structured","index":"C"},{"value":"semistructured","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"452","question":"The decisions involved in creating and producing a corporate intranet can be classified as ________ decisions.","diff":"2","answer":"d"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"29","option":[{"value":"semistructured","index":"A"},{"value":"unstructured","index":"B"},{"value":"structured","index":"C"},{"value":"none of the above","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"452","question":"Checking store inventory is an example of a(n) ________ decision.","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"case":"Content Objective: 12.1","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"30","option":[{"value":"planning, financing, implementation, and maintenance.","index":"A"},{"value":"planning, design, implementation, and maintenance.","index":"B"},{"value":"intelligence, design, choice, and implementation.","index":"C"},{"value":"intelligence, design, financing, and implementation.","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"453","question":"Simon's description of decision making consists of which four stages?","diff":"2","answer":"c"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","option":[{"value":"design","index":"A"},{"value":"intelligence","index":"B"},{"value":"choice","index":"C"},{"value":"implementation","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"31","ref":"454","question":"Which phase of decision making finds or recognizes a problem, need, or opportunity?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"coordinating.","index":"A"},{"value":"leading.","index":"B"},{"value":"managing.","index":"C"},{"value":"negotiating.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"32","ref":"454","question":"The five classical functions of managers are planning, organizing, deciding, controlling, and","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"systematic.","index":"A"},{"value":"informal.","index":"B"},{"value":"reflective.","index":"C"},{"value":"well organized.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"33","ref":"454","question":"In contrast to the classical model of management, behavioral models see the actual behavior of managers as being more","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"perform often fewer than 100 activities a day.","index":"A"},{"value":"operate best with standardized, predictable, printed information.","index":"B"},{"value":"create a formalized, hierarchic structure of contacts to provide filtered information.","index":"C"},{"value":"typically work in a fragmented manner, with only 10% of activities exceeding an hour in duration.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"34","ref":"454","question":"Behavioral models of managers find that, from observation, managers","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Content Objective: 12.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"35","option":[{"value":"interpersonal, informational, and decisional","index":"A"},{"value":"symbolic, decisional, and interpersonal","index":"B"},{"value":"symbolic, interpersonal, and technical","index":"C"},{"value":"technical, interpersonal, and informational","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"455","question":"Mintzberg's classification of managerial roles outlines which three main categories?","diff":"2","answer":"a"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"decisional","index":"A"},{"value":"informational","index":"B"},{"value":"interpersonal","index":"C"},{"value":"symbolic","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"36","ref":"455","question":"The role of liaison falls into which of Mintzberg's managerial classifications?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"decisional","index":"A"},{"value":"informational","index":"B"},{"value":"interpersonal","index":"C"},{"value":"symbolic","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"37","ref":"455","question":"The role of entrepreneur falls into which of Mintzberg's managerial classifications?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"figureheads for the organization.","index":"A"},{"value":"leaders.","index":"B"},{"value":"nerve centers of the organization.","index":"C"},{"value":"negotiators.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"38","ref":"455","question":"According to Mintzberg, managers in their informational role act as","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"spokesperson","index":"A"},{"value":"resource allocator","index":"B"},{"value":"leader","index":"C"},{"value":"nerve center","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"39","ref":"455","question":"Which of the following managerial roles is NOT supported by information systems?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"management support, technical logistics, and user compliance.","index":"A"},{"value":"organization, environment, culture.","index":"B"},{"value":"information quality, information integrity, and information accuracy.","index":"C"},{"value":"information quality, organizational culture, and management filters.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"40","ref":"456","question":"As discussed in the chapter text, the three main reasons that investments in information technology do NOT always produce positive results are","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"accuracy","index":"A"},{"value":"integrity","index":"B"},{"value":"validity","index":"C"},{"value":"consistency","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"41","ref":"456","question":"The concern that data values of an information source fall within a defined range reflects which quality dimension of information?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"accuracy","index":"A"},{"value":"integrity","index":"B"},{"value":"validity","index":"C"},{"value":"consistency","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"42","ref":"456","question":"The concern that the structure of data is consistent within an information source reflects which quality dimension of information?","diff":"3","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"new ways of looking at data that emphasize change, flexibility, and rapid response.","index":"A"},{"value":"fixed, regularly scheduled reports based on data extracted from the organization's TPS.","index":"B"},{"value":"solutions to semistructured problems appropriate for middle management decision making.","index":"C"},{"value":"assumptions, responses to ad hoc queries, and graphic representations of existing data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"43","ref":"457","question":"MIS typically produce","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"44","option":[{"value":"DSS.","index":"A"},{"value":"MIS.","index":"B"},{"value":"GIS.","index":"C"},{"value":"CDSS.","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"457","question":"An information system for a building company that tracks construction costs for various projects across the United States would be categorized as a type of","diff":"1","answer":"b"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"GSS.","index":"A"},{"value":"ESS.","index":"B"},{"value":"TPS.","index":"C"},{"value":"DSS.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"45","ref":"481","question":"Which type of information system supports decision-making by enabling users to extract useful information that was previously buried in large quantities of data?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"internal corporate database, external data sources, and analysis tools.","index":"A"},{"value":"data visualization tools, software, and graphics capabilities.","index":"B"},{"value":"database, graphics capabilities, and analysis tools.","index":"C"},{"value":"database, software system, and user interface.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"46","ref":"458","question":"The components of a DSS are the","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"47","option":[{"value":"CDSS.","index":"A"},{"value":"MIS.","index":"B"},{"value":"DSS.","index":"C"},{"value":"ESS.","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"458","question":"A system that uses data mining to guide senior marketing executive's decisions about customer retention can be categorized as a(n):","diff":"3","answer":"c"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"historical data extracted from transaction processing systems.","index":"A"},{"value":"current or historical data from several applications or groups.","index":"B"},{"value":"external data typically mined from the Internet and other third-party sources.","index":"C"},{"value":"the corporation's current transaction data.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"48","ref":"458","question":"A DSS database is a collection of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"inaccuracies that can be magnified throughout a DSS because of incorrect data.","index":"A"},{"value":"organizational and people challenges may defeat a relatively successful technological solution.","index":"B"},{"value":"despite the best efforts of industry experts and sophisticated DSS, overbooking remains a problem.","index":"C"},{"value":"through the use of DSS, genetic algorithms, and neural networks, the problems of overbooking and bumped passengers have largely been solved.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"49","ref":"459","question":"The chapter case discussing overbooking on airlines illustrates that","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Synthesis Objective: 12.2","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"50","option":[{"value":"DSS to enable greater supplier intimacy.","index":"A"},{"value":"MIS to achieve greater operational excellence.","index":"B"},{"value":"ESS to enable better decision-making.","index":"C"},{"value":"CDSS to enable greater customer intimacy.","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"461-462","question":"The chapter case discussing Dick's Sporting Goods stores illustrates the use of","diff":"3","answer":"a"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"optimization","index":"A"},{"value":"sensitivity analysis","index":"B"},{"value":"statistical","index":"C"},{"value":"forecasting","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"51","ref":"462","question":"Which type of model asks what-if questions repeatedly to determine the impact on outcomes of changes in one or more factors?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"optimization","index":"A"},{"value":"sensitivity analysis","index":"B"},{"value":"statistical","index":"C"},{"value":"forecasting","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"52","ref":"462","question":"Which type of model is used to help managers use historical data to estimate future conditions and sales figures resulting from these conditions?","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"project future conditions and predict the effect of these conditions on sales.","index":"A"},{"value":"determine the proper mix of products within a given market to maximize profits.","index":"B"},{"value":"determine the price of a product given fluctuating sales and advertising budget.","index":"C"},{"value":"establish the best relationship between price and sales and marketing budgets.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"53","ref":"462","question":"You would use an optimization model to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"supply chain optimization.","index":"A"},{"value":"historical what-if analysis.","index":"B"},{"value":"goal seeking.","index":"C"},{"value":"reverse forecasting.","index":"D"}],"answer":"c","number":"54","ref":"463","question":"Backward sensitivity analysis software is used for","diff":"3","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","option":[{"value":"spreadsheet tool that displays two or more dimensions of data in a convenient format.","index":"A"},{"value":"type of relational database.","index":"B"},{"value":"chart tool that can rotate columnar data quickly and visually.","index":"C"},{"value":"tool for performing sensitivity analysis.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"55","ref":"464","question":"A pivot table is a","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"GIS","index":"A"},{"value":"DSS","index":"B"},{"value":"MIS","index":"C"},{"value":"TPS","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"56","ref":"465","question":"Which type of information system uses data visualization technology to analyze and display data for planning and decision making in the form of digitized maps?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"DSS.","index":"A"},{"value":"CDSS.","index":"B"},{"value":"Web-based GIS.","index":"C"},{"value":"Intelligent agent.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"57","ref":"466-467","question":"Dell Computer's online tools that allow users of their Web site to customize and order a new PC are a type of","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.3","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"58","option":[{"value":"CDSS","index":"A"},{"value":"GSS","index":"B"},{"value":"GIS","index":"C"},{"value":"GDSS","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"467","question":"As discussed in the chapter case, the system used in South Carolina to estimate and map the regional damage and losses resulting from an earthquake was a type of","diff":"1","answer":"c"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.3","option":[{"value":"CDSS","index":"A"},{"value":"GSS","index":"B"},{"value":"GIS","index":"C"},{"value":"GDSS","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"59","ref":"466-467","question":"Saturn.com's \"Build Your Own\" feature, allowing customers to select the trim, transmission, engine, and other features of a car model is an example of a","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.5","option":[{"value":"are designed to allow meeting attendees to share their thoughts in real-time with their peers.","index":"A"},{"value":"support decisions that require knowledge about the geographic distribution of resources.","index":"B"},{"value":"are typically used with geographically dispersed attendees.","index":"C"},{"value":"implement structured methods for organizing and evaluating ideas.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"60","ref":"467-468","question":"GDSS","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.5","option":[{"value":"allowing users to contribute simultaneously.","index":"A"},{"value":"using structured methods for evaluating ideas.","index":"B"},{"value":"identifying users informally.","index":"C"},{"value":"the guarantee of user anonymity.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"61","ref":"468","question":"An essential component in the ability of GDSS to contribute to a collaborative environment is","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.5","option":[{"value":"require a small number of attendees in order to maintain high levels of productivity.","index":"A"},{"value":"enable increasing a meeting size without reducing productivity.","index":"B"},{"value":"include specific procedures for priority ranking the order in which participants can respond.","index":"C"},{"value":"utilize shared desktop computers to foster collaboration.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"62","ref":"468","question":"GDSS","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"case":"Analysis Objective: 12.4","type":1,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"63","option":[{"value":"DSS.","index":"A"},{"value":"ESS.","index":"B"},{"value":"CDSS.","index":"C"},{"value":"MIS.","index":"D"}],"chapter":12,"ref":"468","question":"The information system used by Caesar's Entertainment, which combines data from internal TPS with information from financial systems and external sources to deliver reports such as profit-loss statements, impact analyses, is an example of","diff":"1","answer":"b"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"digital dashboard","index":"A"},{"value":"balanced scorecard","index":"B"},{"value":"KPI","index":"C"},{"value":"data visualization","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"64","ref":"468","question":"The leading methodology for understanding the really important information needed by a firm's executives is called the ________ method.","diff":"2","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"balanced scorecards","index":"A"},{"value":"digital dashboard","index":"B"},{"value":"graphic visualization tools","index":"C"},{"value":"drill-down capabilities","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"65","ref":"471","question":"Which of the following features of an ESS displays traditional financial metrics with measurements from additional perspectives, such as customers, or learning and growth, on a single screen?","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"CDSS","index":"A"},{"value":"MIS","index":"B"},{"value":"DSS","index":"C"},{"value":"ESS","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"66","ref":"468-469","question":"A system that displays performance overviews of the firm in an easy-to-read graphical interface, along with the ability to drill down into fine-grained sales data can be categorized as a(n)","diff":"2","aacsb":"Analytic skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"support the structured decision making of senior executives.","index":"A"},{"value":"have the ability to drill down into lower levels of detail.","index":"B"},{"value":"easily integrate data from different systems.","index":"C"},{"value":"are primarily driven by information derived from a company's transaction processing systems.","index":"D"}],"answer":"b","number":"67","ref":"494469","question":"ESS","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"look at more data in less time with greater clarity.","index":"A"},{"value":"use creative analysis.","index":"B"},{"value":"quickly manipulate TPS and historical data.","index":"C"},{"value":"decentralize decision making.","index":"D"}],"answer":"a","number":"68","ref":"470","question":"The easy use of graphics in an ESS allows the user to","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"structured","index":"A"},{"value":"informal","index":"B"},{"value":"system","index":"C"},{"value":"external","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"69","ref":"470","question":"Executives need a wide range of ________ as well as internal data.","diff":"1","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills"},{"chapter":12,"type":1,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","option":[{"value":"have greater span of control.","index":"A"},{"value":"assign lower levels of management greater control.","index":"B"},{"value":"reduce their need to review lower levels of operation.","index":"C"},{"value":"all of the above.","index":"D"}],"answer":"d","number":"70","ref":"470","question":"A well-designed ESS will allow management to","diff":"2","aacsb":"Use of information technology"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.1","diff":"1","number":"71","ref":"452","question":"A(n) ________ decision is repetitive and routine, for which known algorithms provide solutions.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"structured"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","number":"72","diff":"2","chapter":12,"ref":"453","question":"The third stage in Simon's description of decision making is ________.","case":"Content Objective: 12.1","answer":"choice"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","diff":"2","number":"73","ref":"456","question":"The concept of management ________ describes situations in which managers act on biases that reject information that does not conform to their expectations.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"filters"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","diff":"1","number":"74","ref":"457","question":"________-driven DSS have analysis capabilities based on strong theories and used to perform \"what-if\" and similar kinds of analyses.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"Model"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","diff":"2","number":"75","ref":"458","question":"Of the three main DSS components, the ________ system comprises the tools used for data analysis.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"software"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.2","diff":"1","number":"76","ref":"458","question":"A(n) ________ is an abstract representation illustrating the components or relationships of a phenomenon.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"model"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.3","diff":"2","number":"77","ref":"462","question":"A(n) ________ model determines the best resource allocation to maximize or minimize specified variables.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"optimization"},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Use of information technology","number":"78","diff":"1","chapter":12,"ref":"466","question":"A(n) ________ supports the decision-making processes of an existing or potential customer.","case":"Content Objective: 12.3","answer":"customer decision-support system, CDSS"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.5","diff":"2","number":"79","ref":"467","question":"A(n) ________ facilitates the solution to unstructured problems by a set of decision-makers working together as a group.","aacsb":"Use of information technology","answer":"group decision-support systems, GDSS"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Content","objective":"12.4","diff":"2","number":"80","ref":"471","question":"A(n) ________ uses easy-to-understand displays of information to provide management with a comprehensive view of firm performance on a single screen.","aacsb":"Reflective thinking skills","answer":"digital dashboard, executive dashboard"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"objective":"12.3","aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"81","ref":"457-458","question":"Describe MIS and DSS and differentiate between them.","case":"Analysis","answer":"MIS provide information on the firm's performance to help managers monitor and control the business. They typically produce hard copy, fixed, regularly scheduled reports based on data extracted and summarized from the organization's underlying transaction processing systems. DSS provide new sets of capabilities for nonroutine decisions and user control. MIS accents reports based on routine flows of data and assists in the general control of the organization. DSS emphasizes change, flexibility, and rapid response to unstructured problems. Diff: 2"},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.3","diff":"2","number":"82","ref":"458-463","question":"What is the difference between a model-driven and a data-driven DSS?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Model-driven DSS use some type of model to perform \"what-if\" and other types of analyses. Their analysis capabilities were based on a strong theory or model combined with a good user interface to make the model easy to use. Data-driven DSS analyze large pools of data found in major organizational systems. They support decision making by allowing users to extract useful information that was previously buried in large quantities of data."},{"type":2,"aacsb":"Analytic skills","number":"83","diff":"3","chapter":12,"ref":"462-463","question":"Discuss four types of models commonly used by DSS.","case":"Analysis Objective: 12.3","answer":"Statistical modeling software can be used to help establish relationships, such as relating product sales to differences in age, income, or other factors between communities.\nOptimization models determined optimal resource allocation to maximize or minimize specified variables such as cost or time. A classic use of optimization models is to determine the proper mix of products within a given market to maximize profits.\nForecasting models are often used to forecast sales. The user of this type of model might supply a range of historical data to project future conditions and the sales that might result from those conditions. Companies often use this software to predict the actions of competitors.\nSensitivity analysis models ask \"what-if\" questions repeatedly to determine the impact of changes in one or more factors on outcomes."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.3","diff":"2","number":"84","ref":"457-465","question":"What is the business value of a DSS?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"DSS can help companies improve supply chain management and customer relationship management. Some take advantage of the company-wide data provided by enterprise systems. DSS today can also harness the interactive capabilities of the Web to provide decision-support tools to both employees and customers."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.3","diff":"2","number":"85","ref":"458-459, 468-470","question":"If both contemporary ESS and DSS incorporate tools for modeling and analysis, what qualities distinguish the two types of system?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"DSS are concerned with solving more specific business problems, such as determining the best pricing for a product, establishing optimized delivery routes, whereas ESS are designed specifically for executives to use as a way of managing the company and seeing an overview of both external and internal information in order to monitor more general business situations. The ESS modeling tools would be used to provide different views of status, rather than to analyze large amounts of data to arrive at a solution for a specific problem."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Synthesis","objective":"12.3","diff":"3","number":"86","ref":"466-467","question":"What is a GIS? Describe at least three ways in which a GIS could be used by modern business.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Geographic information systems are a special category of DSS that use data visualization technology to analyze and display data for planning and decision making in the form of digitized maps. GIS can best be used to support decisions that require knowledge about the geographic distribution of people or other resources in scientific research, resource management, and development planning. GIS have modeling capabilities, allowing managers to change data and automatically revise business scenarios to find better solutions.\nFor instance, a company could display its customers on a map and then design the most efficient delivery route for its products. A second way in which it could be used would be to analyze demographic information to decide where to open branch restaurants. A third use could be customer demographic data and map information to locate people who are likely to become customers for the company's services."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"12.5","diff":"2","number":"87","ref":"467-468","question":"What do you see as the business value of a GDSS?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"GDSS helps groups make decisions about unstructured problems. Firstly, because GDSS provides value by allowing collaboration over important decisionsthe decision doesn't rest in the hands of one person alone. By having more people working on the problem, the decision is more likely to realistically reflect the needs and goals of the group, rather than just one person. Secondly, because anonymity is a feature, people are encouraged to be more honest. This will also enhance the accuracy of the solution. The ability of the GDSS to record the meeting and decisions means that the decision-making process, its ideas and solutions, can be made part of the company's knowledge base. Additionally, by providing structure, the GDSS may enhance the efficiency of the particular type of unstructured decision making."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.5","diff":"3","number":"88","ref":"467-468","question":"Describe what technologies, facilities, and capabilities would be required to run a GDSS- enabled meeting.","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"GDSS-guided meetings take place in conference rooms with special hardware and software tools to facilitate group decision making. The hardware includes computer and networking equipment, overhead projectors, and display screens. Special electronic meeting software collects, documents, ranks, edits, and stores the ideas offered in a decision-making meeting. The more elaborate GDSS use a professional facilitator and support staff. The facilitator selects the software tools and helps organize and run the meeting. A sophisticated GDSS provides each attendee with a dedicated desktop computer under that person's individual control. No one will be able to see what individuals do on their computers until those participants are ready to share information. Their input is transmitted over a network to a central server that stores information generated by the meeting and makes it available to all on the meeting network. Data can also be projected on a large screen in the meeting room."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Evaluation","objective":"12.4","diff":"2","number":"89","ref":"468-470","question":"You have been hired as a consultant for an established bicycle parts manufacturer to assist senior management in planning a new ESS. What factors will you advise management to take into consideration?","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"Student answers will vary, but should take into account technical difficulties (integrating data from different systems), the types of information and overview of the organization needed, and change management. An example answer is:\nA major challenge of building executive support systems has been to integrate data from systems designed for very different purposes so that senior executives can review organizational performance from a firm-wide perspective. ESS must be designed so that high-level managers and others can use them without much training. One area that merits special attention is the determination of executive information requirements. ESS need to have some facility for environmental scanning. A key information requirement of managers at the strategic level is the capability to detect signals of problems in the organizational environment that indicate strategic threats and opportunities. The ESS need to be designed so that both external and internal sources of information can be used for environmental scanning purposes. Implementation of the ESS must be carefully managed to neutralize the opposition of managers at the lower levels of the organization, because ESS potentially could give top executives the ability to examine their work without their knowledge."},{"chapter":12,"type":2,"case":"Analysis","objective":"12.4","diff":"2","number":"90","ref":"468-469","question":"Describe the balanced scorecard model and its role in ESS.\n","aacsb":"Analytic skills","answer":"The balanced score card is a framework for operationalizing a firm's strategic plan by focusing on measurable outcomes on four dimensions of firm performance: financial, business process, customer, and learning and growth. Performance on each dimension is measured using key performance indicators (KPIs), which are the measures proposed by senior management for understanding how well the firm is performing along any given dimension. The balanced scorecard framework is thought to be \"balanced\" because it causes managers to focus on more than just financial performance. In this view, financial performance is past history–the result of past actions–and managers should focus on the things they are able to influence today, such as business process efficiency, customer satisfaction, and employee training."}]